<item>
		<title>2008 Convergence Reportback Teaser</title>
		<link>http://www.crimethinc.com/blog/2008/07/23/2008-convergence-reportback-teaser/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2008 18:14:48 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc_creator><![CDATA[b. traven]]></dc_creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.crimethinc.com/blog/?p=248</guid>
		<description/>
		<content_encoded><![CDATA[<a rel="lightbox" href="http://thecloud.crimethinc.com/images/convergfire/convergfireb.jpg"><img src="http://thecloud.crimethinc.com/images/convergfire/convergfirea.jpg" alt="" /> </a><span class="invisible">-</span>
Here’s a brief summary of this past week’s convergence, until someone completes a lengthier report. You’ll have to read about it here, if not in the minutes of the next FBI witch hunt (see <a href="http://www.supporteric.org" target="_blank">supporteric.org</a>), since neither the New York Times nor Fox News succeeded in getting their stooges on site and <a href="http://www.jsonline.com/story/index.aspx?id=773869" target="_blank">the local media</a> could only string together the usual clichés.

This year’s CrimethInc. Convergence occurred 40 miles outside of Milwaukee, WI, on the outskirts of the tiny town of Waldo. It began with appropriate theatrics. As participants descended upon the campsite on the first day, so did a massive supercell—spawning a tornado touchdown a mere 15 miles away—and with it, 70 mph horizontal winds and rain that threatened to carry everyone off. The early arrivals lucky enough to experience the storm had to hold on for dear life to prevent the temporary structures from blowing away. Despite this challenge, everything was cleaned up and reconstructed in time for the opening circle at dusk.

<!--more-->

Most of the week’s activities took place at the actual campsite: workshops under tarps in the grassy fields and beneath trees in the surrounding woods, rowdy direct action simulations, cooking over a wood-fire trench on chain link fencing, writing letters at the prisoner support station, perusing hundreds of free ’zines and books in the library, childcare volunteers chasing after the temporary community’s rad kids, day-and-night swimming in the nearby pond, and possibly the most inclusive and spirited event of the week—the Convergence Cabaret, featuring fabulous queer dance troupes, contortionist burlesque, anticapitalist hip hop, stand up comedy, and obscene puppetry.

Readers familiar with the <a href="/texts/recentfeatures/under.php">discussion questions</a> following last summer’s convergence will be pleased to hear that this year there were neither tensions between subcultural groups nor attempts from wingnuts to co-opt the convergence to their own purposes. Practically everyone in attendance made an effort to contribute to an atmosphere of respect and consent-based interaction, and it’s notable that this is the first convergence at which the sobriety policy was not challenged. There were a couple uncomfortable moments, such as an unplanned fireside routine that many felt smacked of cultural appropriation, but participants generally appeared open to dialogue and critique; if anything, such events indicate that the convergence is drawing participants from outside homogenous anarchist circles, who nonetheless are willing to learn new ways to respect others and be accountable for their actions. The closest to last year’s 2012 workshop debacle was a prank on the opening night by an anonymous team of self-proclaimed Maximum Ultraists, which offered a harmless lightning rod for drama and speculation without derailing anything or distracting anyone.

The only off-site event was an <a href="http://stopi69.wordpress.com/" target="_blank">anti-I-69 house demo</a> carried out by 70 people on Saturday night. Afterwards, when everyone had regrouped at camp around the fire, another cloudburst inspired a midnight swim and a dance party characterized by a degree of passionate abandon not seen in North America since the first CrimethInc. convergence in 2002.

Longtime organizers from past convergences agree that this year was the best yet in terms of wide diffusion of responsibility. The Milwaukee locals did an enthusiastic job of assembling infrastructure, and no one had to go without sleep or sanity to keep things on track. At this point, the format of the convergence is understood widely enough to be practically self-sustaining. It remains to those who will plan next summer’s convergence to invent some new experiment that is not yet familiar to anyone, so it will be possible for something to go wrong.

With a final puppet show on the electoral spectacle, the campsite to clean, and yet another impending thunderstorm on the horizon, there wasn’t time in the closing circle for a comprehensive discussion of what went well, what could have been improved, and what participants would like to try next year. If you were in Waldo last week, please share your perspective in the comments section here!]]></content_encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp_post_id>248</wp_post_id>
		<wp_post_date><![CDATA[2008-07-23 11:14:48]]></wp_post_date>
		<wp_post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2008-07-23 18:14:48]]></wp_post_date_gmt>
		<wp_comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp_comment_status>
		<wp_ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp_ping_status>
		<wp_post_name><![CDATA[2008-convergence-reportback-teaser]]></wp_post_name>
		<wp_status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp_status>
		<wp_post_parent>0</wp_post_parent>
		<wp_menu_order>0</wp_menu_order>
		<wp_post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp_post_type>
		<wp_post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp_post_password>
		<wp_is_sticky>0</wp_is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="from-the-trenches"><![CDATA[From the Trenches]]></category>
		<wp_postmeta>
			<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp_meta_key>
			<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[2]]></wp_meta_value>
		</wp_postmeta>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>648</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[bliopo25]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[guhyanath@yahoo.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url/>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[141.233.223.118]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2008-07-23 11:40:59]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2008-07-23 18:40:59]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[cool convergence - just wondering about a dialog between white aux caucus &amp; APOC caucus - also - what was it that around the fire smacked of cultural appropriation? 

concerned.]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>649</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[WapsiWilly]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[WapsiWilly@gmail.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url/>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[63.254.136.35]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2008-07-23 13:25:34]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2008-07-23 20:25:34]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[The local fox affiliate even did a fair and balanced piece about us!

http://www.myfoxnewisconsin.com/myfox/pages/Home/Detail?contentId=7015958&amp;version=1&amp;locale=EN-US&amp;layoutCode=VSTY&amp;pageId=1.1.1]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>650</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[Bryer]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[el.anarquista.poeta@gmail.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url>http://</wp_comment_author_url>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[72.241.211.9]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2008-07-23 21:04:45]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2008-07-24 04:04:45]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[I thought the convergence was pretty amazing. alot of good workshops, alot of good discussions, good food, nice naked lake swimming, just a cool area in general, and most importantly I met alot of really cool people.


um, the fuckin 'tribal' dance???
if you didnt notice that I hope you were off on the compost toilet or something

overall though real good time
forgot to get alot of contacts though...]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>651</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[b. traven]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[b@crimethinc.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url>http://www.crimethinc.com</wp_comment_author_url>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[96.235.18.254]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2008-07-24 00:53:25]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2008-07-24 07:53:25]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[I suggest it might be ideal for either the people who were involved in that event or the people who discussed it with them afterwards to be the ones to speak about it here. That could minimize the amount of needless drama around the issue.]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>2</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>652</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[Davey_Utah]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[flandersdiddly@yahoo.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url/>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[216.83.147.10]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2008-07-24 10:12:14]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2008-07-24 17:12:14]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[THANK YOU Milwaukee folks, from the bottom of my heart! Thanks to every one that made things happen!
   I had an amazing time @ the convergence! Thanks to one &amp; all. The Food was so delicious, bravo! Swimming in the pond was so enjoyable, &amp; I loved hanging out @ the creek. The creek became quite the natural art gallery; the stone stacking &amp; bridge making was indescribably esthetically pleasing. While cooling my feet in the pleasant water &amp; taking in the fresh air I reveled in the beauty of the woods &amp; the sublime endeavors of the stone stackers. Also I'd like to thank the very cool individual who made the compost toilets, THANK YOU! ;^) also thank you for the towering bonfire, &amp; the poetry you reading; you have a gift. 
   Some of my favorite workshops were the ones held by the Winona three (the organizing in a small town workingshop, the news paper workshop, the design workshop). you three were standout, shining individuals who filled me with motivation &amp; inspiration! Also The white aux caucus was quite insightful &amp; a very positive experience. I LOVED the 5 finger discount workshop, the young individuals who taught that workshop were bad@$$ heroes &amp; their song they performed @ the Convergence Cabaret was an uber highlight for me.
* never gonna give you up
Never gonna let you down
Never gonna run around and desert you
Never gonna make you cry
Never gonna say goodbye
Never gonna tell a lie and hurt you
AHEM... kaff kaff, pardon me; I had to sing a little right there... hahahahahahaha!
The Science of Anarchy workshop in the woods was damn interesting, thank YOU, indeed. The Knowing your legal rights was also a greatly informative workshop! 
   So many kind courteous folks, so many smiles, so many thank you's &amp; you're welcomes. So many warm, sweet, open people. I felt completely welcomed &amp; accepted.  Also I want to give a truely heartfelt shout-out to the astoundingly breath taking beauty of Wisconsin.

with the utmost sincerity &amp; over flowing ardent passion,
OXOX]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>653</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[andrenalina]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[vezzea@u.washington.edu]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url/>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[24.18.27.40]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2008-07-24 13:29:14]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2008-07-24 20:29:14]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[Alright, SO Wild Gina and the Freaky Freaks weren't particularly prepared with their dialogue nor with how the performance was going to go. Our emphasis was the costumes and the wood constructed hoola hoops, which aroused in us a sort of "back to the land/post-european" sentiment, which as we have learned now is a concept soaked in racial misconceptions and stereotypes. Winging a performance at any convergence is risky business, but a spontaneous, improvisational performance set in an environment that is trying to smash the perpetuation of power/racial/prejudicial normalcies that are perpetuated in mass entertainment is especially volatile. 

I AM GLAD I HAD TO LEARN THIS THE HARD WAY.
I AM THANKFUL THAT MY PERFORMANCE EXPOSED ME (and the rest of us) TO THE WORD: CULTURAL APPROPRIATION.

I am glad that our more or less "utopic" environment was challenged by ignorance...and for everyone who said they didn't know what the big deal was, i think we all have some more learning to do about how our white dominated system conditions us think that there arent struggles and people and heritage behind all the cutesy tutsey, quaint little costumes and dances of "those other" "brown people", "natives" or "noble savages" which in fact have been exploited by society for entertainment. 

I apologize sincerely for my actions, and i am thankful for everyone who approached me on this issue, for it might not have been brought up otherwise and i would have kept perpetuating by assumptions. Now, however, i see cultural appropriation issues everywhere among mass media and now i must show others whats so wrong about it. 

WildGina will not wilt, but grow on. Dance on. Sing on. Rock on. to all of you, thank you. and until next year, keep dropping think bombs in a white neighborhood near you.]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>654</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[lobsterbeard]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[lobsterbeard@gmail.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url>http://</wp_comment_author_url>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[98.164.80.95]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2008-07-24 14:06:11]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2008-07-24 21:06:11]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[What a mature, intelligent, accountable response, andrenalina. These things so often turn defensive and unproductive, it's awesome that you've taken this as a learning and motivating experience. 

The criticism of the performance was appropriate, but I was made uneasy by peoples' willingness to endlessly continue the drumbeat of derision rather than discuss any of the other racial dynamics of the convergence. Focusing on singular, cut and dry events after they've already been identified and analyzed is one way white people often escape turning a critical lens on their own behavior. So we spend an inordinate amount of time talking about Nazis, for instance, rather than the marginalization of people of color in the anarchist milieu, among a million other things. I'm not saying that talking in depth about cultural appropriation at the convergence wasn't a good use of our time, because clearly it was, I just think it's important that such a conversation be a jumping off point rather than an end.]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>655</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[Bryer]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[el.anarquista.poeta@gmail.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url>http://</wp_comment_author_url>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[72.241.211.9]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2008-07-24 18:14:34]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2008-07-25 01:14:34]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[I really enjoyed it alot. I read alot of crimethinc critiques, and after the convergence I just laugh at most of them.

It really was an amazing experience, despite a few minor speedbumps (media, ultraist letters, wild gina, few other things)

I will absolutly be attending next year, with alot of friends. I really hope it's in a rural location again]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>656</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[Pseudonym]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[mtx7669@juno.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url>http://</wp_comment_author_url>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[70.94.40.138]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2008-07-24 23:02:54]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2008-07-25 06:02:54]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[I also had a great time at the convergence.  One highlight for me throughout the weekend was the positive response from the locals of Waldo (population under 500).  I was a bit nervous about them wandering into the cabaret on Friday night but then when I heard about the amiable interactions between some anarchists and the locals both on and off site, I smiled and felt much more at ease.  Contrary to the tone of caution presented by the FOX broadcast, it seemed as though the Waldonians' thoughts of the convergence ranged from positive to uninterested.

To me, this just shows how some direct relationships can easily overpower the media hype.  See you at Tiff's!

On the other hand, one thing I would like convergences to accomplish in the future is something more concrete.  While we want to keep the convergence as legal as possible, I really think that 100-300 anarchists in a small area for a week or two have the power to establish something really long-lasting before the out-of-towners move on.  After helping to build temporary infrastructure - and knowing the amount of work THAT takes - how could a bit more planning and finesse land us with more PERMANENT infrastructure, and a space that enriches an area for months or years to come?  The actual building could provide hands-on workshops like never attempted.

Setting up a squat could be quite fun and does it have to be risky with the right planning? 

How fast could 75 people till up an empty lot and establish a geurilla garden?

What knowledge or resources could be gained from temporarily taking over a park? a store? a beach? a university? a pre-scheduled local event like a concert/county fair?

How could we insert our large numbers into already gathered, aimless crowds  to turn the mundane into something marvelous? 

What other kinds of things would we like to see happen?

Perhaps this is taking things in a different direction from the anarchist retreat/summer camp that the Waldo convergence seemed to be.  I had a blast in Waldo and the relative safety of the place was nice, but I left wanting  a bit more danger, a bit more of a test.  .  .

Just what are we made of?]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>657</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[Alex T. Gravity CDD]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[wildnettledistro@keoxa.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url/>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[96.235.18.254]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2008-07-26 08:53:51]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2008-07-26 15:53:51]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[My favorite part was the Convergence Cabaret. Breaking down awkward spectacle/spectator dynamics was really exciting. It wasn't just people who were comfortable performing who did. 

To go along with Pseudonym, I think there should be a bit more planning as far as infrastructure building goes. A couple days prior, we spent a lot of time building our little village structures just in time for the convergence to start. It really wasn't all that hard, and could have been done a lot sooner, which would have left us time to build crazy rope swings or time machines or something, and would have probably been less stressful for organizers. Milwaukee kids did a fantastic job, don't get me wrong. I could see there were a few that were very stressed throughout the Convergence that might not have been had the workload been spread out in smaller doses over a longer amount of time. One example was the re-direct point. Some people spent entire days shuttling people back and forth because it simply had to be done, not because they had signed up to do it. Some people had to wait a day to get a ride. 

Overall, the Convergence was focused and empowering.]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>658</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[inmemoryof]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[hotxfeet@gmail.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url/>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[207.246.115.13]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2008-07-26 10:09:13]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2008-07-26 17:09:13]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[In memory of C and A, the authors of the Maximum Ultraist letter, who committed suicide on the Monday following the convergence, too disappointed to even follow through with their threat to take others with them.

Before ending their lives, they put into motion one final project, which should burst into the light in the coming years; a project we could compare, perhaps, to the final project of an earlier Ultraist, Carlo Michelstaedter.

It is disheartening - but not surprising - that Crimethinc considers their letter to the convergence a harmless joke.  To be clear: they were not joking.  Their deaths are evidence of this.  We hope that others will begin where our fallen friends left off and carry out the death sentence on civilization that is long overdue.

Ultraists never forget!]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>659</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[11sense]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[eleven_sense@yahoo.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url/>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[71.56.234.255]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2008-07-26 18:44:38]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2008-07-27 01:44:38]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[There is a lot I wanted to say at the convergence but was to busy adjusting to my surroundings and taking in as much raw information as possible to get it out so here it is.

I'll try to make this part  brief so as not to beat a dead horse...

As one of the freaks I would like to thank Wild Gina for her comment. It summed up our trio's feelings about the Cabaret and the rest of the convergence. I went to learn how to be an anarchist not knowing all that it entailed but with every intention of finding out. The events during and following the cabaret were by far the most impactful for me in what was a crash course on how I am about to live the rest of my life. Our actions certainly were not excusable but I am so greatful that I was corrected right away and can now use what I learned to correct others and continue to remove myself from such misconceptions. 

Now on a completely unbrief and probably way-more-information-than-any-of-you-care-to-know-kind-of-note...
 
I've always been an anarchist at heart whether I knew it or not. I came from a series of tiny towns all over and so for the most part I've lived a somewhat sheltered life. However, because of being so separated from "the real world" what little exposure I did get to it made me realize just how fucked up "the real world" is. Over the past 2 years or so, after moving into the thick of it, it only became more and more apparent. The longer I was part of the system the dirtier I felt and the more I wanted to get out of it. Regrettably, like so many other "trapped" free-thinkers I continued justifying my life thinking "this is just the way the world works." After about the 3rd or fourth month of having the bull-shit cluster fuck scam known as the 2008 presidential race thrown in my face constantly, I began avoiding all mainstream media and got rid of my brand-new TV. Suddenly I was introduced to truth all around me instead of spoon-fed lies. I began seeing the grotesqueness of swarms of urban developements engulfing the last open spaces between growing cities here in colorado. One day while driving down the interstate in slow moving bumper to bumper traffic I looked around me at all of the other cars seeing them like a plague, disgusted with our species and myself for being a part of it. As if that weren't enough the next thing that caught my attention was none other than the SIXTH Wal-Mart being erected within a 40-50 mile radius of the tri-city northern colorado area. I started crying, thinking to myself "why did I have to be born in this time?" "Why me?" "What am I actually supposed to do?" I had felt that way before but never figured out the answer til just then. After that moment I just stopped. I took myself out of it. I have been removing myself from the system to the best of my ability ever since, and, equally important, as I and hopefully many other new comers learned from the convergence(particularly incidents like the infamous Wild Gina skit), removing the system from myself. 

To most of you much or all of these realizations seem obvious and to the seasoned anarchist, activist, extremist etc. living removed from the system is all you know now. The point is that 3 months ago before I knew what it meant to be called an anarchist, let alone knew about crimethinc, I walked away from my comfortable apartment, 1 month after that I walked out on my comfortable job at none other than Starbucks Coffee, and a month after that I learned the words to describe everything I had been feeling for so long from a friend who introduced me to crimethinc. Now, feeling right about my choices but still vulnerable with no income and winging my new lifestyle, I wasn't sure where to go or what to do next. Then three days prior found out about the convergence, I learned that not only were there many other people who felt the same but were organized and ready to stop asking questions and making the answers for themselves. (If you thought any of that was cheesy just wait)
This above all else is what solidified everything in me, I packed up and never having gotten a ride from a stranger farther than through my subdivision, I left. I hitchiked from Ft Collins to Milwaukee. Knowing I had a place I could go to meet people who I know will fight by my side in the revolutions to come and who can show me how to become stronger in these fights, is the only thing that allowed me to take such leaps of faith on my part. I am and and continue to be humble in knowing I still have much to learn as do we all from each other. I f any of you may not have taken it into consideration try to keep in mind that there are many other good people in the world waiting to find out they are anarchists. Albeit, they may not know how to dive right in as I am clumsily attempting to, many are just as willing to relearn how to be/interact with humans. That is exactly how the vast necessary changes can and will happen; not always by forcing people to see the world differently but by cultivating and nourishing the the thoughts and feelings that are the seeds of anarchy already within them.

Thank you to everyone who organized and attended the convergence, and to all other anarchists who I have yet to meet, you are all the answer to my questions

This is why I was born in this time.

I am supposed to fight with all of you, because we can see the wrong in the world.]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>660</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[lycanhardcore]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[gavin.n.steeves@gmail.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url/>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[75.72.232.144]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2008-07-26 21:06:26]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2008-07-27 04:06:26]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[You guys encouraged me to quit school. I felt like a bit of a sellout and a useless hipster when I was at the convergence this year. I come back feeling lighter, feeling inspired, feeling like something potentially very powerful. When you see me at next year's convergence, I will be a new persyn: not the yuppie-in-training I was in my first year of university, nor even the immature punk raging against the world that I was in high school (which, by the way, was still a lot better than Mr. Fair Trade Coffee and Student Union Politics).

The next time you see me, I think I'll actually feel worthy to eat good food, swim naked, and talk revolution with a hundred and fifty or so of the most heartbreakingly beautiful people I have ever met in my short time on this rock speeding through space. I'm glad you guys had me.]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>661</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[ret marut]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[ret@crimethinc.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url>http://</wp_comment_author_url>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[76.112.237.162]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2008-07-28 09:53:47]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2008-07-28 16:53:47]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[I want to thank Andrenalina and 11sense for their courageous and inspiring comments. Rarely can one find such maturity anywhere on the internet, and it's to their credit and the credit of everyone who participated in the convergence that an awkward situation was turned into such a learning opportunity that strengthens bonds rather than breaking them.

I want to say also that the greatest credit must go to the people who addressed the issue with them when it first came up. Despite it striking close to home, they must have been really constructive and conscientious in a way that all of us are now benefitting from. 

I fear that all of us have a difficult road ahead--most of the environments we will spend our lives in will not be supportive, horizontal spaces like the convergence was. Sometimes we will be totally isolated and everything will seem hopeless. But we owe it to ourselves and the world to hold tight to our limitless potential, however hard things get, and to fight to fulfill it. Usually this fight doesn't involve molotov cocktails as much as humility and accountability. Thanks, friends, for demonstrating so much of these.]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>3</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>662</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[Huckleberry Finn mac Cumhail]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[danielmauch@hotmail.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url>http://</wp_comment_author_url>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[199.120.252.122]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2008-07-28 10:55:46]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2008-07-28 17:55:46]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[Here is a cut-and-paste from my blog: 



Wednesday, July 23, 2008 

 The Secret World of Waldo 


Oh, my friends, even if I had the words to explain, I fear you would not have the ability to believe or even comprehend. Nonetheless, with this paltry stream of consonants and vowels, I will try to create a dim shadow of the reality.

I have just returned from an international anarchist conference in Waldo, Wisconsin, a small farming town outside of Milwaukee.

There was no attempt at a census, but, by even conservative estimates, there were at least 300 of us (enough to hold Thermopylae against an advancing Totalitarian army), and all governing decisions were made according to the principles of universal consent and consensus.

I met and formed friendships with people from such far flung locations as: England; Maritime Canada; Melbourne, Australia; Johannesburg, South Africa; Brooklyn, New York; Chapel Hill, North Carolina; London, Ontario and Boise, Idaho – not to mention dozens of Midwesterners for whom the trip was shorter and less arduous.

We discussed plans for the coming months: actions concerning the RNC in St. Paul this September and the G8 summit near Toronto in 2010, as well as innumerable ways to strengthen ourselves and our communities.

We drew the attention of the Milwaukee Sentinel and Fox News, yet, we held fast to our demands to face The Corporate Media on our own terms.

We encountered a strange, dark and mysterious force, and it became (rather than a source of fear) an inspiration to go farther and take greater risks in pursuit of our wildest dreams and desires.

We formed an environment of unprecedented honesty where we spoke truths to people who, a few days earlier, had been complete strangers which, in other circumstances, we could hardly imagine telling ourselves.

By the second day, the locals' curiosity overwhelmed their trepidation, and they came in a steady stream, first, to observe, then, to participate, exclaiming over and over again, "I can't believe it!  Nothing ever happens here!"

In addition to more serious business, there was much beautiful frolicking and frivolity: group meditation to harness the power of the full moon, hours of singalong and joketelling, as well as, a spontaneous nude dance party, the story of which participants will doubtlessly recount for years to come.

All in all, my words can create nothing more than a pathetic game of Connect the Dots.  It is that reason that I wholeheartedly invite everyone who reads this to the next CrimethInc. Convergence, wherever and whenever it happens, so that you can experience it for yourself.

Addendum: My train layover in Chicago on the return trip was three hours longer than expected.  I managed to use that extra time to contact and briefly meet with my sister, brother in law and niece whom I hadn't seen in seven months.]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>663</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[craggie]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[cemajor@uwm.edu]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url/>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[129.89.246.231]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2008-08-02 12:24:00]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2008-08-02 19:24:00]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[Here in Milwaukee, we're doing an art show at our infoshop's gallery with all of the awesome stuff made at the convergence. We want to capture the feeling of this gathering for people who weren't there, and would like to incorporate some written art into the show to do that. We'd really appreciate if people could share their experiences so that we can create one big work of art revolving around the atmosphere that made up the convergence.  If you have a story, poem, notes, or journal entry about something involving the convergence, and wouldn't mind us using it,  just email it to CaE1Ma@aol.com.  Please use discretion, when necessary, with other people's names so that no one would potentially feel uncomfortable. Thanks to everyone for your help in making this convergence happen!]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>664</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[NotoriousGDD]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[notorious@gregorydickson.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url/>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[72.213.180.34]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2008-08-03 15:13:32]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2008-08-03 22:13:32]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[First, I agree with Psedonym. Next time lets make something permanent. I sure wish I had 75 helpers the last time I setup a garden! I have a good amount of experience in urban gardening techniques and would love to help out.

Well, we had an incredible time and it really sucked that we had to leave early. I was there with my wife and 2 year old red-headed daughter (so now you all know who I am). To be in a place, even if for only a short time, where we could be free to have our thoughts respected and some even agreed with!! It was the most welcoming and open experience I have had in years and it was music to our souls. 

Great workshop on small town organizing. We are in a town of 2000 people so you will be hearing from us with many questions.

11Sense, many of us if not all of us share your sentiments. To be able to escape from the dominant industrial capitalist culture that is killing the planet for a few days for even a few days would have been unthinkable to me just a year ago. Now I can't wait for next year and to participate, and contribute everything I can.

Thanks for the great food. Thanks for the help with the kids! You know who you are. Thanks for everyone for providing their own point of view.

One more thing, Lycanhardcore, don't think just because you were 'impure' that you were not worthy of anything (food, the convergence, etc). You are not a poser, you made the decision to come to the convergence and that is enough. The moment you decided not to think the same thoughts as the ones around you deserved the community of the convergence. In order for us to open these ideas to people around us we cannot be exclusionary just because someone does something for a living, or drives a car or owns a house. We have to be open to all walks, etc., as long as they are willing to support our actions. We all have our role to play. Some may be taking direct action, some may provide a place to hide for people that have taken direct action, some may merely cook food for those that take direct action, some may only write letters to a newspaper coming out in support of a direct action. We need it all. You were 'worthy' the moment you decided something was wrong and you wanted to do something about it. You are awesome and I can't wait to meet you at next years convergence.

-G]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>665</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[b. traven]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[b@crimethinc.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url>http://www.crimethinc.com</wp_comment_author_url>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[74.60.183.29]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2008-12-09 02:28:25]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2008-12-09 09:28:25]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[Crimethinc Convergence Report Back

August 12, 2008
This report comes from some Grand Rapids area anarchists that attended the annual Crimethinc convergence:

Several weeks ago, over 150 anarchists gathered in Waldo, Wisconsin for the 2008 Crimethinc Convergence. The Convergence took place on the edge of town, in a privately owned field bordered on three sides by woods and just off of a rarely trafficked road. Some came from as far away as South Africa and Germany, while others came from the United States and Canada to attend the sixth annual gathering of the Ex-Workers Collective. After carpooling from the meet-up point in Milwaukee, most folks set up their tents and began introducing themselves to new arrivals. By late afternoon, a storm had descended upon the campers, complete with sheets of heavy rain and tumultuous wind at 70 mph.

Day two began with an opening circle in which everyone met around the fire pit to lay down the ground rules for respect of the site and respect for each other, as well as a run-through of the workshops scheduled for the day. Once discussion broke, many campers hurried back to their tents to build make-shift clotheslines to dry everything that had gotten wet the night before. By the time the sun came out, folks had eaten breakfast served by the volunteer crew at the designated kitchen tent and were on their way to the workshops.

Workshops were held every day and ranged from a variety of issues and topics, including participatory workshops on spokescouncils, police tactics and blockades; resource sharing workshops such as small town organizing, creating your own media, shoplifting techniques, and DIY sexual health; report-back style workshops that served to inform folks about the organizing around the most recent G8 summit, South African anarchist resistance to racism, and workshops concerning plugging into actions and updates on organizing against the construction of the NAFTA superhighway I-69 in Indiana, the Democratic and Republican National Conventions in Denver and the Twin Cities respectively, the 2010 Olympics that are scheduled to be held on stolen native land in Vancouver, and the 2010 G8 summit north of Toronto.

Throughout the Convergence, tents were set up for specific things like arts and crafts, a zine library, childcare, medical needs, and a prisoner writing station. These tents were operated by volunteers and allowed for individuals with specific needs and interests to take part in the week's events.

Every evening there were events and games near the campfire. One night there was a Cabaret in which everyone was encouraged to participate. Some played instruments and sang, some formed dance troupes, a couple performed poetry and a few told jokes. There were puppet shows, burlesque acts, and juggling. The only glitch to the Cabaret was a poorly thought-out dance that was culturally insensitive--but the issue was quickly and appropriately addressed and brought about healthy discussion on white privilege and cultural appropriation. Following the Cabaret there was a performance by a hip-hop artist that spun poetic lyrics condemning sexism, racism, police brutality and capitalism. After the scheduled events of the evening came to a close, about 30 or so people participated in an interactive lesson on consent--they played consensual spin-the-bottle.

The last full day of the Convergence was intended primarily for caucuses. The white privilege caucus and the anarchist people of color (APOC) caucus met as planned through most of the afternoon. The APOC caucus discussed the problem of radical spaces- including the Convergence--of being predominantly white-dominated spaces, while the white privilege caucus talked about what white radicals could do to be more inclusive and conscious of race dynamics. There were also a significant number of folks who chose not to attend either caucus--many citing that while they felt that they often benefited from white privilege, they did not identify as white and their cultural experiences were such that they felt that they could not contribute to the white privilege caucus. Several of these people also stated that they would feel uncomfortable attending the APOC caucus.

There were other caucuses that were suggested, but unfortunately never took place. Such caucuses included the women's caucus, queer caucus, and working class caucus, and respectively, the auxiliaries for male privilege, hetero privilege, and class privilege. The fact that such discussions failed to take place reflects the constant struggle for space that continues to be an issue even amongst the radical community.

The final night in Waldo, more than 60 people left the site to take part in a home demonstration some 20 miles out, at the residence of an engineer working for the company Earth Tech. Earth Tech is a company that has been involved in developing and financing transportation projects such as I-69, and because of the engineer's role in the company, as well as his proximity to the Convergence space, the action was carried out at his home in Grafton, Wisconsin. Protesters held banners and chanted things like "Stop I-69," and "You can put our friends in Jail, but we will drive the final nail!" Flyers were handed out to his neighbors and other passer-bys and were generally well perceived. After the action, folks returned to the camp site where there was a brief re-cap followed by a midnight naked swim in the nearby lake.

The next couple of hours consisted of cleaning the campsite, goodbyes, and the last minute rush to find a ride home. Unfortunately, there was not adequate time or space to discuss in a large group or breakout small groups what worked, what didn't work, and how the next convergence can be bigger and better (or at least better).

One of the questions organizers should ask themselves is how can to open these convergences to become more empowering to marginalized groups of people, and raise the consciousness of those in positions of privilege. One way to do this is create the space and time for these caucuses, but also encourage and emphasize that it's important as radicals to understand and discuss the internalized racism, sexism, homophobia, class struggle, and other forms of systematic oppression so it doesn't continue to manifest itself in our communities.

These convergences serve as a living model of how people can work collectively to create the kind of world they want on a smaller scale. They show us how we can come together as a community, share with each other, care for each other and bring new ideas to our communities. Some ideas for the next convergence is more interaction with the community in which the convergence takes place in. Whether it be a parade, gardening, music, free childcare, sharing food, etc it seems that as a group of anarchists in one area we could create something WITH the community at large.

Folks from Grand Rapids have high hopes for the convergence next year and hope to see more people from the area ready and motivated to create radical social change in West Michigan.

In Solidarity,
- Some Grand Rapids Anarchists]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>2</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
	</item>