<item>
		<title>Hundreds of Billions of Dollars</title>
		<link>http://www.crimethinc.com/blog/2008/09/24/hundreds-of-billions-of-dollars/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2008 17:31:54 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc_creator><![CDATA[b. traven]]></dc_creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.crimethinc.com/blog/?p=371</guid>
		<description/>
		<content_encoded><![CDATA[<img src="https://cloudfront.crimethinc.com/images/wall_street/wall_street.jpg" alt="" /><span class="invisible">-</span>
<em>Report courtesy of the Center for Strategic Anarchy, in cooperation with the CrimethInc. Free Marketeers. The CSA will begin posting regularly again <a href="http://anarchiststrategy.blogspot.com/" target="_blank">on their blog</a> shortly.</em>

What the hell is going on with <a href="http://online.wsj.com/article_email/SB122169431617549947-lMyQjAxMDI4MjExODYxOTg0Wj.html#project%3DSLIDESHOW08" target="_blank">the economy</a>? As part of our commitment to serve all the investors, bankers, and realty agents who rely on this site, we've solicited a brief introductory analysis.

Capitalism without failure is like religion without sin—it just doesn't work. Far from abnormal, the boom/bust cycle is as predictable as the furious scapegoating and wild-eyed cheerleading that accompany it. But every situation, even the most predictable, presents unique opportunities. We present this analysis in the interest of deriving strategic advantages from our enemies' temporary imbalance.

<!--more-->

So what exactly is going on with the economy right now? The only honest answer is that no one is exactly sure. The American financial system operates on a variety of levels of transparency, making it impossible to know with certainty who has what and how much it is worth. The system also relies upon a high level of interconnectedness between different institutions and industries, making it difficult to predict the implications of failure.

But we can identify a few things that may give us the beginnings of a coherent answer.

The basic outline of the situation is this: starting in the mid-1990's, the American government began deregulating the banking industry, repealing laws that had governed the terms of credit and investment since the Great Depression, due in large part to the money-soaked lobbying of commercial banks. Simultaneously, it created institutional and consumer incentives for home buying, motivated in part by statistical evidence that home ownership was the single greatest determinate of a family's financial success. At the same time, the dot-com boom was putting (fake) money into consumers' and bankers' pockets, and although that bubble burst in 2001, it was quickly replaced by a new bubble in real estate.

Thus began a massive surge in home buying. Part of this up-tick in buying was made possible by "sub-prime mortgages": loans with adjustable interest rates given to people who probably can't afford to buy a house in the first place. They function much like credit cards: if homebuyers miss a payment, which they are likely to do, the interest rate doubles or even triples, dramatically increasing the cost of their monthly payments. These were attractive loans for banks to make since they assumed that all but a few homeowners would continue making payments after the upward adjustment of their interest rates.

The scheme seems idiotic in hindsight. A huge rise in demand for homes led to rapidly rising real estate values. To keep the market booming, less qualified buyers were found and given sub-prime mortgages to buy houses at inflated prices. Because prices were rising and wages were stagnant, lots of people with sub-prime mortgages were unable to keep up with payments. Their interest rates rose, but instead of paying banks a premium, many of them had to stop paying entirely. Now, at least two million of the seven million sub-prime mortgages used to buy homes since 1998 are expected to default.

What exactly led to the failures of Lehman Brothers, AIG, Morgan Stanley, Fannie Mae, and Freddie Mac, the news of which has cable news anchors on the verge of tears? The precise answer is more complicated than space allows. To put it in very general terms, the trading of sub-prime loans became a market unto itself, a market that was almost completely unregulated and pushed to wildly unrealistic heights by mountains of debt. When the loans themselves started going bad, the obscure little financial products based on them—which had been virtually printing money for investment banks—turned to shit. All of a sudden banks had a lot less money, making it impossible for some of them to pay for everything else they do.

Now, the U.S government is planning to buy most of those bad loans for $700 billion. This will take them off the balance sheets of banks and put them on the balance sheet of the Federal government. Naturally, Wall Street is ecstatic, for the moment.

Where things go from here is difficult to predict, but we can safely assume that there will be a lot less money floating around for loans, at least for a while. This means businesses will have a harder time expanding and fewer people will be able to afford homes, cars, and higher educations. This will have broad negative implications for the economy and growth will almost definitely slow; whether that will be an apocalyptic recession or a brief lull is up for debate. And if the federal government ends up spending upward of $1 trillion bailing out failing businesses, we can expect less government spending for a good long while.

What does all of this mean for anarchists and our projects? It means that our context is about to change. As if the change in presidential administration weren't enough of a game-changer, this will shift the terrain even more. Here's some highly subjective advice for taking advantage of the new circumstances:

1) This is going to sound insane, but if you have been thinking about buying a house or land, try to do it in the next 18 months, especially if you won't need a mortgage. Reasonable mortgages will be hard to come by, even if you have good credit, but real estate prices are going to continue to drop. Looking at a house priced in the low five figures or less in some dying Rust Belt city? Negotiate downward as much as possible—which you'll likely have the leverage to do—and pull the trigger.

In places like Greece, anarchist neighborhoods—yes, neighborhoods—are the foundation from which much anarchist resistance, from community meals to bank robberies, is launched. This could be our generation's chance to establish something similar.

2) Be the wrecking ball to gentrification's fragile edifice. The housing bubble facilitated the rapid gentrification that has transformed many neglected inner-city neighborhoods into atrocious playgrounds for young affluent types. During that process, anarchists weren't exactly the sand in gentrification's proverbial diesel engine. Now we have the chance to make up some ground.

The credit crunch will make it temporarily more difficult to expand or even maintain the current reach of gentrification, leaving gentrifying areas more vulnerable to resistance. The recent RNC solidarity actions in Pittsburgh have been an inspiration to many, but keep in mind that going on the offensive also means establishing alternatives that allow more and more of us to survive and resist outside of the labor market. If mutual aid can effectively substitute for spending money, that can be just as damaging to business as a broken window.

3) Propagandize. The contraction of the economy and the change in presidential administration both provide powerful propaganda opportunities. We can offer a unique economic analysis by providing a total critique of capitalism—prominently explaining the natural role played by the boom/bust cycle—and offer the immediate, tangible alternative of mutual aid, unlike authoritarian Leftists who can offer only ineffectual protest and a dystopian vision of the future. Anti-capitalist and anti-political propaganda that is intelligible and relevant to non-anarchists will play better over the next year or two.

That said, you can't fire a cannon from a canoe. Propaganda alone is just more useless paper. It should function as a component of direct action, whether that means <a href="http://www.crimethinc.com/texts/recentfeatures/reallyreally.php" target="_self">Really Really Free Markets</a> or <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=q7_VbnpAvI0" target="_blank">riots</a>. When it appears as part of an amazing experience or a useful gift, what otherwise would have appeared to be extremist claptrap is suddenly worth reading.]]></content_encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp_post_id>371</wp_post_id>
		<wp_post_date><![CDATA[2008-09-24 10:31:54]]></wp_post_date>
		<wp_post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2008-09-24 17:31:54]]></wp_post_date_gmt>
		<wp_comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp_comment_status>
		<wp_ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp_ping_status>
		<wp_post_name><![CDATA[hundreds-of-billions-of-dollars]]></wp_post_name>
		<wp_status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp_status>
		<wp_post_parent>0</wp_post_parent>
		<wp_menu_order>0</wp_menu_order>
		<wp_post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp_post_type>
		<wp_post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp_post_password>
		<wp_is_sticky>0</wp_is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="read-all-about-it"><![CDATA[Read All About It]]></category>
		<wp_postmeta>
			<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp_meta_key>
			<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp_meta_value>
		</wp_postmeta>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>699</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[b. traven]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[b@crimethinc.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url>http://www.crimethinc.com</wp_comment_author_url>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[74.60.183.29]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2008-09-24 12:49:37]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2008-09-24 19:49:37]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[Stories about the RNC solidarity actions in Pittsburgh, referenced in the recommendations above, can be found here:

http://news.infoshop.org/article.php?story=2008083120243184&query=pittsburgh
http://news.infoshop.org/article.php?story=20080901052144720&query=pittsburgh]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>2</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>700</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[Pseudonym]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[mtx7669@juno.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url>http://</wp_comment_author_url>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[70.94.40.138]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2008-09-24 22:44:38]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2008-09-25 05:44:38]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[As usual, brilliant and concise commentary.  I look forward to the return of CSA and the discussions it fosters.  I hate to be a pain, but are there any links to verify or provide more info on the two of seven million loan defaults and the greek anarchist neighborhoods?

Personally, I'm excited that you mention the neighborhoods.  This is something that I've been thinking a lot about lately, particularly in reference to the European focused articles in Rolling Thunder 5.  I would like to have a discussion on the strategic and ethical pros and cons of moving to already established anarchist neighborhoods, assuming they want an influx of anarchists.  Moving to a neighborhood may be much more economically feasible than purchasing land that the state may or may not decide to let us keep (I69/eminent domain anyone?).  In what ways can anarchist resistance be more effective by adding to established anarchist neighborhoods and abandoning those previously lived in?  In what ways is it more effective to stay and build those communities and neighborhoods?

Perhaps there is a better forum for this discussion, but for now I encourage people to discuss this issue and the points raised in the above article.

-p]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>701</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[SalmonGod]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[SalmonGod@gmail.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url/>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[24.33.248.139]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2008-09-24 22:59:53]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2008-09-25 05:59:53]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[$700 billion dollars to be spent in corporate bailout

At the same time, the United Nations calls for .001% of that to save millions of people from imminent starvation.  Will America come to their rescue?

It's hard to produce a more obvious and massive scale demonstration of the values of American authority.

<a href="http://en.wikinews.org/w/index.php?title=United_Nations_requests_US$700_million_in_aid_for_East_Africa_to_avoid_famine&amp;curid=113373" rel="nofollow">UN requests US$700 million in aid for East Africa to avoid famine.</a>]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>703</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[ismac76]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[ismac76@gmail.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url>http://</wp_comment_author_url>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[67.241.81.149]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2008-09-28 21:38:40]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2008-09-29 04:38:40]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[These neighborhoods described (ala Greece) are aka base communities and are essential to any dual power strategy.
 some ideas....
people with good credit , looking to actualize this concept  could look into forming land trusts to shelter those among us with bad credit, provided they aren't purely leeches or scammers who will suck the organization dry. A means of production (some kind of business) attached to the base community (I once read about watchmakers in the Jura region of Switzerland who were anarchists, prob in the 19th c.)  that has the capacity to provide for basic human needs, with those who are deeply indebted  could then further default on their loans and further destabilize the situation.
This would be a fitting response in the class war  to the debt bomb and its bailout (if the people who can best afford to pay for their messes are let off the hook so why should any of us honor our debts to any of their institutions?), and would have the unintended effect of limiting those escaping from debt from the excessive consumption that is not only consuming the earth and it's life support systems, it already kicked their ass and fuels the corporate/police state. The trick would be to own nothing on paper, so there is nothing to garnish, nothing to be sued for(debtors prisons may however return if this idea actually worked). If members identities were protected and there was no other reason to go looking for them (like egregious criminal stuff ) maybe they could disappear into a hole in the capitalist fabric. This would also give members little incentive to rejoin civil society at large.
FYI, buy guns ammo, and reloading equipment with those  credit cards before you walk away.

B/C If anything really does destabilize, if the economy suddenly can't or won't produce enough food, clothing SUV's and trinkets,you'll want to be in an eco-fortified villiage, not the regular kind. All I'm saying is that ignorance and violence have been brewed on a vast scale in this society and don't expect some 1000 years of peace right after this behemoth sinks. Maybe some people will turn out to be better than expected, maybe a sense of community will come together. Realistically, though expect people to act totally spastic, irrational and evil(I know it's a dualistic word, forgive me, I was raised here). It's far better to be let down on the latter than to expect the former. Now is no time for solutions with magical thinking worked into the logic. If you're the one with all food and stuff, from hard work and permaculture thinking, when walmart is burnt out and empty, eventually your collective efforts may recieve attention of a similar kind from people who are in "survival mode".
which brings me back around to destabilization in the first place.....
dual power is about easing that transition, building that community 1st so it can give people some idea of why they shouldn't kill each other when the mob mentality takes over. So we can protect ourselves and maintain autonomy when faced with that mob mentality.


another thought....
If you are willing to risk the wrath of the IRS, protest this give away by exempting yourself from federal withholding if you aren't already. This is a good transitional tactic if some debt shelter communities were to emerge.  Of course you may give them cause to hunt you down if you don't pay  it next april, It might be worth a discussion of pros and cons. Of course it may not matter when we compete with zimbabwe for worst inflation on the face of the earth after we realize the effects of the other countries no longer subsidizing our binges. That alone has more potential to destabilize our country than anyone seems to be letting on or recognizing. Their incentives for buying our shit mopping treasury instruments again?]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>704</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[lobsterbeard]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[lobsterbeard@gmail.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url>http://</wp_comment_author_url>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[98.164.87.243]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2008-09-29 14:26:42]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2008-09-29 21:26:42]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[I tried to post this a few days ago, but it didn't work for some reason.

Glad you liked the post Pseudonym. Here are some links:

Greek anarchist neighborhood:

http://www.anarchistnews.org/?q=node/1206
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Exarcheia

And 2 million foreclosures:

http://realtytimes.com/rtpages/20070608_nationdoomed.htm
http://www.cnn.com/2007/US/03/29/subprime.congress/index.html]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>705</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[farmer]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[b3jamboree@yahoo.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url/>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[70.105.125.64]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2008-10-16 07:27:44]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2008-10-16 14:27:44]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[My wife and I are using this opportunity for cheap land to start a farm. We have worked in agriculture for years and bounced around various activist communities in Seattle and Detroit.
  We have always tried to inspire people to 'leave Babylon' and come start a collective farm, but no one was interested in putting money where their mouths were. Now we can afford to do it on our own and are hoping to lead by example.
  If this crisis turns out to be a  deep depression one of the above posters is absolutely correct; you will not want to be in the city. But in a situation where you can support your own most basic needs without and assistance from the outside world.
  Hopefully our endeavor is a success at least by providing us the means to expand and increase our capacity to support more people. So if the bottom really does fall out we will be able to take people forge a good life for ourselves, independent from the capitalist system.]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
	</item>