<item>
    <title>Poster: Support the RNC Arrestees!</title>
    <link>http://www.crimethinc.com/blog/2008/09/27/poster-support-the-rnc-arrestees/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 27 Sep 2008 15:42:39 +0000</pubDate>
    <dc_creator><![CDATA[ret marut]]></dc_creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.crimethinc.com/blog/?p=377</guid>
    <description/>
    <content_encoded><![CDATA[<a href="https://cloudfront.crimethinc.com/images/rnc/rnc_arrestees_b.gif" rel="lightbox"><img src="https://cloudfront.crimethinc.com/images/rnc/rnc_arrestees_a.gif" /></a>We've just finished a new poster, as a humble effort to support those who were caught up in <a href="http://antiauthoritarian.net/NLN/?p=484" target="_blank">the repression</a> that accompanied the Republican National Convention earlier this month. Please print these out and put them up wherever people might see them. Better yet, organize benefits to raise funds and awareness for the <a href="http://www.rnc8.org" target="_blank">organizers</a> being charged with felony "conspiracy to riot in furtherance of terrorism" and others facing <a href="http://bombsandshields.blogspot.com/2008/09/legal-updates-from-rnc-protests-in-st.html" target="_blank">serious charges</a>.

<strong><a href="https://cloudfront.crimethinc.com/pdfs/rnc_arrestees.pdf" target="_blank">Download Poster PDF [335 KB]</a></strong>

<!--more Poster text after the jump.-->

<strong>SUPPORT THE RNC ARRESTEES</strong>

At the conclusion of the 2008 Republican National Convention, police and federal agents had arrested 159 people for supposed felonies; within two weeks, <a href="http://www.twincities.com/ci_10464876?nclick_check=1" target="_blank">they dropped 140 of those charges</a>, a frank acknowledgment that they had fabricated the charges for sake of intimidation. At events like the RNC, we can see that the authorities take the law even less seriously than anarchists: for them, it is not a means of effecting justice, but only of exerting control.

19 people still have felony trials pending from the RNC, not to mention the hundreds who may be tried for misdemeanors. The majority of these 19 cases are based on the testimony of paid police informants who will say anything to help the government get a conviction. Eight local organizers face felony conspiracy trials, the first of this kind since the notorious show trial following the 1968 Democratic National Convention in which the defendants were all declared innocent after four years.

These cases affect all of us. They are intended to set new precedents for legal repression, to make it easier for the government to suppress dissent. The outcome of the trials will not be determined solely by the evidence but by how much power we can bring to bear by means of fundraising and political pressure. As state-sponsored efforts to silence us escalate, supporting these defendants is simply self-defense.

For more information:
<a href="http://coldsnaplegal.org" target="_blank">coldsnaplegal.org</a>
<a href="http://rnc8.org" target="_blank">rnc8.org</a>]]></content_encoded>
    <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
    <wp_post_id>377</wp_post_id>
    <wp_post_date><![CDATA[2008-09-27 08:42:39]]></wp_post_date>
    <wp_post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2008-09-27 15:42:39]]></wp_post_date_gmt>
    <wp_comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp_comment_status>
    <wp_ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp_ping_status>
    <wp_post_name><![CDATA[poster-support-the-rnc-arrestees]]></wp_post_name>
    <wp_status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp_status>
    <wp_post_parent>0</wp_post_parent>
    <wp_menu_order>0</wp_menu_order>
    <wp_post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp_post_type>
    <wp_post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp_post_password>
    <wp_is_sticky>0</wp_is_sticky>
    <category domain="category" nicename="calling-all-anarchists"><![CDATA[Calling All Anarchists]]></category>
    <wp_postmeta>
      <wp_meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp_meta_key>
      <wp_meta_value><![CDATA[3]]></wp_meta_value>
    </wp_postmeta>
    <wp_comment>
      <wp_comment_id>711</wp_comment_id>
      <wp_comment_author><![CDATA[b. traven]]></wp_comment_author>
      <wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[b@crimethinc.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
      <wp_comment_author_url>http://www.crimethinc.com</wp_comment_author_url>
      <wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[74.60.183.29]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
      <wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2008-12-03 15:22:49]]></wp_comment_date>
      <wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2008-12-03 22:22:49]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
      <wp_comment_content><![CDATA[News as of December 3:

The number of cases dismissed by St. Paul City Attorney John Choi this week is at 30 according to CRASS, all but three of which were scheduled for trial on December 15. Many of the cases are from the Shepherd Road and 7th/Jackson parking lot mass arrests. A minimum of 63 misdemeanor/gross misdemeanor cases have now been dismissed and a dozen others declined for prosecution.

Numbers reported in the Pioneer Press show that of 171 cases either resolved or ongoing, 10 have bench warrants, 27 have been resolved, 62 are still open (that is, the accused are fighting the charges), and 72 have been declined or dismissed. Numbers calculated by CRASS are slightly different, but with a similar average of 75-80% of cases either being challenged or having been dismissed. The number of cases resolved or ongoing - 171 - is starkly short of the 808 arrests during the RNC. The massive arrest of 396 people during John McCain's acceptance speech is still being mulled over by Choi's office.]]></wp_comment_content>
      <wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
      <wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
      <wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
      <wp_comment_user_id>2</wp_comment_user_id>
    </wp_comment>
  </item>