<item>
		<title>From the Depths recording debut: “Germinate”</title>
		<link>http://www.crimethinc.com/blog/2009/02/19/from-the-depths-recording-debut-germinate/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2009 03:03:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc_creator><![CDATA[b. traven]]></dc_creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.crimethinc.com/blog/?p=609</guid>
		<description/>
		<content_encoded><![CDATA[Anarchist punk band <a href="http://www.fromthedepths.info/" target="_blank">From the Depths</a>, currently <a href="http://www.fromthedepths.info/shows.html" target="_blank">on tour in the US</a>, have just finished their <a href="http://www.fromthedepths.info/music.html" target="_blank">debut album</a>. Recorded at Mars Studio (known for recording Catharsis, Undying, and scores of more famous hardcore bands), <a href="http://www.fromthedepths.info/music.html" target="_blank">“Germinate”</a> comprises 7 songs in 36 minutes, an epic paean to self-determination and resistance.

Hearkening back to the days when anarcho-punk was characterized by bands as diverse as Crass, Chumbawumba, and Contropotere, the songs on this album combine d-beat power, slower and faster hardcore, harsh noise, and even a passage from a traditional Italian anarchist folk ballad. This is intense, defiant, dark music, but it is based in compelling melodies; you can scream these songs at the top of your lungs in a riot, but you could also sing them quietly to yourself in jail to maintain your spirits.

From the Depths was formed at the beginning of 2008 by members of Catharsis, Requiem, Network of Terror, Auryn, and Balaclava. Traveling in a van donated by <a href="/blog/2008/04/28/free-market-in-winona/">Winona’s Really Really Free Market</a> after their vegetable-oil-powered truck died mid-tour, they performed for fellow demonstrators outside the 2008 Democratic and Republican National Conventions; they’ve also played benefit shows for RNC arrestees, <a href="/texts/recentfeatures/greenscared.php">Green Scare</a> defendants, and other prisoners in the anticapitalist struggle.

We’re trying a new experiment with this release, <a href="http://www.fromthedepths.info/music.html" target="_blank">making it available via online downloading</a>. We’re hardly convinced that the internet is a positive thing for humanity, but we recognize that it is one of the primary ways people get music these days. In order to offset the tendency of internet downloading to separate music from the context that gives it meaning, the download includes all the lyrics, artwork, and liner notes.

The band paid $3100 to record the album, and mastering cost another several hundred dollars. Presuming that at least 1000 people are interested in the record, we’re requesting that people donate $4 in return for downloading it. If you have particular access to resources, consider donating more to cover those who have less; to do so, simply increase the number in the “Quantity” column of your order. As soon as the recording and mastering expenses are covered, we’ll make downloading free; thus any donation goes towards making this available to everyone. If you can help the band break even on the costs of recording, that will also help them to play more benefit shows so as to contribute more than music to the public.

<!--more More info and tour dates after the jump.-->

We recognize that not everyone has the means to donate money or download music via the internet. From the Depths is also selling a CD version on a sliding scale, and hope to be able to make downloading free shortly. Ideally, everything would be free; unfortunately, until there is a revolution, recording will cost money, and the band is asking you to help pay for this so they can put their personal money into community projects and prisoner support. If there’s absolutely no way you can make a donation over the internet or order the CD from us, email <a href="mailto:booking@fromthedepths.info">booking@fromthedepths.info</a> to figure something out.

From the Depths is on tour on the West Coast right now. Here are the dates; email <a href="mailto:booking@fromthedepths.info">booking@fromthedepths.info</a> for more information about specific shows.

February
&gt; t 17 Tucson, AZ
&gt; w 18 San Diego, CA
&gt; th 19 Tijuana, Mexico
&gt; f 20 Mexicali, Mexico
&gt; s 21 Santa Barbara, CA
&gt; sn 22 Santa Cruz, CA
&gt; m 23 Arcata, CA
&gt; w 25 Medford, OR
&gt; th 26 Eugene, OR
&gt; f 27 Portland, OR
&gt; s 28 Olympia, WA

March
&gt; w 4 Port Townsend, WA
&gt; th 5 Bremerton, WA
&gt; f 6 Seattle, WA
&gt; s 7 Tacoma, WA
&gt; sn 8 Salem, OR
&gt; t 10 Redding, CA
&gt; w 11 Reno, NV
&gt; th 12 Modesto, CA
&gt; f 13 Oakland, CA
&gt; sn 15 Berkeley, CA
&gt; m 16 Riverside, CA
&gt; t 17 Flagstaff, AZ
&gt; w 18 El Paso, TX
&gt; th 19 Austin, TX
&gt; f 20 Baton Rouge, LA
&gt; s 21 somewhere in GA
&gt; sn 22 Carrboro, NC]]></content_encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp_post_id>609</wp_post_id>
		<wp_post_date><![CDATA[2009-02-19 19:03:41]]></wp_post_date>
		<wp_post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2009-02-20 03:03:41]]></wp_post_date_gmt>
		<wp_comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp_comment_status>
		<wp_ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp_ping_status>
		<wp_post_name><![CDATA[from-the-depths-recording-debut-germinate]]></wp_post_name>
		<wp_status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp_status>
		<wp_post_parent>0</wp_post_parent>
		<wp_menu_order>0</wp_menu_order>
		<wp_post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp_post_type>
		<wp_post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp_post_password>
		<wp_is_sticky>0</wp_is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="hot-off-the-presses"><![CDATA[Hot Off the Presses]]></category>
		<wp_postmeta>
			<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp_meta_key>
			<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp_meta_value>
		</wp_postmeta>
		<wp_postmeta>
			<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[_thumbnail_id]]></wp_meta_key>
			<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[3188]]></wp_meta_value>
		</wp_postmeta>
		<wp_postmeta>
			<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[jumbo]]></wp_meta_key>
			<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[https://cloudfront.crimethinc.com/music/ftd_spread_900.gif]]></wp_meta_value>
		</wp_postmeta>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>893</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[Pseudonym]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[mtx7669@juno.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url>http://</wp_comment_author_url>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[70.94.40.138]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2009-02-22 14:18:17]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2009-02-22 22:18:17]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[The sample sounds really good.  Where will CDs be available?  Does any money from CD sales go toward covering the $3100?  Also, I'd like to make a bulk 'recipes' order in the next two weeks but am thinking about waiting for the new rolling thunder.  Any word on how long before RT7 is out?

Sorry for all the questions yall, just want to know what's up.

p]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>894</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[b. traven]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[b@crimethinc.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url>http://www.crimethinc.com</wp_comment_author_url>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[24.6.95.30]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2009-02-23 01:37:24]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2009-02-23 09:37:24]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[CDs will be available for ordering quite soon, along with the new issue of Rolling Thunder, which is currently at press.]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>2</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>895</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[pfm]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[pfm@crimethinc.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url>http://crimethinc.com/blog</wp_comment_author_url>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[75.164.145.177]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2009-02-24 09:31:15]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2009-02-24 17:31:15]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[Odds are very good that we will be accepting orders for RT#7 on March 3rd. Wait till you see how great this issue is, wooohooo!]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>1</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>896</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[Q.V.]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[quilliam@tildeathlongboards.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url>http://</wp_comment_author_url>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[24.57.121.65]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2009-03-03 10:27:01]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2009-03-03 18:27:01]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[Very happy with this album and would like to pick up a hard copy too.
The guitars sound phenomenal.

Pumped to see FTD again, hopefully you'll make it to Detroit sometime in the not-to-distant future.]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>897</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[LudicFeral]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[resist4peace@aol.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url/>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[75.83.139.193]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2009-03-03 23:47:46]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2009-03-04 07:47:46]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[Just wondering where exactly the oakland show is going to be and if there will be a cover charge. Me and my friends are looking for something to do that night before the bookfair the following day.  I also cant wait for the cd's and the new RT to become available.]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>898</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[desiderata]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[desiderata@riseup.net]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url>http://myspace.com/windchimehose</wp_comment_author_url>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[71.107.195.5]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2009-03-06 10:20:32]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2009-03-06 18:20:32]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[Let the black flag fly
Let the conquerors crawl
Let them lecture on justice
With their backs to the wall
Can you even remember
Breathing freely at all
Let us lose all our fear and let loose all our tears
Let a hard rain fall

fuck yes! can't wait to pick up a copy]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>899</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[b. traven]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[b@crimethinc.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url>http://www.crimethinc.com</wp_comment_author_url>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[76.191.156.196]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2009-03-13 11:45:44]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2009-03-13 19:45:44]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[Here's a review from http://www.lasthours.org.uk/reviews/from-the-depths/:

‘From the Depths’ formed in early 2008 and have recently released their debut album ‘Germinate’ through CrimethInc. The band is made up of members of Catharsis, Requiem, Network of Terror, Auryn and Balaclava. They have already toured within the states and played many benefits in solidarity with Green scare victims, prisoners in the anticapitalist struggle and those of us facing the reprisals of the attempted riots/blockades at the Republican National Convention in September 2008. This album is a prodigy of dark, epic and resonant music.

It might take those used to the rough vocal styling of Catharsis/Requiem by surprise when Monica’s powerful yet melodic vocals explode into the song after the initial shout of “Let the black flags fly!”, but you will soon realize how uncompromising and harmonic they make this opening track. Throughout, Monica is backed up by Brian and Neil’s harsh vocals, keeping the intensity of hardcore punk, especially with Catharsis style double kick pedal. They sing with intense and inspiring passion about striking back with a vengeance and the potential of all the exploited, described as “blisters of violence swelling to burst”, holy shit…

The second track, ‘Last Transmission’ is an epic tale of the insurrection in Oaxaca, Mexico. The title refers to an occupied radio station, the last building remaining in the hands of the people after the autonomous zone was taken back by the federal police a month after the uprising began. The space was not lost without intense pitched battles in the streets and unfortunately the life of Indy media journalist, committed anarchist and friend Brad Will. A technical riff that ruptures into a powerful d-beat sets the scene. Quieter guitar breaks slow it down for the anger and strength of the bi-lingual lyrics that speak for standing together and fighting back despite the reprisals of violence and state repression for simply desiring autonomy.

The next song, ‘Murderers’ exemplifies the bands willingness to experiment. They integrate hardcore with noise music and it works particularly well into a lengthy, anticipatory build up. This is the song that stuck in my memory after the first time I saw ‘From the Depths’. Opening with an intimidating, heavyset riff, the song develops into an all out assault against apathy, neutrality and ironically apolitical attitudes. They send a clear message to all those who can afford to sit comfortably and chose to do nothing against systematic abuse, that there are no excuses, “every blow you let fall, you’re accomplices, all murderers”.

I expect a great many of us can relate to the personal message written about the song ‘Marathon’. Steve (bass) describes feelings of loneliness within the bustling metropolis of North American cities. These emotions gave him a great appreciation for his experiences and relationships and how this crowded isolation is motivation enough for resistance. Double kick pedal punches through the intro as abstract lyrics echo over the unrelenting pace building up into a chorus of Monica’s almost operatic melody. The song is dominated by a set of (en)chanting lyrics, that will get stuck in your head for days on end.

Mixing it up a bit, ‘Dirge’ is a dark and heavy slow paced metal track. The drummer, Geoff, refers the lyrics to his experiences of resisting a squat eviction from religious property developers. Although it is not literally mentioned I would assume he is describing the eviction and eventual destruction of Ungdomshuset in Copenhagen, Denmark in 2007,(http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ungdomshuset). Although the short term battle was lost, the seed was planted for the growth of defiant and strengthened community networks.

‘A Sante Caserio’ is a traditional anarchist ballad sung alone by Monica. Although this song does add to the variety of the album and leads well into the final track, I think that if I did not know the context of the song (it is a good story, explained in the booklet) I would skip over it more than I already do. It is more of an intro to the end of the album than something comparable to the other tracks.

Dedicated to eco defense prisoner Daniel McGowan, ‘Joan of Arc With Hair Aflame’ bursts alive with a beautiful beat down that flows into the classic d-beat and more fierce vocals. With bitterness toward those who look so indifferently upon life as something to be controlled they sing about those who have their lives taken away by despicable judges and jailers and how their memories are the fuel that ignites the future. The beat down returns to end the album as
merciless as it began.

‘From the depths’ have a genuine and absolute abhorrence of authority, a steadfast dedication to fighting all forms of domination and they continue to organize for mutual aid and self-determination. This band prove that their rhetoric is not just for their fans to digest, but an integral part of their lives and ‘germinate’ clearly aims to inspire listeners into action.]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>2</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
	</item>