<item>
		<title>Tragic Death and Call to Action</title>
		<link>http://www.crimethinc.com/blog/2006/10/28/tragic-death-and-call-to-action/</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2006 23:29:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc_creator><![CDATA[peter p]]></dc_creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crimethinc.com/blog/2006/10/28/tragic-death-and-call-to-action/</guid>
		<description/>
		<content_encoded><![CDATA[On Friday, October 27, an incredible indepedent media reporter, environmental activist, musician, and friend was murdered by government-affiliated paramilitaries in Oaxaca, Mexico. His name was Bradley Will, and he was there as an independent journalist supporting the five month-long teacher’s strike and city-wide occupation against the poverty and corruption of that region. He was the most recent of many protesters to be shot down in cold blood by police in the streets of Oaxaca.

To  make it worse, Mexican President Vincente Fox is using Brad’s death as an excuse to invade the region with federal forces and crush the rebellion. A national call to action has been made to take action at Mexican Consulates this Monday to demand a halt to this violent invasion, in remembrance of the values our friend and compañero died for.

For more information on Brad and Oaxaca: <a target="_blank" href="http://www.infoshop.org/inews/article.php?story=20061027184945896">infoshop.org</a> : <a target="_blank" href="http://nyc.indymedia.org/en/2006/10/77757.html">indymedia.org</a>

For a listing of all the Mexican consulates in North America, <a target="_blank" href="http://www.embassyofmexico.org/eng/index.php?option=com_content&task=view&id=166&Itemid=60">click here</a>.

Some of you may know Brad from the CrimethInc. convergence in Minnesota last summer, at which he presented a workshop on resistance in Latin America. Please accept our condolences. We share your sadness.

<!--more-->

<strong>Call to Action Across the US Against Mexican Consulates</strong>
This is a call to action to remember Brad, show solidarity with the teachers and protesters of Oaxaca, and attempt to interrupt the invasion of Oaxaca that Fox is beginning.

Yesterday, as many who are reading this probably already know, an amazing companero, journalist, anarchist, freedom fighter, earth firster, musician, and human being was shot down and killed in cold blood, along with three other companeros, by officials employed by the Mexican Government. His name was Bradley Will, and he was shot at the barricades of Santa Lucia, in Oaxaca, Mexico, as an indymedia reporter telling the story of the amazing resistance of people of Oaxaca. For over five months residents have occupied the streets in an attempt to oust the corrupt, brutal governor Ruiz, and achieve the dignity, freedom, and autonomy initially sought after by the teacher's strike which was so brutally repressed by that same governor.

While it is not yet clear which segment of the Mexican government is responsible, it is clear from the many photos taken during the shooting that the chief of police, another policeman, and important members of PRI party which supports Ruiz were involved.

To add insult to injury, President Fox is now using the tragedy of these deaths as an excuse to bring in federal forces, to restore "lawfulness." We can only assume, given the student massacre of '68, the history of repression of the Zapatistas by Fox's military, his recent threats to invade Oaxaca, and the fact that his own government is instigated in the murders, that Fox means to repress the rebellion.

Days before we US residents may have been watching Oaxaca, waiting to "see what happens." No longer shall we wait. We are now a part of this unfolding history. If the Mexican Army invades Oaxaca, it will be with the financial and military support of the US government. We can not let this happen.

On Monday morning, October 30th, Mexican consulates around the US will attempt to open their doors, to continue business as usual. But they will not succeed in doing so, because we will be there to stop them. At every embassy, at every consulate, we will be there, to remember Brad, to support the teacher's strike, to fight alongside Oaxacans in their struggle for self-determination and autonomy from the corrupt Mexican government. This call to action against consulates is in line with what companer@s from the APPO have already called for earlier this week before this shooting.

We already know of many groups who are planning for Monday, and every day following if necessary. Please spread this call to action as wide as possible. Spread the word: to activists, teachers, students, earth firsters, latino social services centers, places where day laborers gather, anti-racist action groups, food not bombs chapters, peace and justice organizations, Zapatista solidarity groups, anarchist people of color chapters, people you work with, your neighbors. Copy and paste this the whole world wide, and do so quickly. And please translate a version of this to Spanish as well, and spread it around!

Here is a <a target="_blank" href="http://www.mexonline.com/consulate.htm">directory</a> of all the locations of all the Mexican consulates in the US and Canada.

In memory of my friend, who I know will be with us in spirit,
signed,
a friend and companero of Brad, who is sad, angry, and organizing.]]></content_encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp_post_id>48</wp_post_id>
		<wp_post_date><![CDATA[2006-10-28 16:29:18]]></wp_post_date>
		<wp_post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2006-10-28 23:29:18]]></wp_post_date_gmt>
		<wp_comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp_comment_status>
		<wp_ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp_ping_status>
		<wp_post_name><![CDATA[tragic-death-and-call-to-action]]></wp_post_name>
		<wp_status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp_status>
		<wp_post_parent>0</wp_post_parent>
		<wp_menu_order>0</wp_menu_order>
		<wp_post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp_post_type>
		<wp_post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp_post_password>
		<wp_is_sticky>0</wp_is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="calling-all-anarchists"><![CDATA[Calling All Anarchists]]></category>
		<wp_postmeta>
			<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[_thumbnail_id]]></wp_meta_key>
			<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[3258]]></wp_meta_value>
		</wp_postmeta>
		<wp_postmeta>
			<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[jumbo]]></wp_meta_key>
			<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[http://cloudfront.crimethinc.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2006/10/77817.jpg]]></wp_meta_value>
		</wp_postmeta>
		<wp_postmeta>
			<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp_meta_key>
			<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp_meta_value>
		</wp_postmeta>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>45</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[ryan_empire]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[ryan_abcn@yahoo.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url>http://</wp_comment_author_url>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[209.98.139.19]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2006-10-29 15:10:55]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2006-10-29 22:10:55]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[There is also an electronic blockade. Simply open the link, and leave it in the background.

http://www.mountainrebel.net/oaxaca/]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>46</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[el enemigo comun]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[solidarity@elenemigocomun.net]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url>http://elenemigocomun.net</wp_comment_author_url>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[63.249.117.155]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2006-10-29 21:03:34]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2006-10-30 04:03:34]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[Mexican Consulates in the U.S. &amp; Canada
http://elenemigocomun.net/128

-------------

Oaxaca solidarity:

El Enemigo Común (film and news)
http://elenemigocomun.net

email 'announcement' list
http://lists.riseup.net/www/info/oaxaca

events and actions
http://elenemigocomun.net/category/solidarity]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
	</item>