<item>
    <title>2008 DNC/RNC Mobilizations: Full Report</title>
    <link>http://www.crimethinc.com/blog/2009/05/05/2008-dncrnc-mobilizations-full-report/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2009 18:40:09 +0000</pubDate>
    <dc_creator><![CDATA[pfm]]></dc_creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.crimethinc.com/blog/?p=679</guid>
    <description/>
    <content_encoded><![CDATA[At long last, we’ve completed our <a href="http://www.crimethinc.com/texts/atoz/rncdnc.php">35,000-word full report</a> on last summer’s anarchist mobilizations against the Democratic and Republican National Conventions, complete with chronological maps and painstaking documentation. Updated from the feature in <em><a href="http://www.crimethinc.com/rt/">Rolling Thunder</a></em> #7 and expanded to include the complete text of thirteen different participant narratives, this report offers a comprehensive history of the preparations for, events of, and aftermath following the protests, and an analysis of their context and implications.

Unlike virtually every other analysis yet published from the radical community, this one utilizes subsequent internal government reports, comparing them against a wide variety of other sources. We hope our investigation and the accompanying archive of personal testimonies will prove useful both to participants still trying to understand the events of this past summer and to organizers looking to derive lessons from them for the future.

In a nutshell, we hypothesize that the chief significance of the 2008 anti-convention mobilizations was in the precedents they might set for future organizing. Anarchists took the initiative to determine their own goals and strategies for the protests, establishing decentralized networks throughout the US far in advance. This enabled them to build relationships with other organizing groups and to coordinate their actions, effectively setting the tone for the protests at both conventions. At the same time, the protests were less attended than expected, perhaps as a result of the Obama campaign detracting from street-level participation in the antiwar movement. In this regard, they were the final act of an era that has now passed.

The RNC protests met with an almost unprecedented degree of state repression, which is still playing out today even as the political climate has changed. The federal government continued its strategy of gathering intelligence and entrapping stragglers, already familiar from <a href="http://www.crimethinc.com/texts/recentfeatures/greenscared.php">attacks on environmentalists and animal rights activists</a>. Local authorities focused on infiltration, profiling, and raids, ultimately arresting over 800 people and bringing conspiracy charges against organizers. Despite all this, they seem to have been remarkably unprepared to maintain order in the streets on the first day of the RNC, and their subsequent overreaction helped discredit them in the public eye. Most arrestees have gotten off scot-free; it remains to be seen how the ongoing felony cases will conclude. The outcome of the <a href="http://rnc8.org/" target="_blank">RNC 8</a> conspiracy trial in particular will indicate how sustainable we can expect the organizing model debuted at the 2008 conventions to be.

<strong><a href="/texts/atoz/rncdnc.php">Going It Alone: Anarchist Action at the Democratic  and Republican National Conventions</a></strong>

<strong><a href="/texts/atoz/rnclegal.php">We Are All Legal Workers: Legal Support at the RNC and After</a></strong>

<strong><a href="/texts/atoz/rncdncdocs.php">Accounts from the Democratic  and Republican National Conventions</a></strong>]]></content_encoded>
    <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
    <wp_post_id>679</wp_post_id>
    <wp_post_date><![CDATA[2009-05-05 10:40:09]]></wp_post_date>
    <wp_post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2009-05-05 18:40:09]]></wp_post_date_gmt>
    <wp_comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp_comment_status>
    <wp_ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp_ping_status>
    <wp_post_name><![CDATA[2008-dncrnc-mobilizations-full-report]]></wp_post_name>
    <wp_status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp_status>
    <wp_post_parent>0</wp_post_parent>
    <wp_menu_order>0</wp_menu_order>
    <wp_post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp_post_type>
    <wp_post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp_post_password>
    <wp_is_sticky>0</wp_is_sticky>
    <category domain="category" nicename="from-the-trenches"><![CDATA[From the Trenches]]></category>
    <wp_postmeta>
      <wp_meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp_meta_key>
      <wp_meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp_meta_value>
    </wp_postmeta>
    <wp_postmeta>
      <wp_meta_key><![CDATA[_thumbnail_id]]></wp_meta_key>
      <wp_meta_value><![CDATA[3171]]></wp_meta_value>
    </wp_postmeta>
    <wp_postmeta>
      <wp_meta_key><![CDATA[jumbo]]></wp_meta_key>
      <wp_meta_value><![CDATA[http://www.crimethinc.com/texts/images/rnc1b.jpg]]></wp_meta_value>
    </wp_postmeta>
    <wp_comment>
      <wp_comment_id>934</wp_comment_id>
      <wp_comment_author><![CDATA[Codewarrior]]></wp_comment_author>
      <wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[david-goodner@uiowa.edu]]></wp_comment_author_email>
      <wp_comment_author_url/>
      <wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[173.30.29.114]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
      <wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2009-05-05 16:30:34]]></wp_comment_date>
      <wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2009-05-06 00:30:34]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
      <wp_comment_content><![CDATA[good lookin' out]]></wp_comment_content>
      <wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
      <wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
      <wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
      <wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
    </wp_comment>
    <wp_comment>
      <wp_comment_id>935</wp_comment_id>
      <wp_comment_author><![CDATA[globalactioncatalyst]]></wp_comment_author>
      <wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[spackard@mix.wvu.edu]]></wp_comment_author_email>
      <wp_comment_author_url/>
      <wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[72.50.164.177]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
      <wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2009-05-05 18:13:06]]></wp_comment_date>
      <wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2009-05-06 02:13:06]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
      <wp_comment_content><![CDATA[I found it interesting how in your first essay how you spoke of the anti-globalization movement almost as if it were dead.  Personally I don’t feel its dead, just on vacation.  9/11 and the war in Iraq distracted most activist from it turning their attention to the Anti-War and Anti-Bush movements.  A classic example of white middle class activists skipping around from issue to issue never according to what’s popular, instead of either diving their concentration to all issues or focusing on the one that they feel the most strongly about.  Don’t misunderstand me, I fully support the Anti-War movement, I just feel activist should stick to their guns no madder what issues are popular to resist.  And it’s important for different Anarchist who decide to focus on different issues to support each other.  How many Anarchist group have been ripped apart because of intra-fighting between Red and Green Anarchists?  One can hardly say the movements aren’t related.
    I feel now is a prime time for the Anti-Globalization movement, or to put in broader terms the Anti-Global Capitalism movement, to make a comeback.  Bush is gone; the Iraq War is still waging, but not raging.  Action ageist the war in no way should cease, but now is a prime time to strike the Anti-Capitalist iron whilst it is hot.  The economic downturn is hitting everyone, people will be looking for someone to blame, lets point the figure at Globalization and Capitalism before the Fascists point their figure at the Immigrants and Minorities as they did in Germany before Hitler took power.]]></wp_comment_content>
      <wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
      <wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
      <wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
      <wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
    </wp_comment>
    <wp_comment>
      <wp_comment_id>936</wp_comment_id>
      <wp_comment_author><![CDATA[b. traven]]></wp_comment_author>
      <wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[b@crimethinc.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
      <wp_comment_author_url>http://www.crimethinc.com</wp_comment_author_url>
      <wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[74.60.183.29]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
      <wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2009-05-08 21:37:37]]></wp_comment_date>
      <wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2009-05-09 05:37:37]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
      <wp_comment_content><![CDATA[This is from an email we received recently. We made every effort to research and corroborate information, but some work is never done...

"I was glad to see your analysis from the RNC up on your site. I was a participant in protests at the RNC and there is one correction I must make. The article states "At 11 a.m., the Coalition to March on the RNC and Stop the War rally kicked off at the capitol, while three miles away police prevented Macalester students from leaving to march to the rally site." This is simply not true. Riot police were present at Macalester campus and the university president told them to leave--the police ignored him. The number of police at the campus was small (I personally saw less than 10) and they only video taped our march as it left. Bike police then sort of escorted our march (we didn't have a permit) while only once did a police car buzz close to our march (which only took up one lane of traffic) sirens blaring. As we marched through the neighborhood many people with Obama signs in their yards came outside to observe or more often to join our march. We left and arrived on time, with no arrests directly in the march, although a few blockades went down in our wake, the fate of which I don't know. Our group dispersed at the capitol grounds during the rally. Campus antiwar network went off to do their own thing, while most of SDS joined the IWW Anticapitalist bloc or Funk the War."]]></wp_comment_content>
      <wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
      <wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
      <wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
      <wp_comment_user_id>2</wp_comment_user_id>
    </wp_comment>
    <wp_comment>
      <wp_comment_id>937</wp_comment_id>
      <wp_comment_author><![CDATA[rechelon]]></wp_comment_author>
      <wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[rechelon@riseup.net]]></wp_comment_author_email>
      <wp_comment_author_url>http://williamgillis.blogspot.com/</wp_comment_author_url>
      <wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[75.164.165.156]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
      <wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2009-05-11 20:00:50]]></wp_comment_date>
      <wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2009-05-12 04:00:50]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
      <wp_comment_content><![CDATA[Just skimming it now.  I'm impressed with the accuracy and the maps correlate incredibly well with those I compiled, which is geeky awesome.  One mild sticking point so far:

After TinCan was raided,  comms work was rerouted through Coldsnap AND INDYMEDIA.  The indymedia space was passed the passwords to some of the TinCan twitter accounts and we kept up 24hr messages on a couple of those lines throughout the following days.  While towards the end of the convention Coldsnap surpassed us in subscribers, there were several significant periods after the TinCan raid in which Indymedia had majority subscribers and was holding down the most comms chatter.]]></wp_comment_content>
      <wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
      <wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
      <wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
      <wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
    </wp_comment>
    <wp_comment>
      <wp_comment_id>938</wp_comment_id>
      <wp_comment_author><![CDATA[b. traven]]></wp_comment_author>
      <wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[b@crimethinc.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
      <wp_comment_author_url>http://www.crimethinc.com</wp_comment_author_url>
      <wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[69.134.127.47]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
      <wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2009-05-11 22:50:39]]></wp_comment_date>
      <wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2009-05-12 06:50:39]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
      <wp_comment_content><![CDATA[Thanks for the note about indymedia. Forgive the omission--once again, there is so very much to cover in any event the scale of the RNC.

We hope people will continue to post corrections and additions here, for the benefit of all who utilize this analysis! Towards that end, whenever there are references or corroborating links, feel free to include those.]]></wp_comment_content>
      <wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
      <wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
      <wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
      <wp_comment_user_id>2</wp_comment_user_id>
    </wp_comment>
    <wp_comment>
      <wp_comment_id>939</wp_comment_id>
      <wp_comment_author><![CDATA[rechelon]]></wp_comment_author>
      <wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[rechelon@riseup.net]]></wp_comment_author_email>
      <wp_comment_author_url>http://williamgillis.blogspot.com/</wp_comment_author_url>
      <wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[75.164.162.161]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
      <wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2009-05-12 10:10:51]]></wp_comment_date>
      <wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2009-05-12 18:10:51]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
      <wp_comment_content><![CDATA[another note (on the first map):

Without a doubt, funk the war was already in skirmishes at Minnesota and 7th mere minutes BEFORE the caution tape attempt at Wacuta.  It's almost certainly your estimate on the caution tape time that's off.  #4 happened just minutes (2? 5? 10?) before #13.]]></wp_comment_content>
      <wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
      <wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
      <wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
      <wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
    </wp_comment>
    <wp_comment>
      <wp_comment_id>940</wp_comment_id>
      <wp_comment_author><![CDATA[ret marut]]></wp_comment_author>
      <wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[ret@crimethinc.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
      <wp_comment_author_url>http://</wp_comment_author_url>
      <wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[71.70.217.227]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
      <wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2009-05-29 21:27:14]]></wp_comment_date>
      <wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2009-05-30 05:27:14]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
      <wp_comment_content><![CDATA[Right wing terrorist group report on the use of Twitter at the RNC:

http://www.terrorresponse.org/generator/downloads/Social_Networking_Sites_and_Coordinated_Mayhem,_An_Examination_of_the_Incorporation_of_Twitter_by_the_RNC_Welcoming_Committee.pdf]]></wp_comment_content>
      <wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
      <wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
      <wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
      <wp_comment_user_id>3</wp_comment_user_id>
    </wp_comment>
    <wp_comment>
      <wp_comment_id>941</wp_comment_id>
      <wp_comment_author><![CDATA[b. traven]]></wp_comment_author>
      <wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[b@crimethinc.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
      <wp_comment_author_url>http://www.crimethinc.com</wp_comment_author_url>
      <wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[71.70.217.227]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
      <wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2009-09-16 22:24:37]]></wp_comment_date>
      <wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2009-09-17 06:24:37]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
      <wp_comment_content><![CDATA[This is informative--a police undercover active before and during the RNC has published a tell-all memoir:

http://tc.indymedia.org/2009/sep/ex-bloomington-cop-richard-greelis-book-reveals-rnc-undercover-work-pdf

The book confirms suspicions that the "Indy-TACT" group that claimed to be adopting a sector was actually a police fabrication.]]></wp_comment_content>
      <wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
      <wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
      <wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
      <wp_comment_user_id>2</wp_comment_user_id>
    </wp_comment>
  </item>