<item>
		<title>CrimethInc. Convergence 2009 Update</title>
		<link>http://www.crimethinc.com/blog/2009/05/10/crimethinc-convergence-2009-update/</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2009 15:56:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc_creator><![CDATA[b. traven]]></dc_creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.crimethinc.com/blog/?p=688</guid>
		<description/>
		<content_encoded><![CDATA[<em>Meet at the Northside Commons (<a href="http://maps.google.com/maps?f=q&amp;source=s_q&amp;hl=en&amp;geocode=&amp;q=W.+North+Ave.+and+Brighton,+pittsburgh,+pa&amp;sll=40.458171,-80.016203&amp;sspn=0.082221,0.116901&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;ll=40.453985,-80.014533&amp;spn=0.010091,0.014613&amp;z=17&amp;iwloc=A" target="_blank">W. North Ave. and Brighton</a>) by the pond, on Monday, July 20. Write to <a href="mailto:info@crimethincconvergence.com" target="_blank">info@crimethincconvergence.com</a> with workshop proposals, offers of assistance, and accessibility concerns.</em>

A lot of water has passed under the bridge since the first CrimethInc. convergence in August 2002. We've witnessed a protracted war and occupation, an economic crisis, and most recently a change—however superficial—of rulers. We have come full circle from being isolated dissidents in a time of patriotic consensus to seeing our radical critique co-opted by politicians at the very moment our neighbors are becoming aware of the injustices of capitalism and empire.

Seven convergences later, we have reduced the limitless possibilities of the format we first tested to a precise science. We're in a different social context now, and it's time to debut a new experiment.

As the economic downturn affects the geography of urban centers, tremendous spaces are opening up that could become new sites of autonomy and struggle. This year, rather than gathering in a wilderness setting to nurture our subversive desires in seclusion, we will stage our convergence in the decaying metropolis of Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania. We hope that this event can contribute to building long-term infrastructure for our culture of resistance.

This will be nothing like the urban anarchist conferences of the past decade--no antiseptic university setting, no dispersing to isolation in individual meals and housing at the end of the scheduled programming. We will actively contest the city environment in an effort leave a permanent mark upon it, just as we hope to contest the rituals and informal hierarchies of the anarchist milieu.

All spring, rumors have circulated about the secret plans of the contingent in Pittsburgh organizing this event. What's this about squatting a castle? Is it true that they're buying a giant warehouse in the city center? Will we be building a hammock village spread across empty lots? There aren't actually catacombs in Pittsburgh, are there?

We'll have more news here shortly. In the meantime, here are fliers announcing the event {<a href="https://cloudfront.crimethinc.com/images/converg09/convergence_flyer_2_up.pdf" target="_blank"><strong>2-up Handbill</strong> [2.6MB]</a> &amp; <a href="https://cloudfront.crimethinc.com/images/converg09/convergence_flyer.pdf" target="_blank"><strong>Full-page Flyer </strong>[2.4MB]</a>}--please disseminate them everywhere you can. There also a rudimentary website at <a href="http://www.crimethincconvergence.com" target="_blank">www.crimethincconvergence.com</a>, which will be expanded soon.

Finally, here are the policies for this summer's convergence, which have been thoughtfully revised by the locals bottomlining the event. If you are frustrated about any of them, please organize your own event!

<!--more Policies after the jump.-->

<em><strong>Policies</strong></em>

<strong>Respect:</strong> We ask for your respect for the building and the local area. We aim for the convergence to be a positive, constructive force in Pittsburgh. Exercise discretion, friendliness, and respect while interacting with the local community. Please, no aimless graffiti, public urination, late night loudness, or similar activity likely to attract negative attention. Whatever you’re doing, please keep in mind that the convergence needs to fly somewhat under the radar to come off successfully. Do not put the convergence or its attendees at risk through careless or insensitive behavior, and do not give the cops reasons to interact with the convergence. There are plenty of times to sow mayhem; this convergence is a time to create a safe community space that will hopefully exist long into the future.

<strong>Consent:</strong> Any interaction you have with others here, whether sexual or otherwise, should be consensual. Silence and passivity do not count as consent. If someone says no to something or is unsure and you badger them until they say yes, that’s not consent; if someone is intoxicated they may not be in a position to give you consent. If someone says you violated their wishes, that counts as breach of consent, whatever a court of law would say. By the same token, don’t define others’ experiences for them: the person who has an experience gets to decide whether or not their wishes were respected in it, and also what, if anything, the community should do about it.

<strong>Security:</strong> Security is a consent issue just as much as sex is. Don’t say or do anything that puts others at risk unless you have their express permission; don’t speak about their involvement in illegal activity or endanger them by your own actions. Be aware that you may be under observation by your enemies at all times. Don’t alienate others by speculating about whether they are informants or ostracizing them based on suspicion; at the same time, don’t put yourself at risk by trusting people just because they’re here. Also, please don’t needlessly break the law, as that will cause trouble for all of us; there will plenty of time after this week to hone your criminal skills. Food, shelter, and everything else you might want are already provided here.

<strong>Pronouns:</strong> Part of respecting each other means respecting our varied and infinite gender identities. In the pursuit of making this convergence a safer space for people of all genders, its vitally important to respect one another’s pronouns. The world of gender is a huge and complicated terrain, but it can be more easily navigable with some simple guidelines: Don’t assume someone’s gender simply based on your perception. Ask! People will be glad you did. Make sure to refer to people by their chosen gender (or non-gendered) pronouns. If you mess up, apologize and work on that in the future. If in doubt, "they" works wonders.

<strong>Drinking and Drugs:</strong> There is a strict policy of no alcohol or drug use during the convergence. This is for several reasons, but the most important are to comply with the express wishes of our hosts and to avoid giving the authorities a pretext for harassing us. An urban convergence is particularly challenging in this regard. With the possibility that convergence attendees will scatter throughout the city at various points during the week, the 'site' of the convergence is not as clearly defined as in past years. It is for this reason that we ask that convergence attendees remain sober for as long as they intend on taking part in convergence activities. There is no judgment or morality attached to this policy; the last thing we want is an obvious division between people who drink and people who don’t. If you smoke cigarettes, please do not do so inside the building and do not congregate in front it; our concern is with the safety of the building, not personal habits. Also, please do not scatter cigarette butts on the street.

<strong>Building Safety:</strong> Please be hyper-vigilante about fire hazards: no flames, incense, candles, lanterns, flammable liquids, fire dancing tools, stoves, or anything similar may be brought inside the building. Be aware that the building’s unfinished condition can create safety hazards for attendees as well.

<strong>Photographs:</strong> Don’t photograph anyone or anything without permission—this is also an issue of consent and respect. Bear in mind that the density of an urban convergence makes this challenging.

<strong>Money:</strong> Nothing is bought or sold at the Convergence. Occasionally people have asked for donations for items as benefits for political prisoners or projects. This is fine in small doses, but generally the Convergence shouldn't be a place where a lot of money changes hands.

<strong>Non-humans:</strong> Attendees may not bring dogs or other pets to the convergence space or to convergence events. Given the space constraints and safety considerations of an urban convergence, no exceptions can be made.

<strong>Exclusion:</strong> Because this convergence should be a safe space for everyone, people who violate these policies may be asked to leave. In cases of breach of consent, both sexual and security, we will 1) trust the survivor and 2) abide by the survivor’s wishes. For example, if you gave information to the police about someone without their permission and they don’t want you in this space, we will ask you to leave; likewise, if you have sexually assaulted someone and they are comfortable with you being here as long as you participate in a mediated discussion about their boundaries during this event, we will ask you to do so, or else to leave. This is not a matter of permanently excluding "undesirables" from the anarchist movement, but simply of making things work in a limited space for a limited time. People can be asked to leave the convergence without being exiled from our communities. If anything, this simply provides an incentive for individuals and communities to work out their conflicts in advance of events like this, so we won’t all have to deal with unresolved conflicts here.]]></content_encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp_post_id>688</wp_post_id>
		<wp_post_date><![CDATA[2009-05-10 07:56:11]]></wp_post_date>
		<wp_post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2009-05-10 15:56:11]]></wp_post_date_gmt>
		<wp_comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp_comment_status>
		<wp_ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp_ping_status>
		<wp_post_name><![CDATA[crimethinc-convergence-2009-update]]></wp_post_name>
		<wp_status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp_status>
		<wp_post_parent>0</wp_post_parent>
		<wp_menu_order>0</wp_menu_order>
		<wp_post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp_post_type>
		<wp_post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp_post_password>
		<wp_is_sticky>0</wp_is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="calling-all-anarchists"><![CDATA[Calling All Anarchists]]></category>
		<wp_postmeta>
			<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp_meta_key>
			<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp_meta_value>
		</wp_postmeta>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>942</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[Mandude Guyssonson]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[eeeceedee@gmail.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url>http://</wp_comment_author_url>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[68.155.249.142]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2009-05-11 16:04:25]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2009-05-12 00:04:25]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[AHH! When do the forums open for posting!?]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>943</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[mboda]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[more.plain.words@gmail.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url/>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[173.75.5.130]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2009-05-12 14:35:52]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2009-05-12 22:35:52]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[The park you are referring to is called West Park, not Northside Commons]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>944</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[piratesparty]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[piratesparty@gmx.de]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url/>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[213.49.228.133]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2009-05-15 08:17:04]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2009-05-15 16:17:04]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[hey you guys, hope you have a nice convergence. cause i think no one of us can come around to help making it nice.

see you someday and i say we built up our own convergence with hundreds of people and next year we invite you!

greets from germany
pierre for the piratesparty]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>945</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[piratesparty]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[piratesparty@gmx.de]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url/>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[213.49.228.133]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2009-05-15 08:43:08]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2009-05-15 16:43:08]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[oh i forgot our website, check it out: piratesparty.wordpress.com]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>946</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[atomicpunk]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[breckbeeman@yahoo.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url/>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[24.144.241.53]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2009-05-15 09:23:01]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2009-05-15 17:23:01]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[see you all in june]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>947</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[willdraven]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[will.draven@gmail.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url/>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[24.163.123.172]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2009-05-18 09:32:01]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2009-05-18 17:32:01]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[Well I haven't been able to make a convergence since Bloomington and it looks like I'll be missing this one too. My SO is going to be 8 months pregnant at the time and I doubt she'll be up for the trip, and would probably kill me if our son decided to show up early and I missed his birth. But I wish you all the best of luck and hope to see you all in 2010!]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>948</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[bmayfiel]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[brettmayf4@yahoo.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url/>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[173.26.21.32]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2009-05-21 07:14:44]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2009-05-21 15:14:44]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[Hey doesn't anyone know any anarchists in Iowa City? I'm moving there in August and am trying to find some like minded people. Thanks! Wish I could make it to the convergence, probably next year.]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>949</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[@dam]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[exworker@gmail.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url>http://</wp_comment_author_url>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[75.167.101.125]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2009-05-21 16:44:21]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2009-05-22 00:44:21]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[bmayfiel, feel free to email me for contacts in iowa city:  exworker@gmail.com]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>950</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[The Kar]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[collapsingtowers@hotmail.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url/>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[8.7.69.31]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2009-05-21 20:47:45]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2009-05-22 04:47:45]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[Hello

Are there any like-minded people in the San Diego or Southern California area reading this? I will be attending the convergence. I am planning to fly there. Is there anyone else flying to the convergence?  Or are there any people who will be driving there, from southern California? Well if anyone is flying there or traveling by car, please contact me, I would like some traveling companions : )

The Kar: collapsingtowers@hotmail.com]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>951</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[timebomb]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[kushycrizzak@aim.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url/>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[75.118.63.154]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2009-05-24 07:28:39]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2009-05-24 15:28:39]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[need a ride form cleveland ohio, close enough to PA that if anyone could make a small detour on their way it would be greatly appreciated email me at kushycrizzak@aim.com]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>952</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[Nick]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[stonerraver@soundsystemsyndicate.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url>http://</wp_comment_author_url>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[68.52.140.72]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2009-05-26 21:23:44]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2009-05-27 05:23:44]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[I might try to come...how runaway freindly will this be?

Oh and by the way...how come I just saw an AD(VERTISEMENT) for crimethinc? On myspace nontheless.]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>953</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[antagonasm]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[apperception@gmail.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url/>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[75.209.49.99]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2009-05-28 11:37:57]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2009-05-28 19:37:57]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[Spread the word, far and wide:  The G20 summit is coming to Pittsburgh in September, two months after the convergence.

http://content.usatoday.com/communities/theoval/post/2009/05/67374871/1

As a resident 'burgher, my mind is blown.]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>954</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[revolution509]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[revolution509@gmail.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url/>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[67.185.177.81]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2009-06-02 23:41:53]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2009-06-03 07:41:53]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[I plan on hitch-hiking from Spokane, WA... so if any of you diry little anarcho-commies see a fellow with blue hair and a beard thumbing their way towards Pittsburgh, feel free to pick me up, yeah?]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>955</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[revolution509]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[revolution509@gmail.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url/>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[67.185.177.81]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2009-06-02 23:42:59]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2009-06-03 07:42:59]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[Damn. I feel much a fool that I didn't have the forethought to put this in my <i>first</i> comment:

My email address is revolution509@gmail.com

...you know, should you need it.]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>956</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[Ace_the_tank]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[candace_teran18@yahoo.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url/>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[75.50.72.177]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2009-06-04 15:58:14]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2009-06-04 23:58:14]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[*sigh* too bad plane tickets from CA to PA are like $250 ONE WAY!!!]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>957</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[molotovsolution]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[autonomy666@gmail.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url>http://forthebirds</wp_comment_author_url>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[69.229.29.201]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2009-06-08 03:35:40]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2009-06-08 11:35:40]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[no drinking? i'll be the guy with multiple water bottles full of vodka.]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>959</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[M. Snacks]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[itcanallbeours@gmail.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url/>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[71.70.143.55]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2009-06-09 15:12:39]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2009-06-09 23:12:39]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[Molotovsolution, I'll be the guy dumping your water bottles out out all over your sleeping bag. Don't be a scumfuck at the convergence. Come sober or organize your own OoglethInc. convergence.]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>960</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[ret marut]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[ret@crimethinc.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url>http://</wp_comment_author_url>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[71.70.217.227]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2009-06-09 19:30:28]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2009-06-10 03:30:28]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[In all seriousness, over the past few years the convergence has been interesting in that it has been a space in which many people who usually drink have chosen not to for a few days, yet still had a good time. (There haven't been any documented cases of people pouring vodka on other people's sleeping bags, either.)

Because this will be an urban event, and so may come under significant pressure from the authorities, it will be particularly important to keep the area substance-free. At the 2007 convergence in Athens, the police harassed and detained a number of people for drug searches, but eventually had to let them all go, having found nothing.

No judgment on anyone's needs or life choices, but if it's truly difficult to imagine having a fulfilling time without alcohol, it might be worth trying out taking a few days off from the stuff.]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>3</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>961</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[basshead99]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[ezzek99@gmail.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url/>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[71.98.152.219]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2009-06-15 18:59:57]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2009-06-16 02:59:57]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[im stuck in tampa bay. if anyone would be so kind as to make a quick pickup id be eternally grateful. hit me up @ ezzek99@gmail.com]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>962</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[user_name]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[jcur634@yahoo.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url/>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[71.31.11.157]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2009-06-15 20:25:02]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2009-06-16 04:25:02]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[me and my girlfriend are stuck in Russell Springs, Kentucky. if anyone could make a detour and pick us up we would really appreciate it.]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>963</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[user_name]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[jcur634@yahoo.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url/>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[71.31.11.157]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2009-06-15 20:30:52]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2009-06-16 04:30:52]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[P.S. my e-mail address is rebelyell89@gmail.com]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>964</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[Mikeisfree]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[mikebarron82290@yahoo.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url/>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[68.83.193.55]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2009-06-16 18:58:26]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2009-06-17 02:58:26]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[Anyone else from Michigan going?]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>965</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[tryto]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[alabamaslim@gmail.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url/>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[70.129.57.19]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2009-06-18 18:58:40]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2009-06-19 02:58:40]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[My buddy and I are going down from Michigan, mikeisfree. Perhaps you would like to join us.]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>966</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[dystopiate]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[dystopiate@gmail.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url/>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[67.184.69.184]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2009-06-23 16:00:35]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2009-06-24 00:00:35]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[Hi, I would like to attend. I am coming from Chicago, IL. It will probably just be me. I need two things.

I need transportation to Pittsburgh. (I thought there was a rideshare sub-forum, but apparently not? If there is, will someone please direct me to it?) If anyone else is planning on train-hopping, I would like to come with, but I have never done that before, so I will not do it alone. I will hitchhike if necessary (which I also prefer not to do alone, but whatever,) but if anyone happens to be driving from Chicago or somewhere near it or can stop in the area and has an extra seat in their vehicle, I would  really appreciate a ride!

I need someone who lives in Pittsburgh to claim to be my internet friend whose name and phone number I can tell me probation officer. I already got clearance to go "on vacation" in the end of July, but I need to give an address of where I will be and a contract number (which can be my cell phone.) They won't talk to you or anything, I'm pretty sure, but I would really prefer to use a real person who will know what they're talking about if anyone calls or something. Not that they will, but say we all get arrested or something, because they think we're terrorists, well, I will be clear and not violate my probation if I was officially staying at my "friend's" house when it happened. I really want to be off paper and not violate this probation, so ... show some love, peeps.

Thanks.
~Karma
dystopiate@gmail.com]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>967</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[dumpsterjam]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[bikesandbandanas@gmail.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url/>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[76.235.203.36]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2009-06-23 21:24:02]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2009-06-24 05:24:02]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[tryto -
do you have room for one more from michigan? im in the south west area...

dumpsterjam

bikesandbandanas@gmail.com]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>968</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[BrooklynJay]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[thinkxnegative@hotmail.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url/>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[97.115.155.160]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2009-06-24 12:37:47]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2009-06-24 20:37:47]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[Does anyone know what timeee would be best?
because my bus gets in at at 12:45 am, and its only a 1.5 mile walk from the greyhound station to West Park
but i'd like to do some exploring[and napping ;}] first.]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>969</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[M.G.]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[clamourandawhisper@gmail.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url/>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[98.179.5.154]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2009-06-25 10:12:01]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2009-06-25 18:12:01]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[Hey, is there a chance that some who are reading this know anyone living in or near Omaha, NE? I'm trying to find a few like-minded people to get in contact with. Feel free to email me at clamourandawhisper@gmail.com

Thanks. And hopefully I'll be able to make it to the 2010 convergence. Best of luck to those participating this year. :] ]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>970</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[M.G.]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[clamourandawhisper@gmail.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url/>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[98.179.5.154]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2009-06-25 10:12:48]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2009-06-25 18:12:48]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[lol, know any anarchists, I mean. Just clarifying. :P]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>971</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[ohbursar]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[ohbursar@gmail.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url/>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[76.97.144.66]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2009-06-28 07:00:24]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2009-06-28 15:00:24]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[hey i'm from atlanta and would like to go to the conference.  i saw that someone else on here posted that they were from atlanta as well, but i'm having trouble finding the old posting.  does anyone from georgia or any nearby states want to meet up and hitchhike or drive together?  ohbursar@gmail.com]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>972</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[pfm]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[pfm@crimethinc.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url>http://crimethinc.com/blog</wp_comment_author_url>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[75.164.162.64]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2009-06-28 07:12:42]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2009-06-28 15:12:42]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[hey ohbursar, check out our awesome search function. search for Atlanta, in the blog only, and here is the result: http://www.crimethinc.com/search/search.php?zoom_query=atlanta&zoom_cat%5B%5D=1&zoom_per_page=10&zoom_and=0&zoom_sort=0]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>1</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
	</item>