<item>
		<title>Rolling Thunder Seeks Accounts from Chile</title>
		<link>http://www.crimethinc.com/blog/2009/05/28/rolling-thunder-seeks-accounts-from-chile/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2009 21:49:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc_creator><![CDATA[b. traven]]></dc_creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.crimethinc.com/blog/?p=703</guid>
		<description/>
		<content_encoded><![CDATA[Following the <a href="http://news.infoshop.org/article.php?story=20090523013528979">death of an anarchist</a> alleged by corporate media to be transporting a destructive device, a <a href="http://news.infoshop.org/article.php?story=20090525024614576">wave of government repression</a> is sweeping Chile. We extend our heartfelt condolences to those who mourn the loss of a friend, and our support to all who still suffer under a repressive apparatus that has not fundamentally changed since <a href="http://www.crimethinc.com/blog/2006/08/11/remembering-the-other-september-11/">the reign of Pinochet</a>. We fear the worst is yet to come, as the Chilean government will likely use this as a pretext for further raids, arrests, and harassment.

As a humble gesture of solidarity, the next issue of our biannual journal <a href="www.crimethinc.com/rt">Rolling Thunder</a> will include a report on Chilean resistance movements over the past decade; we hope this will provide more context for and awareness of the Chilean situation for readers around the world. As we did for our coverage of <a href="http://www.crimethinc.com/blog/2007/06/19/rolling-thunder-seeking-accounts-from-g8-and-ungdomshuset-protesters/">the Ungdomshuset and G8 protests</a>, we are soliciting anonymous accounts from participants in the past decade of social struggles in Chile to fill out our coverage.

If you have experiences you are willing to share or can direct us to publicly available narratives, please contact us at <a href="mailto:rollingthunder@crimethinc.com" target="_blank">rollingthunder@crimethinc.com</a>. Those who have privacy concerns should consider starting a new email account on a public-access computer.

Please circulate this statement anywhere it may be relevant. Thank you.

<!--more En Español After the Jump-->

<em><a href="/rt">Rolling Thunder</a></em> Busca Relatos De Chile

Después de la <a href="http://news.infoshop.org/article.php?story=20090523013528979"> muerte de un anarquista</a> alegado por los medios capitalistas transportar un artefacto explosivo, una <a href="http://news.infoshop.org/article.php?story=20090525024614576">oleada de represión estatal</a> está llegando a Chile. Mandamos nuestras condolencias a lxs que han perdido un amigo, y nuestro apoyo a lxs que todavía sufren bajo un aparato represivo que no ha cambiado a fondo desde el <a href="http://www.crimethinc.com/blog/2006/08/11/remembering-the-other-september-11/">mando de Pinochet</a>. Nos preocupa el peor todavía viene, como el estado chileno probablemente utilizará el hecho como un pretexto para más allanamientos, detenciones, y hostigamiento.

Como un gesto humilde de solidaridad, la próxima edición de nuestra revista bianual <a href="www.crimethinc.com/rt">Rolling Thunder</a> incluirá un reportaje sobre los movimientos de resistencia en Chile durante la ultima década; esperamos que dé más contexto y conocimiento a la actualidad en Chile para los lectores por todo el mundo. Como hicimos para nuestro reportaje sobre <a href="http://www.crimethinc.com/blog/2007/06/19/rolling-thunder-seeking-accounts-from-g8-and-ungdomshuset-protesters/">las protestas de Ungdomshuset y G8</a> buscamos los relatos anónimos de participantes durante la ultima década de las luchas sociales en Chile para llenar nuestro reportaje.

Si tienes algunas experiencias que estás dispuestx compartir o sino puedes indicar unos relatos ya publicados y disponibles, por favor contáctanos a <a href="mailto:rollingthunder@crimethinc.com" target="_blank">rollingthunder@crimethinc.com</a>. Para la gente con preocupaciones de seguridad debe abrir una cuenta nueva de correo electrónico en un computador publico (como un cibercafé).

Por favor que difundan esta declaración donde puede ser relevante. Salud.]]></content_encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp_post_id>703</wp_post_id>
		<wp_post_date><![CDATA[2009-05-28 13:49:05]]></wp_post_date>
		<wp_post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2009-05-28 21:49:05]]></wp_post_date_gmt>
		<wp_comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp_comment_status>
		<wp_ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp_ping_status>
		<wp_post_name><![CDATA[rolling-thunder-seeks-accounts-from-chile]]></wp_post_name>
		<wp_status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp_status>
		<wp_post_parent>0</wp_post_parent>
		<wp_menu_order>0</wp_menu_order>
		<wp_post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp_post_type>
		<wp_post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp_post_password>
		<wp_is_sticky>0</wp_is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="calling-all-anarchists"><![CDATA[Calling All Anarchists]]></category>
		<wp_postmeta>
			<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp_meta_key>
			<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp_meta_value>
		</wp_postmeta>
		<wp_postmeta>
			<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[_thumbnail_id]]></wp_meta_key>
			<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[3169]]></wp_meta_value>
		</wp_postmeta>
		<wp_postmeta>
			<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[jumbo]]></wp_meta_key>
			<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[https://cloudfront.crimethinc.com/images/chile/chile_b.jpg]]></wp_meta_value>
		</wp_postmeta>
	</item>