<item>
		<title>State Repression at the G20 Protests</title>
		<link>http://www.crimethinc.com/blog/2009/09/30/state-repression-at-the-g20-protests/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2009 17:20:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc_creator><![CDATA[b. traven]]></dc_creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.crimethinc.com/blog/?p=941</guid>
		<description/>
		<content_encoded><![CDATA[The dust has settled: a total of <a href="http://www.pittsburghlive.com/x/pittsburghtrib/news/specialreports/g20/s_645198.html" target="_blank"> 193 arrests</a> took place during the G20—a great number of those being random bystanders. 17 people face felonies; one young person is being <a href="http://www.post-gazette.com/pg/09268/1000965-100.stm" target="_blank">absurdly scapegoated</a> for $20,000+ of damage, while two alleged participants in the comms group are being charged with “hindering apprehension or prosecution, criminal use of a communication facility, and possessing an instrument of crime,” presumably in hopes of setting a precedent to suppress the use of communications technology to keep demonstrators safe in the future.

Indeed, several people have been charged with “hindering apprehension,” which is a new one to us here. It sounds more like an existential condition than a crime—picture Woody Allen in some sex farce, awkwardly explaining to his mother that he’s been suffering from hindering apprehension!

This report focuses on <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xjB5SB9JrKk" target="_blank">the events of Friday evening</a>, when police and National Guardsmen gratuitously attacked students at the University of Pittsburgh.

<!--more Read on after the jump.-->

<em>We’ve retreated to a back street; a cacophony of sirens, gunshots, and explosions echoes off the walls ahead of us. With our experience, this isn’t exactly frightening—it all seems to be happening in slow motion; but the irrationality of the authorities’ behavior is unsettling. A tremendous cloud of white smoke is filling the air above the roof of the dormitory, and a familiar acrid scent is beginning to mingle with the sweet stench of tear gas: is something on fire? Two more tear gas canisters soar high into the night sky, trails of poison billowing behind them, and land on the same roof. It’s like the Fourth of July, only with crying, bleeding college students fleeing beneath the fireworks.</em>

<a href="https://cloudfront.crimethinc.com/images/g20photos/g20_special_b.jpg" rel="lightbox[g20_2]"  class="legacyimage"><img src="https://cloudfront.crimethinc.com/images/g20photos/g20_special_a.jpg" /></a><span class="invisible">-</span>
<a href="http://news.xinhuanet.com/english/2009-09/25/content_12108256.htm" target="_blank">According to reports,</a> the authorities assembled a force of nearly 5000 for the G20, including 2500 National Guard troops, 1200 state troopers, 875 Pittsburgh city police, and small groups from other agencies. It’s a potentially significant precedent that the National Guard comprised more than half of the total force; it may point to greater military involvement in domestic policing in the future. It’s also important to note that the original plan had been to utilize more police and fewer National Guard, but it appears that only the National Guard was available—one more sign of overextension among our foes.

According to <a href="http://cindysheehanssoapbox.blogspot.com/2009/09/tell-me-what-police-state-looks-like-by.html" target="_blank">Cindy Sheehan</a> and others, the National Guard troops in Pittsburgh had recently returned from <a href="http://pittsburghlive.com:8000/x/pittsburghtrib/news/specialreports/g20/s_643938.html" target="_blank">duty in Iraq</a>. This may explain their behavior the night of Friday, September 25, when they pointlessly brutalized a gathering of students at the University of Pittsburgh in downtown Oakland.

Earlier that day, <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2009/09/27/world/27protest.html?_r=1&amp;hpw" target="_blank">a flier had circulated</a> reading “Go Pitt; Fuck the Police; 10 p.m., Schenley Plaza,” the location of the previous night’s <a href="http://www.breitbart.tv/five-most-watched-videos-police-clash-with-students-at-university-of-pittsburgh/" target="_blank">standoff between police and students</a>. By ten o’clock, hundreds of people had gathered in and around the plaza. A small minority were avowed anarchists; perhaps a greater proportion had participated somehow in the previous day’s events, but the vast majority appeared simply to be curious students.

The university had sternly instructed students to stay away from Schenley Plaza that night, but this backfired, making the Plaza irresistible. Police and National Guard were already present in the area in tremendous force, parading in full riot gear. Helicopters combing the ground with searchlights intensified the atmosphere of military occupation.

No protest ensued: no march, no banners, no chants, no confrontations or property destruction. All the same, the police soon forcibly cleared the square. Not content with this, they then began to shoot tear gas canisters at spectators on the sidewalk across the street. Eventually, they advanced further, shooting tear gas and projectiles at hapless, fleeing onlookers and beating and arresting anyone they could catch. This continued for hours; in the end, 110 people were arrested, mostly passers-by and medics who stayed behind to treat the injured. The National Guard pacified Oakland the same way they pacified neighborhoods in Iraq.

Despite years of police brutality and “Bring the War Home” rhetoric, witnessing this was downright dumbfounding. Anarchists always decry police repression, arguing that every use of coercive authority is illegitimate. But it is difficult to imagine how even a statist conservative could justify this particular exercise of repressive force; there was no resistance to repress. The events of Friday night show that the authorities can produce a “riot” simply by ordering people not to do something that they don’t even realize they <em>are</em> doing; this is the heavy-handed stupidity that helped generate the Iraqi resistance.

<a href="https://cloudfront.crimethinc.com/images/g20photos/g20_pitt_b.jpg" rel="lightbox[g20_2]" class="legacyimage"><img src="https://cloudfront.crimethinc.com/images/g20photos/g20_pitt_a.jpg" /></a><span class="invisible">-</span>
No outrage was capable of igniting resistance among the students, however. The flier had cast them as the protagonists in a struggle against the police; some radicals came hoping to support them in this conflict, their hopes buoyed by the clashes that had taken place on the same terrain the previous evening. But the students refused to see themselves as protagonists; despite 36 hours of other young people in hooded sweatshirts confronting the police, they still saw themselves as inert and helpless. This underscores the foolishness of pinning one’s hopes on another demographic as the revolutionary subject. Instead of waiting for others to take the initiative, those who wish to struggle against this society must cast themselves as protagonists in that struggle and find common cause with all who join in.

Some anarchists took the dim view that the students were carrying their apathy to a sadomasochistic extreme, paradoxically asserting their right to be spectators of their own repression: “Why are you tear-gassing us? We have the right to be here watching you tear-gas us!” Conversely, one might argue that, by being present in defiance of the decrees and threats of the university, the students were already challenging their social roles—perhaps more so than the anarchists who were just there to do what anarchists always do. In that light, simply in coming out, the students were protesters: not politicized protesters like those who elaborated their critiques of the policies of the G20 into indymedia cameras, but protesters all the same against the authority of the school administration and the tedium of college life.

For their part, though they set out to break up a presumed protest, the police had no method by which to identify protesters. They began by threatening everyone; those who did not immediately flee they assumed to be protesters. They tear-gassed everyone; those who covered their faces were obviously protesters. As they claimed territory block by block, they shot projectiles at anyone in view; those they struck were marked as protesters by their own blood. They charged anyone who remained on the street; those who ran away were protesters, and were chased, tackled, and beaten accordingly.

At one point, word went out that the police were about to raid the dormitory towers in search of protesters. Had this occurred, it would have been a bloodbath. All this illustrates how those serving authoritarian power can only see—and thus produce—enemies everywhere they look. Coercive force can never resolve conflict, only intensify it.

Following Thursday’s clashes, it turned out that a mere flier sufficed to provoke a full-scale police state. Once again, the apparatus of repression causes a great deal more disruption than the protests to which it responds: the tiny sting of the anarchist mosquito provokes an intense allergic reaction that can be disproportionately costly for the state. In some ways, the events of Friday night were strategically fortuitous for anarchists: the police discredited themselves, and this is bound to help the cases of those who were arrested on Thursday.

At the same time, it’s possible to be overly optimistic about this. Manifestations of the violence inherent in state power don’t necessarily persuade people of the possibility or value of the anarchist alternative. The police didn’t win any new friends Friday night, but nothing empowering occurred either. It will take months of serious follow-up work from Pittsburgh locals if the events of September 25 are to attract new people to anti-authoritarian struggle.

In this regard, the invisibility—dare we say the mythological character—of actual anarchists Friday night was a loss of ground. Anarchists were at once everywhere and nowhere. Everywhere—or else why were the police attacking everyone?—yet nowhere, in that there was no explicitly anarchist presence. This indeterminacy implies a tremendous potential—<em>Are those people over there anarchists? Might I be one, myself?</em>—but usually ends up serving the interests of the state. As the underdogs, anarchists generally have to stay in the shadows for security reasons; we can hardly speak honestly about our intentions in our own spokescouncils, let alone to the public at large. We remain utopian ghosts, shadows pursuing something otherworldly, while the police prove again and again that <em>they</em> are the only reality, writing this on the skin of civilians in a Morse code of rubber bullets when need be.

This is why moments of visibility and togetherness like those we experienced Thursday afternoon are so important. When enough of us join in action, we are no longer isolated lunatics pursuing will-o'-the-wisps; brought into reality, our dissident desires are legitimized in a such a way that we can finally believe in them, so that others will be able to as well. Suddenly, fighting capitalism is more realistic than knuckling under to it. Nothing makes more sense than pulling masks over our faces, linking arms, and charging our oppressors. Dumpsters cease to be organs of denial about the wastefulness of our civilization and become mobile barricades; corporate windows cease to display merchandise and sing instead the uproar of social transformation. The world itself becomes something different.

Now that the G20 protests are over, let us not retreat into obscurity, but lay the groundwork for other battles in which we can give our dreams flesh together.

<em>[First Photo by <a href="http://www.iwasaround.com">Foo</a>]</em>]]></content_encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp_post_id>941</wp_post_id>
		<wp_post_date><![CDATA[2009-09-30 09:20:23]]></wp_post_date>
		<wp_post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2009-09-30 17:20:23]]></wp_post_date_gmt>
		<wp_comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp_comment_status>
		<wp_ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp_ping_status>
		<wp_post_name><![CDATA[state-repression-at-the-g20-protests]]></wp_post_name>
		<wp_status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp_status>
		<wp_post_parent>0</wp_post_parent>
		<wp_menu_order>0</wp_menu_order>
		<wp_post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp_post_type>
		<wp_post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp_post_password>
		<wp_is_sticky>0</wp_is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="from-the-trenches"><![CDATA[From the Trenches]]></category>
		<wp_postmeta>
			<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp_meta_key>
			<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp_meta_value>
		</wp_postmeta>
		<wp_postmeta>
			<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[_thumbnail_id]]></wp_meta_key>
			<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[3141]]></wp_meta_value>
		</wp_postmeta>
		<wp_postmeta>
			<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[jumbo]]></wp_meta_key>
			<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[https://cloudfront.crimethinc.com/images/g20photos/g20_dumpster_b.jpg]]></wp_meta_value>
		</wp_postmeta>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>1130</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[polarbear]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[polarbear@riseup.net]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url/>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[128.146.146.167]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2009-09-30 10:09:51]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2009-09-30 18:09:51]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[i would caution crimethinc when using ideas like "revolutionary subject" "protagonists" and "inert".

one of the major projects undertaken in italy during the 70s was a radical rethinking of radical subjectivity.  they reworked certain subject-positions that were rather passe or bourgeois (student, leisure class, non-worker) and theorized how they could be re-articulated in radical way in order to facilitate a critical understanding among those identified as part of those groups.

there is now a burgeoning body of literature, concepts, and movements that is an outgrowth of this rethinking.  it calls itself "precarity" - the idea that marginalized subjectivities aren't victims who needs protection and rights (ie: recognition), but actually categories that can be emptied out in refusal of the position that was forced onto them.

what makes this move so radical is that it's not liberal "reclaiming" of categories or proselytizing about one-size-fits-all subject-positions (anarchist, for example).  RATHER, it's finding ways to rearticulate the things people are ALREADY doing in ways to transform the positions (and figure out new ways of solidarity, political behavior, types of association, etc etc).

a quick read of pitt makes this point clear.  the students may have created the most antagonistic and radical outcome:

*the possibilities that emerge from what the anarchists did is minimal -- smashy smashy is nothing new and compared the massive influx of money coming into the city, it's utilitarian/functional effect was pretty minimal.  this is not a slight for the institution building or the cultural imagination that was expanded as a direct result of a large "presence" in the city - but the usual functional metrics used by anarchists (PD [property destruction], blockades, arrests, working-class solidarity, etc) neither met the necessary conditions for a radical rupture nor really challenged politics as usual.  of course there was anarchist infrastructure built - but who in the world really cares about anarchist administration, bureaucracy, and logistics (another anarchist franchise project is possible)??

*guess what people have been talking about when discussing g20pitt?  the police riots against the pitt students (not old anarchist summit reruns).  the students show the ever-growing possibility of groups not otherwise defined as political niche groups (anarchists, socialists, dems) who otherwise found themselves caught within the pincers of state control.  modern policing has wet dreams about keeping repression specifically focused on those groups, knowing that the ideological web surrounding niche group activity is strong enough to capture and control any justification produced for protesting outside the channels set out by the political system.

their asses were in the right place, everything else can follow.  the failure of marxist movements of the last 150 years demonstrates the failure of german idealism, which thought that the ideas of ideology were what transformed material conditions.  politics of purity is the game the vanguardists play.   anarchists should know better -- regardless of the students see themselves, they were there provoking cops in a meaningful way.  our role is not to define the right categories other should put themselves in, but to figure out the roles they already inhabit and create ways to re-articulate the actions in ways that build solidarities and affinities.

but then again, if we just want to play "more revolutionary than thou" or "more punker than thou" we can keep on getting yelling at students rather than figuring out ways to incorporate them into our strategy.]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>1131</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[b. traven]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[b@crimethinc.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url>http://www.crimethinc.com</wp_comment_author_url>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[71.70.217.227]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2009-09-30 11:14:59]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2009-09-30 19:14:59]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[Hey--thanks for this lengthy comment.

First, any CrimethInc. text that uses terms like “revolutionary subject” or "proletariat" does so with tongue firmly planted in cheek.

Second, nobody here is arguing that anarchists should "keep on yelling at students." Your suggestion that we should "figure out how to incorporate them into our strategy" sounds a little manipulative, though.

Myself, I'd argue that the important thing is to find common cause with others in resistance to capitalism and hierarchy. This involves violating the boundaries and categories of our society, yes, but it doesn't stop there. There are plenty of ways people can challenge or transform their roles in society that don't contribute at all to collective liberation: hence the value in articulating values.

It's possible that simply by being present, the students were "provoking the cops in a meaningful way," as you say. However, if they didn't see themselves as doing so, but just happened to be positioned in such a way that this happened, that doesn't offer a lot of promise that such a thing might happen again, or that it will necessarily produce liberating results.

If you read the above text closely, it isn't a criticism of the students. It's an argument that anarchists should have tried harder to connect with them on the basis of collective actions to resist the police, rather than on the basis of an individualized suffering at their hands.

As for the meaningless of anarchist summit mobilizations--the whole event would not have occurred had there not been a mobilization. We can agree that anarchists need to see ourselves as playing a minor role in a much bigger world, though.]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>2</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>1132</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[polarbear]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[polarbear@riseup.net]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url/>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[128.146.146.167]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2009-09-30 11:39:30]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2009-09-30 19:39:30]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[tav,

you are right that i am not generous enough in my characterization of the irony in the words used in the article.  please excuse my careless but note that it can also be read as highlighting the play left within the initial text which oscillates between a) a refusal of any category of radical subjectivity and b) a desire to still have a radical subjectivity despite an acknowledgement of its impossibility.  i think references leap out throughout the text that indicate an unconscious desire of a radical class of individuals who will emerge to fight capital.

maybe what i intended to highlight the most is that the students desire (an unconscious, nearly impossible to articulate drive) was in the right place.  when told by their school administration to not demonstrate, it provoked them to do so (known in everyday language as 'reverse psychology').  the struggle for representing and articulating the events within the terms of the theater of traditional political protest (protestors, police, etc) will always fall short, there will never be formal categories to describe the level of self-organization and spontaneity necessary to combat the state.

the article poses opposing questions: 1) are the students taking part in their own repression or 2) are they challenging the state in their refusal to be part of sedimented forms of political protest (maybe in its generosity to others' opinions, or maybe as a simple strawman [sic]).  The article never goes on to conclude with the latter, though giving more ink.  I was expressing my agreement for the latter statement, and giving it more context.

to emphasize the argument even more: anarchist mobilizations are useful but limit themselves by trying to brand them as specifically anarchist.  it's the unintended connections that are drawn in which ultimately make the mobilizations a success or not.  whether it's the outrage TV/internet news viewer beamed in over fiber optics [imc?], the unassuming spectator-turned-participant [pitt?], or the third world countries looking for a way out of the new trade bloc [wto] - anarchist strategy has never been about trench warfare with the cops.  we could trot out example after example and what makes them successful is their ability to put into motion and intensify a whole assemblage of outside forces, of which the state and captains of industry are always trying to predict, contain, capture, and re-direct.

so yeah - no doubt the mobilization was necessary to get pitt involved.  and we both agree, but i want to push it one step further -- it's all about thinking about the indirect, external connections that are held in 'common'.

ps: the sustainability of the pitt students resistance or their  "understanding what they were doing" probably doesn't matter as much as we might wish.  but that is what precarity is trying to get at (or spinoza/TCI's resonance).]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
	</item>