<item>
		<title>Millions of Dollars in Prizes</title>
		<link>http://www.crimethinc.com/blog/2009/12/22/millions-of-dollars-in-prizes/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2009 20:07:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc_creator><![CDATA[b. traven]]></dc_creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.crimethinc.com/blog/?p=1040</guid>
		<description/>
		<content_encoded><![CDATA[On the heels of <a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/wp-dyn/content/article/2009/12/15/AR2009121504345.html" target="_blank">three new settlements</a> in which the government of Washington, D.C. is paying protesters well over $22 million, we’ve completed a new <a href="/texts/atoz/prizes.php">feature</a> and <a href="/tools/downloads/posters.html#prizes">two-sided poster</a> on the subject of payouts to survivors of police repression. Both black and white and color versions of the poster are available.

Over the past decade of mobilizations, CrimethInc. agents have repeatedly pulled off <a href="/texts/pastfeatures/miamiheat.php">narrow escapes</a> from mass-arrest situations in which all our comrades were captured. We felt pretty pleased with ourselves until we learned, some years too late, that everyone who didn’t get away was making thousands of dollars! How embarrassing—we’re such dropouts, we can’t even get a job getting arrested! This, despite <a href="http://www.msnbc.msn.com/id/7908466/" target="_blank">the FBI defaming our milieu</a> as the “top domestic terror threat.” What’s a ne'er-do-well supposed to do? So we read with sympathy <a href="http://news.infoshop.org/article.php?story=2009a16" target="_blank">the account from our comrades</a> who followed in the footsteps of the <a href="http://www.forward.com/articles/116259/" target="_blank">Warsaw Ghetto fighters</a>, crawling through the sewers to escape arrest and, little did they know, a whopping $18,000.

Pass the word around—resistance doesn’t always end in defeat, even when we get beaten and arrested. We may not believe in the legitimacy of the law any more than our rulers do, but we still ought to include the battle in the courts in our strategizing alongside the battle in the streets. By bringing lawsuits against our oppressors, we can increase the costs of repressing us, and sometimes tie their hands for future demonstrations—compare the behavior of the Washington, D.C. police at the <a href="http://www.starhawk.org/activism/activism-writings/A-16_Starhawk.html" target="_blank">2000</a> and <a href="http://www.anarchistresistance.org/abolishthebank/strike_storyindex.shtml" target="_blank">2002</a> IMF protests to their conduct during the <a href="/blog/2007/10/25/notes-on-the-october-rebellion/">2007 IMF protests</a>. Unfortunately, some sectors of the current anarchist milieu have such short memories that by the time the lawsuits are concluded, many have stopped paying attention, and the initial thoughtless appraisal of protests as “a failure” is all that sticks in people’s heads. We’re only now learning the net results of mobilizations that occurred a decade ago. To mount an effective resistance to capitalism, we need to think in terms of decades, not months.

<strong><a href="/texts/atoz/prizes.php">Read full text here.</a></strong>]]></content_encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp_post_id>1040</wp_post_id>
		<wp_post_date><![CDATA[2009-12-22 12:07:59]]></wp_post_date>
		<wp_post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2009-12-22 20:07:59]]></wp_post_date_gmt>
		<wp_comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp_comment_status>
		<wp_ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp_ping_status>
		<wp_post_name><![CDATA[millions-of-dollars-in-prizes]]></wp_post_name>
		<wp_status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp_status>
		<wp_post_parent>0</wp_post_parent>
		<wp_menu_order>0</wp_menu_order>
		<wp_post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp_post_type>
		<wp_post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp_post_password>
		<wp_is_sticky>0</wp_is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="read-all-about-it"><![CDATA[Read All About It]]></category>
		<wp_postmeta>
			<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp_meta_key>
			<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp_meta_value>
		</wp_postmeta>
		<wp_postmeta>
			<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[_thumbnail_id]]></wp_meta_key>
			<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[3124]]></wp_meta_value>
		</wp_postmeta>
		<wp_postmeta>
			<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[jumbo]]></wp_meta_key>
			<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[http://thecloud.crimethinc.com/images/prizes/prizes_b.jpg]]></wp_meta_value>
		</wp_postmeta>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>1193</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[puneta]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[hacktiffler@riseup.net]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url/>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[173.53.88.219]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2009-12-22 22:08:54]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2009-12-23 06:08:54]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[This isn't exactly a condemnation of the poster, because it does have its great points and uses, but I wanted to bring a gentle reminder that there's also a great ton of other cases outside of summit/protest/activism cases that involve just as much resistance to capitalism.  But these cases and lawsuits end up completely ignored or forgotten by the court system or the general populace because so and so didnt have the right amount of privilege or comfort necessary to be paid attention to (prisoners, people of color, trans folk, etc.) among other reasons, most of the time around the fact that so and so didn't have the community of support necessary to hang on.

Which makes systems of legal support all the more important, really.  So how do we use the infrastructures and examples of these small victories to apply them to our local everyday cases?  Or is it an entirely different dynamic?]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>1194</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[b. traven]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[b@crimethinc.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url>http://www.crimethinc.com</wp_comment_author_url>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[66.56.28.135]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2009-12-22 22:22:54]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2009-12-23 06:22:54]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[That is an important point. Really, legal support structures are barely on the anarchist radar when it comes to mass mobilizations, and even less so outside that very narrow context. [Some of us do have a project in the works to remedy that, but it's bad luck to speak about such things until they're ready to present to the public.]

In this case, we had to focus on this particular aspect of legal support just to make the point--but it's not an attempt to obscure all the other (generally more important!) purposes that ongoing legal support can serve in the struggle against hierarchy and oppression. As usual, with so many fronts to fight on, it's always hard to figure out where to start; we're generally able to do our best work with the stuff that's closest to home, but that doesn't mean it's the most important.

A huge thank you to our comrades who spend their lives doing legal work to support prisoners and members of targeted communities. Talk about grueling, thankless work.]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>2</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>1195</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[harc]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[harcesz@obin.org]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url>https://harce.wordpress.com/</wp_comment_author_url>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[217.17.37.74]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2009-12-25 11:00:28]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2009-12-25 19:00:28]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[I know it's a side issue, but it leads to general misconceptions so just to set one thing straight - canals (sewage) were used in the final stages of both Warsaw Ghetto Uprising and the Warsaw Uprising - in case of the ghetto one it was a way for the remaining fighters to escape (under a hundred, very few Jews decided to fight), in the Warsaw uprising, they were used through a big part of it, but most famously to escape the surrounded old town and inner city, as depicted by Wajda in his Kanal (1957). 
it might also worth noticing that some of the last fighters to make it into the canals were a syndicalist squad, some of them wearing red'n'black armbands (instead of the red and white national colours worn by all other fighters), this squad included the few of polish anarchists still alive and active in Warsaw.
and just on a final note - most of them got slaughtered either by the nazis or the invading bolshevick 'red army', which first stopped allowing the german troops to change Warsaw into a bloodbath, and when under their occupation, prosecuting polish freedom fighters (including anarchists). 

and on a lighter note - getting $$$ for each instance of arrest could make the movement quite wealthy...]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>1196</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[ret marut]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[ret@crimethinc.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url>http://</wp_comment_author_url>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[69.134.207.171]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2010-01-11 15:56:35]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2010-01-11 23:56:35]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[Gus Ganley Wins $70,000 Settlement Resulting From August 2007 Critical Mass:

http://twincities.indymedia.org/2010/jan/gus-ganley-wins-settlement-city-resulting-aug-2007-critical-mass]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>3</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>1197</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[ntinator]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[davidjohnkowalski@gmail.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url>http://ntinator@blogspot.con</wp_comment_author_url>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[65.185.156.99]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2010-01-21 21:41:19]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2010-01-22 05:41:19]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[Another reason aggressive civil litigation is such an important weapon is the public nature of court proceedings.  The intentional and malicious misrepresentation of the facts is far more difficult when a trial transcript is available for public inspection.

It is also an important means of spreading the knowledge of the struggle.  What my be white washed or not talked about at all must be acknowledged when it as attached to a public proceeding,

If Socrates is to be put to death for the corruption of the youth of Athens, and he is to thwart his jailers by taking his own life, let us at least insure that this travesty is on the front page of at least one newspaper and the cause of a painful, expensive, and very public wrongful death suit.]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>1199</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[@dam]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[exworker@gmail.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url>http://</wp_comment_author_url>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[75.167.121.5]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2010-04-08 15:02:26]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2010-04-08 23:02:26]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[Seattle anarchists win $30,000 and lawsuit against police:

http://news.infoshop.org/article.php?story=2010flag3]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
	</item>