<item>
		<title>Seattle, Seven Years Later</title>
		<link>http://www.crimethinc.com/blog/2006/11/30/seattle-seven-years-later/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2006 02:18:50 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc_creator><![CDATA[peter p]]></dc_creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crimethinc.com/blog/2006/11/30/seattle-seven-years-later/</guid>
		<description/>
		<content_encoded><![CDATA[<a class="smallitem" title="n30.gif" href="http://crimethinc.com/downloads/n30.html"><img id="image62" src="http://www.crimethinc.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2006/11/n30.gif" alt="n30.gif" /></a>Our CrimethInc. cell is delighted to commemorate the seven-year anniversary of the historic Seattle WTO protests with the release of a new publication, <em>N30: A Memoir and Analysis, with an Eye to the Future</em>. This 64-page treatise draws on the perspectives of anarchist rioters and corporate think tanks alike, supplementing them with maps, forgotten archival material, and contemporary critique to present a coherent, comprehensive picture of what took place in Seattle and how that affected the course of history. <a href="/tools/downloads/zines.html#n30">Download the e-book and/or replication-ready versions </a><a href="http://crimethinc.com/downloads/n30.html">here</a><a href="http://crimethinc.com/downloads/n30.html">.</a>

Here follows a selection from the afterword, which briefly addresses the successes and failures of the “Seattle model” of struggle and the extent to which it remains relevant today.

<!--more-->

<strong>WTO Protests Retrospective</strong>

From this vantage point, it is possible to interpret the WTO protests according to any number of frameworks. They were a watershed in the development of the contemporary anticapitalist movement, at which thousands of disparate groups discovered each other and the power they could wield together. They were the point at which, a decade after the fall of the Berlin Wall and the end of the old “democracy versus communism” opposition, the fundamental dichotomy of global politics was recast as corporate capitalism versus the common people. They were, as the researchers of the RAND corporation self-servingly discovered, the substantiation of theories about how new communications technologies would shape social conflict. They were simultaneously the beginning and the high point of a “movement of movements” which ended when terrorists hijacked the global stage on September 11th, or when communist splinter groups hijacked the anti-war movement a year and a half later, or which continues so long as certain anthropology professors require a subject for inquiry.

The only thing that matters for us anarchists, of course, is what we can learn from the past to act effectively in the present. Does it make sense to pursue “another Seattle,” or is that just a will-o’-the-wisp? Could any of the tactics that succeeded in Seattle be as effective today, or are they subject to a law of diminishing returns?

<strong>What Happened in Seattle</strong>

Immediately following the Seattle WTO protests, some reformists moaned that the confrontational tactics and far-reaching goals of militant participants alienated people and ruined any chance of concretely affecting national policy. Yet by reformist standards, the so-called anti-globalization movement [1] associated with the Seattle protests achieved practically unprecedented triumphs, and the credit for this must go at least in part to the militants. The next WTO meeting had to be held in Qatar, cementing the image of the WTO as an anti-democratic, oppressive elite. Many of the proposals that had most outraged activists were immediately dropped; likewise, the Free Trade Area of the Americas (FTAA) agreement is now essentially dead in the water. Some analysts have concluded that the mobilization against corporate globalization peaked early because its goals were not ambitious enough.

In addition to giving the WTO a public image makeover and successfully forcing concessions from it, the militancy of the demonstrators in Seattle pushed its supposed critics to adopt a more uncompromising stance. Organized labor and segments of the Democratic Party have to present the illusion of being oppositional in order to justify their existence. As was frankly acknowledged in the RAND report, they hoped to maintain this illusion and simultaneously absorb and neutralize any radical tendencies by putting in an appearance at the Seattle WTO protests. Once they found themselves caught up in a huge, obviously popular demonstration against the WTO, they had to feign at least some sympathy or else reveal their “opposition” to be a mere pretense. Thus we can see that direct action is the most effective means both for putting pressure on adversaries and for exerting leverage on supposed allies. Even if you don’t want to overthrow the government, forget about voting and petitioning—the only hope for change is in the streets.

Finally, the successes in Seattle brought US anarchists worldwide visibility, along with a needed morale boost, and provided a format for future actions. The “summit-hopping” model made a virtue of the transience that has been such a stumbling block for anticapitalist organizing in North America; like it or not, a movement must make the best of its weaknesses, and if many anarchists couldn’t be counted on to stay in one place long enough to do effective local organizing at least that mobility enabled them to come together occasionally at capitalist summits.

The breakthroughs in Seattle that affected the anarchist community turned out in the long run to be dangerous gifts: as soon as the media attention, the thrill of victory, and the effectiveness of the new model were taken away, many anarchists felt they were back at square one.

<strong>A Complex Legacy</strong>

In reflecting on the mobilization in Seattle, people often overlook the years of failure that had preceded it. What happened in Seattle was possible precisely because it had been years, if not decades, since so many people joined in disruptive action against a capitalist institution in the US. As noted in the RAND analysis, police expected symbolic arrests à la the anti-nuclear demonstrations of the 1980s, not the coordinated obstruction and rioting they got. Subsequent mass actions were much more difficult to pull off, as the authorities mobilized every resource to ensure that what happened in Seattle would not happen again.

Despite this, Seattle was followed by a series of demonstrations unlike anything in the preceding decade: Washington, D.C. was shut down the following April by protests against the International Monetary Fund, and a year later the FTAA ministerial in Quebec City occasioned the most intense street fighting since the Los Angeles riots of 1992. All the teargas in the country was no match for the enthusiasm of the anticapitalist movement once people had a model to work from and a structure to plug into. It was not until after September 11, 2001 that the tide finally began to recede, and this occurred primarily as a result of the widespread self-fulfilling prophecy that the high point of anticapitalist mass actions was over. The momentum that followed Seattle was not destroyed by the government response, it was abandoned by those who had maintained it: the most significant question presented by the post-Seattle phase of struggle is not how to handle repression, but how to sustain morale.

After anticapitalists lost the initiative, it was inevitable that the partisans of willful impotence would regain it. Proportionate to the number of participants, the antiwar movement of 2002 to 2003 was incredibly ineffectual, largely due to the machinations of liberals and communists who did their best to prevent anyone from taking effective action. And once the legend of Seattle ceased to be the origin myth of an existing, vibrant movement, it became a burden upon everyone who tried to apply the mass action model. Even though many anarchist demonstrations between 2002 and 2005 put everything that happened in the mid-1990s to shame, they seemed stunted and disappointing compared with the Battle of Seattle. Past accomplishments always cast a shadow over the present, and shadows loom bigger the further the object casting them recedes.

The FTAA ministerial in Miami four years after the Seattle WTO protests showed how much ground anticapitalists had lost and how much their adversaries—both those in uniform and those carrying protest signs—had learned. While there were probably almost as many committed anarchists in Miami as there were in Seattle, far fewer other protesters showed up—partly because Miami is so far from the rest of the US, partly because it has the most reactionary Latino population of any US city, and partly because the ability of anticapitalist networks to bring out protesters had been sapped by demoralization and competition with antiwar organizing. The AFL-CIO duplicitously coordinated with the police while asking demonstrators not to carry out direct action during their march, and the demonstrators—insanely—agreed to this request. This enabled the police to concentrate on beating and pepper-spraying people before the union march, controlling the streets during it, and then viciously brutalizing and arresting everyone who remained in town after it. The police tactics in Miami, which were significantly more aggressive than those of the police in Seattle, showed that the fluke in Seattle was not that the police were so aggressive but that the corporate media were caught off guard and accidentally reported on their violence [2]. Finally, the strategy of the demonstrators in Miami, which consisted of a largely symbolic assault on the fence surrounding the meetings, had no hope of actually interfering with them. The protests in Miami only succeeded in disrupting business as usual and giving the FTAA a bad name because the authorities, still transfixed by the specter of Seattle, went to such lengths to repress them.

As of this writing, the Miami FTAA ministerial is itself three years behind us, and there have been no major mass actions in the US since Bush’s second inauguration almost two years ago. Paradoxically, the good news is that enough time may now have elapsed since the WTO protests that a mass mobilization with a clever strategy could catch the powers that be by surprise again—but the bad news is that anarchists, demoralized from so many years of trying to “repeat Seattle,” may not yet be ready to stake everything on another attempt.

<strong>What Next?</strong>

The presidential campaign of 2008 will be the next backdrop against which major mass actions can be expected to take place. Whatever misgivings some of us currently have about them, for anarchists not to have a powerful presence in mass actions in 2008 would be tantamount to our disappearance from the national arena of social struggle.

The essential challenge of the mass action model is that its greatest strengths and weaknesses are identical. Working from the physics equation tension=force/area, this model brings together a great number of people in a small space so their coordinated actions can have exponential effects—but with sufficient warning, the state can also concentrate its forces to neutralize their efforts. Consequently, successful mass actions must either come as a surprise themselves or employ an unexpected strategy. At the G8 protests in Scotland in 2005, for example, participants outwitted the authorities by dispersing into the countryside to block roads outside the areas where police forces were concentrated.

Effective mass action necessitates that people from a broad range of perspectives work together without limiting each other. In that regard, mass actions are good practice for building the symbiotic relationships fundamental to an anarchist society. The mobilizations that succeeded in Seattle, Quebec City, and elsewhere succeeded because a great number of people simultaneously engaged in a diverse array of complementary tactics. Regardless of the success of a particular action, the ability to do this itself constitutes a victory over the segregation, isolation, and conflict promoted by the capitalist system. In that regard, the Seattle WTO protests were not an unrepeatable miracle, but rather an example of how powerful we can be whenever we find ways to work together.

<strong>Suggested Reading</strong>

We Are Everywhere: The Irresistible Rise of Global Anticapitalism—Through testimony, photos, tactics, and history, this book provides an excellent context for anticapitalist organizing in the years up to and immediately following the WTO protests.

"<a href="http://www.infoshop.org/inews/article.php?story=04/11/30/3793047&amp;mode=print">Five Years After WTO Protests</a>” by Chuck Munson—In this article, one of the administrators of www.infoshop.org refutes corporate media reports that the movement behind the WTO protests had come to an end by 2004.

"<a href="http://www.zmag.org/acme.htm">N30 Black Bloc Communiqué</a>” by the Acme Collective—Some of the participants in the Black Bloc in Seattle released this excellent and nuanced defense of anarchist property destruction at the WTO demonstrations immediately afterwards.

"<a href="/texts/recentfeatures/demonstrating.php">Demonstrating Resistance</a>,” the feature article in the first issue of Rolling Thunder—This extensive analysis follows the anarchist experimentation with mass action and autonomous action models that occurred between 2000 and 2005, drawing conclusions about what factors must be present for each approach to succeed.

1—Ironically, the “anti-globalization movement” was perhaps the most globally interconnected movement in the history of protest movements. The corporate media christened it with that misnomer because identifying it for what it was—a movement opposing capitalist globalization—would acknowledge the existence of capitalism, and thus the possibility of other social and economic systems.

2—Likewise, as the dramatically militarized police force in Miami consisted of at least six times as many officers as protected the WTO in Seattle, and they faced off against crowds perhaps a fifth the size of those that had gathered in 1999, they could not fall back on the excuse of being “overwhelmed” and forced into violence. If anything, the police in Miami were more violent than those in Seattle, thoughtlessly attacking demonstrators, retired union members, and corporate media reporters alike.]]></content_encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp_post_id>61</wp_post_id>
		<wp_post_date><![CDATA[2006-11-30 19:18:50]]></wp_post_date>
		<wp_post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2006-12-01 02:18:50]]></wp_post_date_gmt>
		<wp_comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp_comment_status>
		<wp_ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp_ping_status>
		<wp_post_name><![CDATA[seattle-seven-years-later]]></wp_post_name>
		<wp_status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp_status>
		<wp_post_parent>0</wp_post_parent>
		<wp_menu_order>0</wp_menu_order>
		<wp_post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp_post_type>
		<wp_post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp_post_password>
		<wp_is_sticky>0</wp_is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="read-all-about-it"><![CDATA[Read All About It]]></category>
		<wp_postmeta>
			<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp_meta_key>
			<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp_meta_value>
		</wp_postmeta>
		<wp_postmeta>
			<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[_thumbnail_id]]></wp_meta_key>
			<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[5347]]></wp_meta_value>
		</wp_postmeta>
		<wp_postmeta>
			<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[jumbo]]></wp_meta_key>
			<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[http://www.crimethinc.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2006/11/1b.jpg]]></wp_meta_value>
		</wp_postmeta>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>57</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[Coyote06]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[ztk2006@gmail.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url/>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[72.205.195.96]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2006-11-30 21:58:12]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2006-12-01 04:58:12]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[This document is amazing!  It answers so many of my questions...  Thank you!]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>58</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[red maroot]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[crimethinc@yahoo.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url>http://</wp_comment_author_url>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[66.57.241.33]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2006-12-03 20:58:03]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2006-12-04 03:58:03]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[Hey everyone--

Those of you who have internet access but no printing access and want hard copies of this to distribute should email crimethincbooking@yahoo.com, or else just send a donation to cover postage to 

CrimethInc.
(attn: Rolling Thunder)
P.O. Box 2133
Greensboro, NC 27402]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>59</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[someguy]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[guy_787@hotmail.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url/>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[201.214.77.60]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2007-01-05 18:20:20]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2007-01-06 01:20:20]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[good retrospective.  
but, got to pick at it.  "Even if you don’t want to overthrow the government, forget about voting and petitioning—the only hope for change is in the streets."  
    the author is contrasting voting to direct street action.  but i feel that the issue is put in terms that are too absolute.  i feel the most important work we can be doing is long-term neighborhood organizing.  i'm not making a universal claim, but rather a claim reflecting where our emphasis currently is and what i see as current needs.  we have to start really focusing on community work, espeially if we want to expand beyond a narrow segment of disillusioned traveller kids(myself included).  where do we think street warriors will come from if we don't estblish constructive programs in working class neighborhoods?  
    the author talks about demoralization and the drop off of participation.  me and a lot of friends go to a lot less street actions not because of demoralization but because of a change in tactics and priorities.  the state has diminished our returns on mass protests, and while there are valuable skills to be learned in those confrontations, most of the skills we need are probably better learned in a radical community kid's programlibrarycollective.  
     this isn't to say that i'm against street actions, or mass actions.  i just don't get making it the center of my activity anymore like i used to.  
    the author stresses the demoralization.  my friends and i involved in our community program are the very opposite.  we're more excited and inspired than ever before, as are most the activists i know involved in successful community programs.   if people feel so demoralized maybe they should consider trying some different activities.  
     seattle was perfect, for it's moment.  but mass street action could probably never have been hoped to expand indefinately. it had internal limits; like costs of travel, participants being in a stage in their life that left them free to not work, free to get arrested, etc.  if we want a popular, mass revolution, instead of a vanguard of specialized young professional activist, then the mass street demos probably aren't our ticket. street actions are inclusive in the sense that most young people can come and participate to varying levels.  but it is exclusionary in that most working people with families can't participate, and that's most of the population. we need to create possibilities for useful activity that more normal people can participate in without traveling across the entire fucking country and being arrested and rammed through a legal process.  
      the condition of the movement in the US shouldn't be assesed by how much the communists or liberals are attempting or pretending to control big protest actions.  sure, we could do better, have a better presence, be on top of oppurtunities more, get more literature out, etc we could do it all better, and we should keep striving to.  i saw no anarchist lit being distributed in the huge new york thing against the republican primaries (2004).  the anarchists just filled the ranks without taking much iniative, nor setting the tone.  the liberals organized shit, the communists were getting their lit. out.  so we could definately do better.  
    but still, we shouldn't judge the movement by how much the communist or liberals are pretending to be on top of things.  maybe it's just hard for me to get too worried about such dead-end groups.  but i think anarchists are doing less street activity because they're doing more local work.  if that's true, the the liberals and the communists have an ass-kicking in the mail.  cause that's how we're finally going to bring this motherfucker down.  starting little, effective, cultural, political community groups all through the heartland.  
    but, protests aren't even a good venue to organize, attract, or involve new people.  they are bad for that.  it's classic 19th century liberal and communist method.  and while i've been inspired and excited at protests, i've also been bored out of my mind, learned almost nothing, made ridiculous personal risks for pretty untangible revolutionary gains.  
     just some reflections...]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>60</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[eriick]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[eriick@msn.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url>http://</wp_comment_author_url>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[65.9.26.164]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2007-11-26 22:48:12]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2007-11-27 05:48:12]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[Hey guys, if you have Facebook, please join this group, and honor our democracy by commemorating N30 (11/30/99):

http://www.facebook.com/group.php?gid=6450353524

Thanks!]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>1847</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[| unrest.info]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url>http://unrest.info/?p=160</wp_comment_author_url>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[159.253.149.219]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2013-07-28 08:30:53]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2013-07-28 15:30:53]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[[...] it seems that now we’re experiencing what the insurrectionary anarchists experienced in Seattle in 1999. Pacifists attacking radicalized protesters and anarchists; people giving flowers to policemen and [...]]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[pingback]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
	</item>