<item>
    <title>Test Their Logik Benefit Album</title>
    <link>http://www.crimethinc.com/blog/2010/09/30/test-their-logik-benefit-album/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2010 22:49:09 +0000</pubDate>
    <dc_creator><![CDATA[b. traven]]></dc_creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.crimethinc.com/blog/?p=1525</guid>
    <description/>
    <content_encoded><![CDATA[Two of our favorite hip hop artists, <a href="http://www.crimethinc.com/blog/2009/11/05/testament-kiss-me-through-the-phone/">Testament</a> and Illogik, <a href="http://www.crimethinc.com/blog/2010/09/03/overview-toronto-g20-legal-fallout/#more-1472">are facing serious charges</a> for their alleged involvement in the <a href="http://www.crimethinc.com/texts/recentfeatures/toronto.php">historic protests against the G20 summit</a> in Toronto last June.

Performing as <a href="http://www.myspace.com/testtheirlogik" target="_blank">Test Their Logik</a>, the two were in the middle of preparing their debut album when they were arrested. Now their release conditions prohibit them from associating with each other, and they are unable to continue recording.

Fortunately, we managed to get our hands on the material they finished just before their arrests, and we’re releasing it as a benefit to help with their legal expenses. This is some of the most powerful, passionate music we’ve heard in years; it’s an honor to share it here.

<a href="https://cloudfront.crimethinc.com/images/tlcad/ad_500.jpg" rel="lightbox[ad]" class="smallitem"><img src="https://cloudfront.crimethinc.com/images/tlcad/ad_125.gif"></a><strong>Test Their Logik <br />“Arrested Development” 9-Song Album<br /><a href="https://cloudfront.crimethinc.com/music/ttl_ad_mp3.zip" target="_blank">: 160kbs (VBR) MP3 [40.3MB] :</a><br /><a href="https://cloudfront.crimethinc.com/music/ttl_ad_aac.zip" target="_blank">: 160kbs (VBR) AAC [41.9MB] :</a></strong>
<span class="invisible">-</span>


<strong> <a href="http://g20.torontomobilize.org/support">Click here to make a donation to<br />the Test Their Logik Legal Fund.</a></strong>

The album is available here for free downloading, but we urge everyone to donate to their support fund. If you can’t use Paypal, <a href="http://www.crimethinc.com/blog/2010/09/30/test-their-logik-benefit-album/#a">click here</a> to learn how to send a check to their support committee.

The charges against Testament and Illogik are a shameless attack on political activism. The two <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=p8QNX6WDCpM" target="_blank">have been outspoken critics</a> of the G20, the <a href="http://www.crimethinc.com/blog/2010/02/15/riot-2010/">2010 Olympics</a>, and capitalism in general, publicly speaking out even when others were intimidated into silence. They are among <a href="http://www.crimethinc.com/blog/2010/09/03/overview-toronto-g20-legal-fallout/">over 100 people</a> facing conspiracy charges in connection with the G20 protests, an unprecedented crackdown on dissent.

The charges are also an attack on hip hop. Sure to come up in the trial is the <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ninV5yx7FW4" target="_blank">Crash the Meeting</a> video the two released to promote the G20 protests, which has received nearly 50,000 views on youtube. The video is hardly shocking by corporate hip hop standards; it doesn’t objectify women, promote guns or gang violence, or glorify personal acquisition of wealth. Instead, it spreads a positive message of collective struggle against tyranny—exactly the kind of message the authorities want to keep out of popular music.

Before corporate America started paying attention, groups like Public Enemy used hip hop to spread revolutionary messages and consciousness. Profiteers moved into the hip hop market not only to make millions off it but also to promote artists who rap about pimpin and blingin instead of social change.

Test Their Logik take hip hop back to real life, describing the destruction wrought by capitalism and calling for grassroots resistance. Everything they predicted in the Crash the Meeting video came true in Toronto beyond anyone’s wildest expectations. Essentially, they’re being charged for having their finger on the pulse. The authorities can try to jail the messengers, but there’s nothing they can do to stop the music.

<!--more Additional details after the break.-->
Testament and Illogik were arrested June 27, 2010. Both are charged with Conspiracy to Commit an Indictable Offense, Council to Commit an Indictable Offense, and Disguise with Intent to Commit an Indictable Offense. Testament was also charged with breach of bail as a result of being arrested wheatpasting posters about the G20 in London, Ontario a week before the summit; the charges from that arrest were dropped immediately afterwards and the London police chief went on record saying they had only charged him so he would be out on bail conditions during the G20. Bail was set at $20,000 each.

The release conditions for the two include not associating with each other, not associating with members of “Black Bloc” [sic], not possessing anything that could be used as a disguise including bandanas and scarves, and not associating with various people from Quebec they’ve never met.
<a name="a" title="a" id="a"></a>
If you want to support them but you can’t use Paypal, mail a check made out to Russell Silverstein to:

Test Their Logik Legal Defense Fund
C/O Submedia
2746 East Hastings St. #57024
Vancouver BC V5K 5G8
Canada

<a href="https://cloudfront.crimethinc.com/images/tlcad/1b.jpg" rel="lightbox[ad]" class="legacyimage"><img src="https://cloudfront.crimethinc.com/images/tlcad/1a.jpg"></a>
<span class="invisible">-</span>
<blockquote>
And I’m a poltergeist, you know a violent spirit
Product of a world with too much violence in it
So many people trees and animals’ll die in a minute
Can’t ask them to stop, they ain’t tryin to hear it</blockquote>

]]></content_encoded>
    <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
    <wp_post_id>1525</wp_post_id>
    <wp_post_date><![CDATA[2010-09-30 14:49:09]]></wp_post_date>
    <wp_post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2010-09-30 22:49:09]]></wp_post_date_gmt>
    <wp_comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp_comment_status>
    <wp_ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp_ping_status>
    <wp_post_name><![CDATA[test-their-logik-benefit-album]]></wp_post_name>
    <wp_status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp_status>
    <wp_post_parent>0</wp_post_parent>
    <wp_menu_order>0</wp_menu_order>
    <wp_post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp_post_type>
    <wp_post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp_post_password>
    <wp_is_sticky>0</wp_is_sticky>
    <category domain="category" nicename="calling-all-anarchists"><![CDATA[Calling All Anarchists]]></category>
    <wp_postmeta>
      <wp_meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp_meta_key>
      <wp_meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp_meta_value>
    </wp_postmeta>
    <wp_postmeta>
      <wp_meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_old_slug]]></wp_meta_key>
      <wp_meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp_meta_value>
    </wp_postmeta>
    <wp_comment>
      <wp_comment_id>1353</wp_comment_id>
      <wp_comment_author><![CDATA[puneta]]></wp_comment_author>
      <wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[hacktiffler@riseup.net]]></wp_comment_author_email>
      <wp_comment_author_url/>
      <wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[70.33.147.3]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
      <wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2010-09-30 16:22:09]]></wp_comment_date>
      <wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2010-10-01 00:22:09]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
      <wp_comment_content><![CDATA[I honestly thought with just the headline it would be Testament and Illogik getting caught up in a prank to make a mock metal album.

But now I kinda wish it was actually that... best wishes to y'all and all that have to suffer through the state taking repression and criminalization to its logical conclusion.]]></wp_comment_content>
      <wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
      <wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
      <wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
      <wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
    </wp_comment>
    <wp_comment>
      <wp_comment_id>1354</wp_comment_id>
      <wp_comment_author><![CDATA[ReverendRev]]></wp_comment_author>
      <wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[reverendrev23@gmail.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
      <wp_comment_author_url/>
      <wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[24.30.106.148]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
      <wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2010-11-12 06:27:05]]></wp_comment_date>
      <wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2010-11-12 14:27:05]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
      <wp_comment_content><![CDATA[Great album - very raw and foreceful. As soon as I get a hold of some cash, I'll send it their way.]]></wp_comment_content>
      <wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
      <wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
      <wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
      <wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
    </wp_comment>
    <wp_comment>
      <wp_comment_id>1355</wp_comment_id>
      <wp_comment_author><![CDATA[Michael Lessard]]></wp_comment_author>
      <wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[miclesgeo@yahoo.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
      <wp_comment_author_url>http://www.reseauforum.org</wp_comment_author_url>
      <wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[69.157.144.223]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
      <wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2011-01-08 18:41:24]]></wp_comment_date>
      <wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2011-01-09 02:41:24]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
      <wp_comment_content><![CDATA[« not associating with various people from Quebec they’ve never met »

I'm from Quebec City, and I am of course pissed off when reading this. Blatant discrimination of the people of Quebec. Do they teach human rights and civil liberties to the police! (I'm trying very hard here to remain polite).

Anyhow, we've met before ! You gave a show at a coop-bar in Quebec City, so fuck their anti-democratic bail conditions. Welcome back to Quebec City in January!]]></wp_comment_content>
      <wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
      <wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
      <wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
      <wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
      <wp_commentmeta>
        <wp_meta_key><![CDATA[akismet_result]]></wp_meta_key>
        <wp_meta_value><![CDATA[false]]></wp_meta_value>
      </wp_commentmeta>
      <wp_commentmeta>
        <wp_meta_key><![CDATA[akismet_history]]></wp_meta_key>
        <wp_meta_value><![CDATA[a:4:{s:4:"time";s:13:"1294540885.21";s:7:"message";s:28:"Akismet cleared this comment";s:5:"event";s:9:"check-ham";s:4:"user";s:15:"Michael Lessard";}]]></wp_meta_value>
      </wp_commentmeta>
    </wp_comment>
  </item>