<item>
		<title>Eco-Defense and Repression in Russia</title>
		<link>http://www.crimethinc.com/blog/2010/10/19/eco-defense-and-repression-in-russia/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Oct 2010 16:40:35 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc_creator><![CDATA[b. traven]]></dc_creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.crimethinc.com/blog/?p=1589</guid>
		<description/>
		<content_encoded><![CDATA[We just received this inspiring and instructive report from anonymous comrades in Russia, describing two years of struggle against logging operations in one of the major forests near Moscow. The struggle culminated this summer in the “Khimki battle,” in which several hundred armed antifascists and anarchists attacked a government building in suburban Moscow; the authorities responded in kind, and subsequent solidarity efforts in Belarus provoked further repression.

Most of the links in this text lead to Russian-language pages; those too busy to teach themselves Russian can at least plug the website addresses into <a href="http://translate.google.com/#ru|en|" target="_blank">Google translate</a> and struggle through computer-generated translations.

<!--more Read on after the break.-->


<strong>Prelude: A Spiking We Will Go</strong>

We learned of Moscow city authorities’ <a href="http://ecmo.ru/problems/Road/?drgn=2" target="_blank">plans to destroy the Khimki forest</a> in summer of 2008, when local environmentalists started an outreach campaign to drum up support for their cause. Even then it was already late, since the forest—one of the three major forests surrounding Moscow—had already been extensively logged and was pockmarked with tumors: cottages for the nouveau-riche, warehouses, parking lots, and malls.

So without a minute to lose, we grabbed some spikes and rushed in. The logging site was patrolled by guards, but their attention was distracted by the official “eco-camp” in front of their cabin so it was easy to sneak in and <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tree_spiking" target="_blank">spike</a> every tree we could get our nails into. This was our first experience of eco-action and it was exciting and inspiring: we didn’t get caught and we accomplished what we had come to do. We were sure that between our action, the constant pressure liberal ecologists were putting on the authorities, and the popular movement gaining momentum in the local suburbs, the tree-killers would retreat and leave the forest for good. Soon we learned better.

The trees were being felled to prepare the way for a massive new road plan authorized by the federal government. High-ranking officials—as high-ranking as <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vladimir_Putin" target="_blank">Putin</a> himself, we later learned—had a stake in lobbying for the new toll highway to be built right through the forest. The construction was financed by the international syndicate <a href="http://eco.rian.ru/nature/20100720/256646955.html" target="_blank">Vinci</a>, <a href="http://www.vinci.com/" target="_blank">headquartered in France</a>, and several European banks working in partnership with the Russian national bank, <a href="http://ru.indymedia.org/newswire/display/23872/index.php" target="_blank">Sberbank</a>. With such powerful enemies arrayed against the forest and its defenders, the situation turned ugly.


<strong>Foreword: The Russian Context</strong>

<blockquote>“Those numbers are murdered antifascists only. We don’t know exactly how many immigrants are killed by Nazis every year.”
-Anarchist spokesperson at an international Antifa conference</blockquote>

In fall 2008, Khimki journalist <a href="http://www.beketov-fond.ru/" target="_blank">Mikhail Beketov</a>, who played a major role in news coverage of the corrupt road plans of local and government officials, was brutally attacked by thugs. The attack left him in a coma and he later had to have his legs amputated. That same month, elsewhere in Moscow, <a href="http://www.ikd.ru/node/7846" target="_blank">several well-known activists were attacked or threatened with violence</a>. That’s not to say that cops haven’t <a href="http://community.livejournal.com/himki_protest/7509.html" target="_blank">beaten ecologists before</a>. But it was the first time such blatant attempts were made on the lives of our comrades.

We were sucked into “the wormhole of violence” in the dead of winter 2009, when Stanislav Markelov, who provided legal support for Beketov, and Anastasya Baburova, an eco-anarchist and journalist, were <a href="http://ru.wikipedia.org/wiki/Убийство_Станислава_Маркелова_и_Анастасии_Бабуровой" target="_blank">shot dead in the center of Moscow</a>. By the time some of us returned to the surface—fortunately, almost unscathed—the whole activist landscape had changed.

Since winter 2009 the streets of Russian cities have been rife with Nazi/Antifa violence, as the conflict has steadily shifted from the social-political context towards a scenario of gang warfare. This context is crucial for understanding how the struggle for Khimki forest developed.

For almost six years now, the anti-authoritarian movement in Russia has consisted primarily of two wings, one ecological and the other antifascist; the former is primarily anarchist, but the antifascist movement also includes significant participation from patriots and Stalinist parties. These groups meet infrequently at convergences, eco-camps, and other events such as the numerous <i>in memoriam</i> actions dedicated to murdered comrades. But with machismo increasing in the antifascist scene because of the perceived necessity to maim and kill more Nazis in retaliation for Nazi attacks, and paranoia spreading in the eco-defense movement because of the need to <a href="http://ru.indymedia.org/newswire/display/23531/index.php" target="_blank">constantly attack construction sites and engines</a> in the absence of popular opposition to deforestation, the rift widened. By the time of the Khimki defense, the movement was already straining to maintain coherence. Some people suspect that if it weren’t for the <a href="http://www.gzt.ru/topnews/accidents/272115.html" target="_blank">selective murders of the few anarchists and antifascists</a> wise and widely respected enough to hold the various schisms in check, the movement would have been more prepared for this crisis.


<strong>Interlude: We Don’t Need No Water</strong>

Two years after our first adventure, we experienced a touching reunion with our dear forest. It was the first night of the resumed logging operation when we disembarked from our special eco-defense vehicle and ran for the cover of the nearby tree line. In several minutes we changed clothes and double-checked our comms, camouflage, and the presents we had brought along for the construction vehicles. Soon several shadows glided silently over the nocturnal plain under the pale moonlight towards the faraway forest, which was still alive and foreboding.

When we arrived at the logging encampment, we split up. Some of us lay in the romantic cover of some bushes, enjoying the stars and the sound of each other’s breath; our friends who were more eager to do reconnaissance bounded off toward the black shapes of tractors and excavators. Then all hell broke loose. Suddenly we could hear the all-too-familiar sound of a vehicle going up in flames, which sometimes reminds one of a jet plane flying overhead. The entire forest was bathed in dancing red and orange light, and the comms scouts were yelling in surprise. We tried to figure out what had happened. Luckily we evaded the guards’ attention and made it back to our transport on the remote and empty road. Red lights, comm talk—and we were sound and safe, spirited away to another town.

<a href="http://directaction.info/news_july18_10.htm" target="_blank">As it turned out</a>, ours was not the only group sneaking around the site that busy night. Needless to say, the inhabitants of the eco-camp were blamed for the arson. In fact, the presence of the camp actually prevented eco-defenders from damaging everything they wanted to—that is why only one vehicle was torched at the site. But this didn’t occur to the logging manager, who immediately requested a police investigation of the arson and the ecologists’ suspected part in it; soon enough, he got his revenge on them in a perverse but typically Russian manner.

Over the following days our scouts reported increased guard and cop nighttime activity around the logging site, including roadblocks and patrols in the vicinity, so eco-defenders had to cancel their initial plans and <a href="http://directaction.info/news_july09_10.htm" target="_blank">shift focus a bit</a>. Khimki is a big forest, and the logging and despoiling of wildlife in the name of profit took place almost everywhere. The incident did raise serious questions regarding overall security though: because ELF groups do not share their plans with each other, such accidental encounters are bound to happen again and again as these methods are propagated.

<a href="http://thecloud.crimethinc.com/images/russia/2b.jpg" rel="lightbox[russia]"  class="legacyimage" class="legacyimage"><img src="http://thecloud.crimethinc.com/images/russia/2a.jpg" /></a>
<center><em>A logging truck sheds some light on the ecological policy of the Russian government.</em></center>


<strong>Enter the Nazis</strong>

As we found out later, one early morning we barely missed <a href="http://izhevsk.avtonom.org/2010/07/23/football_huligans_attack_himkhi_forest_ecologists_/" target="_blank">a mob of hired Nazi thugs</a> who were marching towards the eco-camp at about the same time we were escaping yet again into the mist after another scouting mission. Upon arriving, they started verbally and physically abusing every eco-protestor present, but settled for guarding the logging equipment once the police made their appearance. A <a href="http://wisegizmo.livejournal.com/38246.html" target="_blank">top manager of the logging company later admitted</a> that he had hired the Nazis “for security reasons.”

This episode showed every doubting critic how easily capitalists fall back upon fascist support—a truism not yet obvious even to most activists in Russia—and sparked a fire in the hearts of the previously dormant antifascist wing of our movement. The confrontation that morning did more to popularize and escalate the conflict than any eco-camp, internet PR campaign, or eco-defense action ever could have. Some of our comrades reflected that what we had witnessed was a fine example of how an unforeseen, unplanned, chaotic event—even one deemed negative—can push the movement and its supporters in the right direction.

That is to say, in a <i>revolutionary</i> direction.

<a href="http://thecloud.crimethinc.com/images/russia/3b.jpg" rel="lightbox[russia]" class="legacyimage"><img src="http://thecloud.crimethinc.com/images/russia/3a.jpg" /></a>
<center><em>The corpulent guy with the number 19 painted on his t-shirt has been identified as the leader of the right-wing football support mob “Gladiators.”</em></center>


<strong>The Khimki Battle</strong>

The loggers had made a major mistake. Employing Nazis in what was perceived by almost every citizen as an anti-human project broke the ranks of the extreme right; most fascist groups tried to capitalize on the situation by posing as opponents of the destruction of the forest. More importantly, now every antifascist in the vicinity had enemies in sight and rushed to the battle.

The next day the announcement went out that a huge unpermitted show would take place in the center of Moscow. Hundreds of anti-authoritarian activists, antifascists, and party-goers gathered in anticipation of a street-party with a <a href="http://www.antifa.ru/4700.html" target="_blank">long-disbanded famous antifascist band</a> as the headliner. Instead, as everybody arrived at the meeting place a guy in sunglasses announced that there would be no show, no street-party, and that the plan all along had been to go to the suburbs and attack the logging camp and the Nazis gathered there. Some people left, but the majority set out for Khimki.

While most of protesters were traveling via railway, scouts reported multiple riot police squads at the logging site. It was then decided to head for the Khimki municipal building—Khimki formally being a town in its own right—which was defenseless while every available police unit was on guard in the forest. Dressed for a party, people gathered in a bright and colorful bloc at the railway station and started marching towards the target. The bloc was accompanied by two scooters that acted as lookouts and rear guard during the action. At first local residents reacted with fear or suspicion, but after hearing the slogans and reading the banner or talking to protestors many expressed approval and support. Cars continued honking throughout the march and assault on the building.

<a href="http://thecloud.crimethinc.com/images/russia/4a.jpg" rel="lightbox[russia]" class="legacyimage"><img src="http://thecloud.crimethinc.com/images/russia/4a.jpg" /></a>
<center><em>At the doorstep of the ecological riots.</em></center>

So it came to pass that on July 28 in broad daylight, with the approval of hundreds of onlookers, several hundred anarchists and antifascists gathered in the center of Moscow, traveled to the railway station, hopped on the train, rode to the suburban district Khimki, disembarked, blocked up, and marched up to the municipal office chanting and lighting flares. Participants immediately commenced <a href="http://svpressa.ru/society/article/28356/" target="_blank">breaking windows, painting anti-logging and pro-forest graffiti, opening fire on the building with handguns, and even chopping the front door with an axe</a>. Throughout this action no police officer showed up to protect state property.

Satisfied with the damage done and having received word from lookouts that riot police were loading up into busses at the logging camp, anarchists and antifascists started back towards the railway station. At this moment, two encounters with police took place. The first to face the angry mob were several cops on foot, who were strolling down the street when it suddenly flooded with anarchists. The cops retreated to the sound of breaking bottles and crashing stones. Then a police patrol made the mistake of trying to intervene in the protest; they quickly realized their mistake and retreated. Unfortunately, antifascists on foot couldn’t catch up with the swiftly retreating police car. It should be pointed out that, although the local populace supported the action verbally and symbolically via honking horns, the action failed to entice onlookers into any sort of participation.

<a href="http://thecloud.crimethinc.com/images/russia/5b.jpg" rel="lightbox[russia]" class="legacyimage"><img src="http://thecloud.crimethinc.com/images/russia/5a.jpg" /></a>
<center><em>Cops fleeing anarchists.</em></center>

Nevertheless, protestors managed to reach the railway station and crowd into the train, where they waited patiently for the doors to close. The doors, however, did not close. As it turned out, the locomotive driver was at that moment involved in a tense conversation with the police commander. A group of antifascists with handguns was quickly dispatched to explain to him the negative consequences of siding with our class enemies, and finally the engine started moving, pulling the train towards the safety of the big city with no trees.

Criticism has been raised in the aftermath of this event about the distribution of information, the lack of advance organizing, and on-site video recording. Most of the people who took part had initially expected to attend a street party and arrived unprepared for direct action, without matching clothes, masks, or gloves and with working cell phones. Many young participants used social transport cards with ID tags in them to gain entrance to subway. The few organizers who <i>did</i> know the whole plan from the beginning hadn’t prepared accordingly and failed to provide even the most minor riot gear such as face masks. This led to a huge number of protestors being videotaped with their facial features clearly distinguishable.

The Russian anti-authoritarian movement has yet to learn from its own mistakes when it comes to video recording during street protests. Protesters and “media-activists,” most of whom turned out to be journalists invited from the liberal press, failed to recognize what a fatal mistake it was to videotape the unmasked faces of activists. Some of these reporters continued shooting even after people had gotten into the train and started pulling their masks off, so even participants who had provided for their own security failed to remain anonymous in the end because of this media-activism fetish. Later, people interrogated by the police reported that they were presented with a frame-by-frame breakdown of <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IB6RtXg2x80&feature=related" target="_blank">the video that circulated on the internet</a>. Some comrades have been forced to leave the country because of this evidence.

<center><object width="453" height="280"><param name="movie" value="http://www.youtube.com/v/IB6RtXg2x80?fs=1&amp;hl=en_US&amp;rel=0&amp;color1=0x3a3a3a&amp;color2=0x999999"></param><param name="allowFullScreen" value="true"></param><param name="allowscriptaccess" value="always"></param><embed src="http://www.youtube.com/v/IB6RtXg2x80?fs=1&amp;hl=en_US&amp;rel=0&amp;color1=0x3a3a3a&amp;color2=0x999999" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" allowscriptaccess="always" allowfullscreen="true" width="453" height="280"></embed></object></center>


<center><object width="452" height="364"><param name="movie" value="http://www.youtube.com/v/jei64glPpQA?fs=1&amp;hl=en_US&amp;rel=0&amp;color1=0x3a3a3a&amp;color2=0x999999"></param><param name="allowFullScreen" value="true"></param><param name="allowscriptaccess" value="always"></param><embed src="http://www.youtube.com/v/jei64glPpQA?fs=1&amp;hl=en_US&amp;rel=0&amp;color1=0x3a3a3a&amp;color2=0x999999" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" allowscriptaccess="always" allowfullscreen="true" width="452" height="364"></embed></object></center>
<center><em>Video footage of the action.</em></center>


<strong>The Fallout: Repression and Solidarity</strong>

<a href="http://www.avtonom.org/en/node/12872" target="_blank">Alexei Gaskarov and Maxim Solopov, public spokespersons for the Russian antifascist movement, were arrested on July 30</a>. This was followed by attempts to capture several other suspected organizers; because of their frustrating failure to turn themselves in, they were placed on a wanted list.

Facing intense pressure from government officials, unable to catch the elusive anarchists and receiving little cooperation from anyone, the police opted for massive sweeps of “prophylactic arrests.” Throughout August and September more than 500 antifascists, activists, and anarchists were detained, put in custody, tortured, and bullied into providing information on the movement—not only in Moscow, but in Nizhni Novgorod, Vladimir, and other cities as well. Police harassed people at public Antifa and animal rights events, football matches, and gatherings. Following this sweep, the sheer volume of data on the movement has swelled tenfold. As of this writing it seems that our enemies have moved on to the next phase, probing further into the network in what appears to be a third wave of interrogations of a select few activists who have been apprehended and deemed “interesting.”

It is still too early to draw conclusions, but some ideas about this repression can be explored, if only as a basis for future discussions. It is now obvious that the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Federal_Security_Service_(Russia)" target="_blank">FSB</a>, the Russian secret service, didn’t have any aces up their sleeves; their investigators have been joining in and ganging up on detainees from the start without a particular plan. Only two people are in jail awaiting trial, the main reason for their apprehension being their public profiles. The choice to rely on sweeping arrests and the total failure of the authorities to round up any direct action group despite all their attempts to convert detained activists into informants indicate that the Russian police approached 2010 unprepared in terms of provocateurs and informants within the Russian anti-authoritarian movement. This situation, of course, <i>may yet change.</i>

With all this said, it seems that the repression succeeded soundly in several ways. First, the movement seems to be isolated in a cocoon of fear. Support from outside is meager at best; social activists are second-guessing their cooperation with known antifascists. Second, almost every known “leader” or “organizer” has either been jailed or driven into hiding. Third, the authorities have managed to gather an ever-increasing amount of information since, as often happens, those who read about security practices and try to implement them in their daily lives are frequently not the ones who end up being arrested and answering questions.

Finally, and most importantly, almost everyone has forgotten about the original problem. Just as the capitalist leviathan has overextended itself, our movement has thinned its resources by betting everything on an ill-conceived riot and now all we can do is try to stem the rising tide of repression. This has happened before: in 2008 <a href="http://www.grani.ru/Politics/Russia/activism/m.135801.html" target="_blank">an anti-police campaign</a> turned into <a href="http://www.avtonom.org/node/8527" target="_blank">a prisoner support campaign</a> after police started hitting back with arrests and trials. Now we are watching the original environmental campaign fade into the background while prisoner support actions demand more and more attention.

There may be ways for anarchists to use the situation to our advantage, both in anti-Nazi outreach efforts and narratives and as an opportunity to reach out to the ecological movement and grassroots collectives. But the way the movement perceives itself has changed dramatically and we may need some reflection and self-assessment if we are to outmaneuver our enemies at this stage.

This is not to say that prisoner support is unimportant. Solidarity campaigns are crucial not only for the people in jail facing trial, but for the sake of those who <i>may end up there yet.</i> However, we should not forget the reason our comrades were arrested in the first place.

<blockquote><b><i>Most importantly, almost everybody has forgotten about the original problem. Our movement has thinned resources by betting everything on an ill-conceived riot, and now all we can do is try to stem the rising tide of repression.
</i></b></blockquote>



<strong>Two Cocktail Parties</strong>

On September 2, <a href="http://belarus.avtonom.org/?p=15178" target="_blank">the Russian embassy in Minsk, the capital of Belarus, was firebombed by anarchists</a>. One of the Molotov cocktails hit a car parked in the yard. The car burned up. Evidently, this was the only damage inflicted by the attackers. Soon <a href="http://belarus.avtonom.org/?p=15171" target="_blank">a communiqué</a> was published on Belarusian anarchist websites, stating that the attack had taken place in solidarity with the Russian anarchists fighting for the Khimki forest and that Belarusian anarchists held the Russian government responsible both for the continuing deforestation and the repression of the movement.

The next morning repression hit the Belarusian scene. It took the Belarusian <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/State_Security_Committee_of_the_Republic_of_Belarus" target="_blank">KGB</a> several days to round up and arrest almost every known or suspected anarchist in Minsk, Gomel, Soligorsk, and other Belarusian cities. Our comrades were pressed for confessions of having cooperated with the Russian secret services in an attempt to discredit the Belarusian government and bring down <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alexander_Lukashenko" target="_blank">Lukashenko</a>’s regime. Most were formally questioned, then locked away and “forgotten” in cells for several days.

Some of our friends were not so lucky. One girl was hospitalized after she cut her veins during interrogation; another person, with previously existing serious health issues, developed major health problems as a result of the prison conditions and the severe beatings he received. Some lucky few fled the country; others stayed, taking it upon themselves to organize prisoner support campaigns. Among those who stayed were the comrades brave enough to carry out a follow-up attack on the Minsk detention center three days after the KGB started mass-arresting anarchists. A group calling itself “Friends of Liberty” <a href="http://blackblocg.blogspot.com/2010/09/blog-post_05.html" target="_blank">firebombed a guard post in the detention center perimeter</a> and claimed responsibility for both firebombing attacks—the Russian embassy and the police guard post—on the internet. <a href="http://blackblocg.blogspot.com/2010_09_05_archive.html" target="_blank">In their second communiqué</a>, “Friends of Liberty” stated that the KGB reacted by arresting innocent people simply because the latter had already been on the KGB’s radar. The aim of their second attack was evidently noble and brave: to demonstrate that the KGB got the wrong suspects. But the KGB was acting on Lukashenko’s direct order to “pacify the opposition,” a common practice in both Russia and Belarus shortly before presidential elections; so arrests, disappearances, and tortures continued unabated.


<strong>The Wings of a Butterfly </strong>

<blockquote>“Anarchy is all about order, not chaos.”
-popular Russian anarchist saying</blockquote>



Two notable events marked the fall of 2010: a deepening crisis in Belarusian-Russian relations, and the removal of Luzhkov from his position as the mayor of Moscow. Anarchists did their best to bring about both events.

Luzhkov, a petty Moscow tyrant who’d been abusing his position as mayor for more than 10 years, was relieved of his duties by presidential decree “for incompetence and failure to stand up to expectations.” This occurred immediately after he returned from vacation, a month after the Khimki riots. Among the reasons cited by experts and analysts was Luzhkov’s <a href="http://www.dw-world.de/dw/article/0,,6031529,00.html" target="_blank">failure to cope with the Khimki crisis, as well as the part he played in the corrupt city development program</a>.

Lukashenko, the Belarusian national-socialist dictator, gave in to fits of rage and <a href="http://top.rbc.ru/politics/02/09/2010/459150.shtml" target="_blank">anti-Russian rhetoric</a> after the anarchist attacks on the Russian embassy and the police detention center where most of the anarchists arrested in Minsk were being held. An exchange of notes at the highest levels of diplomacy failed to avert the crisis, which had already been brewing before the Molotovs hit their targets. <a href="http://www.regnum.ru/news/russia/1333044.html" target="_blank">A series of bad political and economic decisions</a>, the conspiracy-theory worldview every dictator seems inclined to, and a minor anarchist action <a href="http://www.ng.ru/cis/2010-09-03/6_minsk.html" target="_blank">led to the deepest political crisis Russia and Belarus have yet experienced</a>.

This is not to imply that the departure of the mayor of Moscow and the collapse of relations with Lukashenko happened as a result of an anarchist plot or anything else along those lines. But it is important not to lose sight of the political perspective. We should consider the ways our actions can sometimes contribute to significant social changes and political upheavals—or at least scare the shit out of rich bastards!—however minor (like the Minsk firebombing) or major (like the Khimki battle) these actions may seem to participants and experts. It may be impossible to plan such things ahead of time, but we—boisterous chaos-loving anarchists—should take heart from these developments nevertheless. Hope for change and <i>be the change.</i>

<a href="http://thecloud.crimethinc.com/images/russia/6b.jpg" rel="lightbox[russia]" class="legacyimage"><img src="http://thecloud.crimethinc.com/images/russia/6a.jpg" /></a>
<center><em>A butterfly in the Khimki forest.</em></center>


<strong>Calls for solidarity</strong>



<blockquote>Freedom for the working class can be won only by the working class itself.
-Nestor Makhno</blockquote>



Repression hit both the Belarusian and Russian anarchist scenes hard, and we are in dire need of support from around the world. <a href="http://belarus.indymedia.org/21366" target="_blank">A call circulated for solidarity actions in support of the Belarusian anarchists (in jail for suspected firebombing attempt) on October 14-20</a>; solidarity actions are called for the Khimki arrestees this coming November 12-15.

Also, as much as we need solidarity and support for our friends in prison and in hiding, let us not forget about the forest that’s still being threatened with destruction. We ask for international support for the eco-defense campaign against the <a href="http://www.novopol.ru/-o-chem-shumit-himkinskiy-les-text88471.html" target="_blank">deforestation planned by the Russian government</a> backed by <a href="http://www.ecmo.ru/signs/alternative/?drgn=3" target="_blank">Vinci Group and other international financial institutions</a>.

You can read more about the repression in Belarus and planned solidarity actions <a href="http://belarus.indymedia.org/" target="_blank">on Belarus indymedia</a>.

Information about the solidarity campaign in support of arrestees after “the Khimki battle” is available at <a href="http://khimkibattle.org/" target="_blank">www.khimkibattle.org</a>.

You can contact the Moscow Anarchist Black Cross via <a href="http://wiki.golosa.info/en/index.php?title=Portal:Anarchist_Black_Cross" target="_blank">this site</a> to learn more about supporting anarchist prisoners in Russia.

You can send letters to the prisoners in Moscow care of this address:

&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;P/B 13 109028 Moscow, Russia.

Letters should be sent in an envelope without any name on it. Letters can also be sent to the prisoners digitally via the email address <a href="mailto:helphimki@gmail.com" target="_blank">helphimki@gmail.com</a>.

Finally, support stencil PDFs are available <a href="https://www.avtonom.org/node/12969" target="_blank">here</a>.]]></content_encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp_post_id>1589</wp_post_id>
		<wp_post_date><![CDATA[2010-10-19 08:40:35]]></wp_post_date>
		<wp_post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2010-10-19 16:40:35]]></wp_post_date_gmt>
		<wp_comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp_comment_status>
		<wp_ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp_ping_status>
		<wp_post_name><![CDATA[eco-defense-and-repression-in-russia]]></wp_post_name>
		<wp_status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp_status>
		<wp_post_parent>0</wp_post_parent>
		<wp_menu_order>0</wp_menu_order>
		<wp_post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp_post_type>
		<wp_post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp_post_password>
		<wp_is_sticky>0</wp_is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="read-all-about-it"><![CDATA[Read All About It]]></category>
		<wp_postmeta>
			<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp_meta_key>
			<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp_meta_value>
		</wp_postmeta>
		<wp_postmeta>
			<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_old_slug]]></wp_meta_key>
			<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp_meta_value>
		</wp_postmeta>
		<wp_postmeta>
			<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[_thumbnail_id]]></wp_meta_key>
			<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[3055]]></wp_meta_value>
		</wp_postmeta>
		<wp_postmeta>
			<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[jumbo]]></wp_meta_key>
			<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[http://thecloud.crimethinc.com/images/russia/1b.jpg]]></wp_meta_value>
		</wp_postmeta>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>1362</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[Copylefter]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[alexander.bidin@gmail.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url/>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[95.220.168.187]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2010-10-20 05:39:01]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2010-10-20 13:39:01]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[Ive been surprised that in this article there's no link to the official site of the  campaign against repressions on russian antifascists wich contains a lot of information translated into english and other european languages. 
http://khimkibattle.org/]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>1363</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[b. traven]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[b@crimethinc.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url>http://www.crimethinc.com</wp_comment_author_url>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[71.23.109.102]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2010-10-20 09:16:33]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2010-10-20 17:16:33]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[Actually, that website is linked near the end: "Information about the solidarity campaign in support of arrestees after “the Khimki battle” is available here."

But maybe we could make it more explicit. Thanks for pointing it out.]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>2</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>1365</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[xkathrynx]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[xtradone@yahoo.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url/>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[75.168.249.9]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2010-10-20 21:56:43]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2010-10-21 05:56:43]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[i'm not sure what is meant by "stalinist antifascist".  mentioned in paragraph four under "russian context".  not saying it's impossible, just never read of that possibility.  ? can someone link me to a site defining the stalinist party with a slant that is inclusive of anti-fascism?  thanks, k]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>1366</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[b. traven]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[b@crimethinc.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url>http://www.crimethinc.com</wp_comment_author_url>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[71.23.109.102]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2010-10-20 22:39:55]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2010-10-21 06:39:55]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[K--We'll have to let Russians answer this for the context of this article. The really short version would be that the relationship between Stalinism and fascism is a complicated one, with Stalin and Hitler having concluded a pact at one point, and yet Stalin having presided over the defeat of the Nazis shortly thereafter, establishing a legacy by which Stalinism could be associated with antifascism (despite sharing certain characteristics with fascism).]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>2</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
	</item>