<item>
		<title>Latest Actions Against the Minutemen</title>
		<link>http://www.crimethinc.com/blog/2007/01/17/latest-actions-against-the-minutemen/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2007 04:57:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc_creator><![CDATA[peter p]]></dc_creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crimethinc.com/blog/2007/01/17/latest-actions-against-the-minutemen/</guid>
		<description/>
		<content_encoded><![CDATA[<b>Wrap up for Anti-Minuteman Project demonstration on Jan. 15:</b>
<i>Marie Callenders restaurant, San Juan Capistrano</i>

On short notice after a last minute discovery of a special Minuteman Project meeting organizers were able to pull together a crowd of about 30 people to make <a href=http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jim_Gilchrist  target="blank">Gilchrist</a>, Minuteman Project founder, and his foolish legions feel unwelcome. The mixed faces of anti-racist activists, community leaders, anarchists, media, and families from the surrounding neighborhood took to the sidewalk in front of the restaurant holding signs and rallying support from the passing traffic.

<!--more-->

An inside source tipped the activists off as to the exact time that Jim Gilchrist was going to be delivering his speech. A spontaneous plan was put in to effect that began with the activists pretending to leave. The sly crowd then hopped a small wall and entered a park that allowed them to be just a few feet away from the Minuteman Project meeting. Managing to elude 30 or so Sheriff's deputies (and helicopter) and catch the room full of Minutemen completely off guard they announced their presence by chanting, “Hey Gilchrist you’re a clown, racist Minutemen get out of our town!” According to our inside sources our timing was perfect sending the entire room into chaos right as Gilchrist was at a highlight in his foolish speech!

The group then reassembled in front of the restaurant and offered the Minutemen the kind of send off that racist assholes deserve. Gilchrist was forced to sneak out through the kitchen and, as discomfort showed on the faces of the rest of the Minutemen, the crowd was quick to point out the fact that the police were there to protect them because they, indeed, needed protection.

Upon being sure that all of the Minutemen were gone the activists disbanded and headed home to warm frozen fingers and toes knowing that they had taken a brave stand against racism.

We are getting better at confronting these assholes but we need your help. Keep an eye out because more action against the Minuteman Project is coming soon.

Join us next time!]]></content_encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp_post_id>63</wp_post_id>
		<wp_post_date><![CDATA[2007-01-17 21:57:25]]></wp_post_date>
		<wp_post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2007-01-18 04:57:25]]></wp_post_date_gmt>
		<wp_comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp_comment_status>
		<wp_ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp_ping_status>
		<wp_post_name><![CDATA[latest-actions-against-the-minutemen]]></wp_post_name>
		<wp_status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp_status>
		<wp_post_parent>0</wp_post_parent>
		<wp_menu_order>0</wp_menu_order>
		<wp_post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp_post_type>
		<wp_post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp_post_password>
		<wp_is_sticky>0</wp_is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="from-the-trenches"><![CDATA[From the Trenches]]></category>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>68</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[mynamewasunavailable]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[mynamewasunavailable@hotmail.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url>http://</wp_comment_author_url>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[72.194.98.154]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2007-02-27 13:45:01]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2007-02-27 20:45:01]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[The story continues:

San Juan Capistrano.
2/21/07

Meeting canceled.
Jim Gilchrist and Minutemen Project supporters banned from local eatery.

Victory is being enjoyed tonight by social justice activists working to counter the nationalism, violence, and justice deterring efforts of the Minuteman Project. Those who gathered this evening in front of Marie Callender's restaurant, a long time favorite meeting place for Jim Gilchrist and his Minuteman Project supporters, thoroughly enjoyed witnessing Jim and his friends being denied entry and forced to leave by the Orange County Sheriff Department. With the meeting canceled, egos deflated, and tails between their legs the Minute-fools left one carload at a time as the activist took full advantage of the chance to rub this victory in their "patriotic" faces.

Before being banished from his favorite restaurant Jim himself was confronted and asked to offer an intelligent argument as to why anyone should support his project. As usual he said nothing. Apparently it isn't possible. A couple of other Minutemen took a stab at intelligent reasoning but, not surprisingly, failed. One invented a new classification of asshole that he called "Americanist" or "Americanism." The other offered dizzying logic about how only immigrants steal and if we reform immigration laws we wouldn't have to lock the doors to our houses or cars anymore. Wow. 

About a month ago the counter Minuteman movement upon discovering this long time secret meeting spot immediately organized to establish counter presence and Marie Callender's was asked to make the sound ethical choice to stop supporting the Minuteman Project. Upon trying to reserve their usual room this month the Minutemen were denied. In a second attempt they tried to reserve a large table under a fake name but showing up in mass and flying flags like idiots blew their cover. Marie Callender's assured the activists that the Minutemen would no longer be welcomed and, in fact, asked to be notified if plans for meeting at the restaurant in the future were discovered.

To the Minuteman project: 
We promised that you would no longer feel welcomed in the community of San Juan Capistrano. We promised that we would strip you of your comfortable little meeting place. Tonight it happened.
We have also promised that the Minuteman Project will always be met with resistance and that the Minuteman Project will fall. 
WE KEEP OUR PROMISES.

In solidarity with those who seek justice for all people,
Anti-Minutemen Project.]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
	</item>