<item>
		<title>Poster Series: What Does Democracy Mean?</title>
		<link>http://www.crimethinc.com/blog/2012/04/29/poster-series-what-does-democracy-mean/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2012 00:02:38 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc_creator><![CDATA[b. traven]]></dc_creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.crimethinc.com/blog/?p=2312</guid>
		<description/>
		<content_encoded><![CDATA[Just in time for May Day, we are excited to debut a new line of posters: <a href="http://cloudfront.crimethinc.com/images/democracymeans/democracy-posters.pdf" target="_blank"><strong>“What Does Democracy Mean?” [PDFs 700k]</strong></a> Together, the posters explain how democracy depends upon policing, borders, and other institutions of control. Please print, photocopy, and circulate widely!

<p>We hope that this series will help to clear up lingering confusion about the differences between democracy (a form of government) and anarchy (i.e., freedom). Democracy, even direct democracy, is not the same as self-determination. Democracy is premised on the idea that only one decision-making body should have legitimate authority, while anarchism proposes the decentralization of power: not just horizontality, but also autonomy.</p>

<p>Just as anticapitalism has entered public consciousness in the US since we published last year’s <a href="http://www.crimethinc.com/blog/2011/06/27/supplementary-materials-for-work/">line of anti-capitalist posters</a>, the coming year may see people looking for alternatives to democracy as well. It’s up to us to offer liberating possibilities, since the other alternatives to democracy are even more oppressive than it is.</p>

<!--more Read on after the jump.-->


<strong>What Does Democracy Mean?</strong>

<p>Our forebears overthrew kings and dictators, but they didn’t abolish the institutions by which kings and dictators ruled: they <em>democratized</em> them. Yet whoever operates these institutions—whether it’s a king, a president, or an electorate—the experience on the receiving end is roughly the same. Laws, bureaucracy, and police came before democracy; they function the same way in a democracy as in a dictatorship. The only difference is that, because we can cast ballots about how they should be applied, we’re supposed to regard them as <em>ours</em> even when they’re used against us.</p>

<a href="http://cloudfront.crimethinc.com/images/democracymeans/1b.jpg" rel="lightbox[dm]" class="legacyimage"><img src="http://cloudfront.crimethinc.com/images/democracymeans/1a.jpg" /></a><span class="invisible">-</span>
<strong><em>Democracy means police.</strong></em> Democracy doesn’t just mean public participation in making decisions. It presumes that all power and legitimacy is vested in one decision-making structure, and it requires a way to impose those decisions.  As long as anyone might defy them, there have to be armed personnel to <em>regulate</em>, to <em>discipline</em>, to <em>control</em>.

<p>Without police, there would be <em>anarchy</em>: people would act on their own initiative, only implementing decisions they felt to be in their best interest. Conflicts would have to be resolved to the mutual satisfaction of all parties involved, not suppressed by a gang with a monopoly on force.</p>

<a href="http://cloudfront.crimethinc.com/images/democracymeans/2b.jpg" rel="lightbox[dm]" class="legacyimage"><img src="http://cloudfront.crimethinc.com/images/democracymeans/2a.jpg" /></a><span class="invisible">-</span>
<strong><em>Democracy means borders.</strong></em> Democracy presumes a line between participants and outsiders, between legitimate and illegitimate. Only a fraction of the men could vote in ancient Athens; the Founding Fathers owned slaves. Citizenship still imposes a barrier between included and excluded, shutting over 10 million undocumented residents out of the decisions that shape their lives.

<p>The liberal answer is to expand the lines of inclusion, extending rights and privileges until everyone is integrated into one vast democratic project. But as long as all power must flow through one bottleneck, there are bound to be imbalances and outsiders. The alternative would be <em>anarchy</em>: abolishing centralized power structures and all the borders they impose. Without borders, people would only live and work together of their own free will, flowing freely between communities without top-down control.</p>

<a href="http://cloudfront.crimethinc.com/images/democracymeans/3b.jpg" rel="lightbox[dm]" class="legacyimage"><img src="http://cloudfront.crimethinc.com/images/democracymeans/3a.jpg" /></a><span class="invisible">-</span>
<strong><em>Democracy means prisons.</strong></em> Those who don’t accept the authority of the state must be isolated, lest their disobedience spread to the rest of the population. We’re told that prisons protect us, but the only constant since their invention has been that they protect the state from those who might threaten it. In practice, by breaking up communities and fostering antisocial tendencies, they only endanger us—even those of us who aren’t behind bars.

<p>Without prisons, there would be <em>anarchy</em>: people would have to work out conflicts directly rather than calling in the authorities, and it would no longer be possible to sweep the inequalities of this society under the rug.</p>

<a href="http://cloudfront.crimethinc.com/images/democracymeans/4b.jpg" rel="lightbox[dm]" class="legacyimage"><img src="http://cloudfront.crimethinc.com/images/democracymeans/4a.jpg" /></a><span class="invisible">-</span>
<strong><em>Democracy means surveillance.</strong></em> Democracy presumes transparency: a marketplace of ideas, in which decisions are made in the open. Of course, in an unequal society, transparency puts some people at risk—the employee who could be fired for expressing the wrong opinion, the immigrant who fears deportation—while the powerful can feign transparency as they make back-room deals. In practice, political transparency simply equips intelligence agencies to monitor the populace, preparing reprisals for when dissidents get out of hand—and what government could maintain its authority without intelligence agencies?

<p>Without surveillance, there would be <em>anarchy</em>: people would say and do what they really believe in. Those who defend centralized power fear nothing more than privacy—the keeping of secrets—which they call <em>conspiracy</em>.</p>

<a href="http://cloudfront.crimethinc.com/images/democracymeans/5b.jpg" rel="lightbox[dm]" class="legacyimage"><img src="http://cloudfront.crimethinc.com/images/democracymeans/5a.jpg" /></a><span class="invisible">-</span>
<strong><em>Democracy means war.</strong></em> Democracy means constant competition. Just as corporations contend for resources in the marketplace, politicians and governments vie for power. When power is centralized, people have to attain domination over others in order to determine their own destinies. Those in power can only hold onto it by waging war perpetually against their own populations as well as foreign peoples: hence the National Guard troops brought back from Iraq to suppress domestic protests.

<p>As long as we remain at a distance from our own potential, being governed rather than acting freely, being <em>represented</em> rather than acting on our own interests, people will seek power over each other as a substitute for self-determination. The alternative is <em>anarchy</em>: a world in which people fight only for themselves—not for empires, flags, or gods—and conflicts cannot produce hierarchy and oppression.</p>

<h2>We have to be tireless in our critique of democracy, as the alternative people in this society intuitively fall back on against the excesses of capitalism. The more unpopular this is, the more important it is that we do it. Private property and government are the two great sacred cows of our age—the ones for which our lives and the earth itself are being sacrificed—and challenging the ways they monopolize legitimacy is one project, not two. They are two heads of the same beast; they cannot be beaten separately.</h2>
<p>–<a href="http://www.crimethinc.com/texts/recentfeatures/nightmares.php">Nightmares of Capitalism, Pipe Dreams of Democracy</a></p>

<p>For more ammunition: <a href="http://www.crimethinc.com/vote">www.crimethinc.com/vote</a></p>]]></content_encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp_post_id>2312</wp_post_id>
		<wp_post_date><![CDATA[2012-04-29 17:02:38]]></wp_post_date>
		<wp_post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2012-04-30 00:02:38]]></wp_post_date_gmt>
		<wp_comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp_comment_status>
		<wp_ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp_ping_status>
		<wp_post_name><![CDATA[poster-series-what-does-democracy-mean]]></wp_post_name>
		<wp_status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp_status>
		<wp_post_parent>0</wp_post_parent>
		<wp_menu_order>0</wp_menu_order>
		<wp_post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp_post_type>
		<wp_post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp_post_password>
		<wp_is_sticky>0</wp_is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="calling-all-anarchists"><![CDATA[Calling All Anarchists]]></category>
		<wp_postmeta>
			<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp_meta_key>
			<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp_meta_value>
		</wp_postmeta>
		<wp_postmeta>
			<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[_thumbnail_id]]></wp_meta_key>
			<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[2509]]></wp_meta_value>
		</wp_postmeta>
		<wp_postmeta>
			<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[shorturl]]></wp_meta_key>
			<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[http://cwc.im/democracy]]></wp_meta_value>
		</wp_postmeta>
		<wp_postmeta>
			<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[jumbo]]></wp_meta_key>
			<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[http://cloudfront.crimethinc.com/images/democracymeans/6b.jpg]]></wp_meta_value>
		</wp_postmeta>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>1833</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[Prism: The Internet as New Enclosure | Earth First! Newswire]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url>http://earthfirstnews.wordpress.com/2013/06/10/prism-the-internet-as-new-enclosure/</wp_comment_author_url>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[72.232.113.44]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2013-06-10 14:44:23]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2013-06-10 21:44:23]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[[...] We told you so [...]]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[pingback]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
			<wp_commentmeta>
				<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[akismet_result]]></wp_meta_key>
				<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[false]]></wp_meta_value>
			</wp_commentmeta>
			<wp_commentmeta>
				<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[akismet_history]]></wp_meta_key>
				<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[a:4:{s:4:"time";d:1370900663.3275840282440185546875;s:7:"message";s:28:"Akismet cleared this comment";s:5:"event";s:9:"check-ham";s:4:"user";s:0:"";}]]></wp_meta_value>
			</wp_commentmeta>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>1832</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[Prism: The Internet as New Enclosure | Internationalist Prison Books Collective]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url>http://prisonbooks.info/2013/06/10/prism-the-internet-as-new-enclosure/</wp_comment_author_url>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[72.232.112.17]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2013-06-10 14:32:31]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2013-06-10 21:32:31]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[[...] We told you soOne of the foundational events in the transition to capitalism was the original enclosure of the commons, in which land that had once been used freely by all was seized and turned into private property. Indeed, this process has repeated again and again throughout the development of capitalism. [...]]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[pingback]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
			<wp_commentmeta>
				<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[akismet_result]]></wp_meta_key>
				<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[false]]></wp_meta_value>
			</wp_commentmeta>
			<wp_commentmeta>
				<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[akismet_history]]></wp_meta_key>
				<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[a:4:{s:4:"time";d:1370899951.877952098846435546875;s:7:"message";s:28:"Akismet cleared this comment";s:5:"event";s:9:"check-ham";s:4:"user";s:0:"";}]]></wp_meta_value>
			</wp_commentmeta>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>1627</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[b. traven]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[b@crimethinc.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url>http://www.crimethinc.com</wp_comment_author_url>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[24.130.83.85]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2012-05-02 23:16:17]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2012-05-03 06:16:17]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA["Because they still believe that the question of representation is the question that must be answered, many anti-representational strategies – the participatory democracy of the general assembly, for instance – remain trapped within politics in the same way that the atheist remains trapped within religion because he or she takes seriously the question of god’s existence."

from an article well worth reading: http://www.bayofrage.com/uncategorized/from-passive-to-active-spectacle-afterimages-of-the-la-riots/]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>2</wp_comment_user_id>
			<wp_commentmeta>
				<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[akismet_history]]></wp_meta_key>
				<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[a:4:{s:4:"time";s:13:"1336025777.82";s:7:"message";s:28:"Akismet cleared this comment";s:5:"event";s:9:"check-ham";s:4:"user";s:9:"b. traven";}]]></wp_meta_value>
			</wp_commentmeta>
			<wp_commentmeta>
				<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[akismet_result]]></wp_meta_key>
				<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[false]]></wp_meta_value>
			</wp_commentmeta>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>1628</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[everything4every1]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[hadda.b.playin@gmail.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url/>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[203.122.192.218]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2012-05-07 07:47:18]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2012-05-07 14:47:18]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA["Democracy means police. Democracy doesn’t just mean public participation in making decisions. It presumes that all power and legitimacy is vested in one decision-making structure, and it requires a way to impose those decisions.  As long as anyone might defy them, there have to be armed personnel to regulate, to discipline, to control."

Of all the democratic organisations I have participated in, not one has required armed personnel in any capacity. If you're only talking about capitalist governments which are democratic, the fact that they have armed personnel has is far more influenced by the fact that they are governments in a society which is based on inequality has more to do with than the fact that they contain some democratic decision making processes. Sure, I can see how democracy has downsides, but it seems most often the way Crimethinc has managed to buy extra traction for the anti-democracy position is by pretending like the US electoral system is the pinnacle of democracy. It's like pointing to sexual relationships in this society and making a series of posters saying 'sexual relationships require violence' 'sexual relationships require objectification' etc. because they happen to be things that are prevalent in regards to sexual relationships in this society.]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
			<wp_commentmeta>
				<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[akismet_result]]></wp_meta_key>
				<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[false]]></wp_meta_value>
			</wp_commentmeta>
			<wp_commentmeta>
				<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[akismet_history]]></wp_meta_key>
				<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[a:4:{s:4:"time";s:13:"1336402038.52";s:7:"message";s:28:"Akismet cleared this comment";s:5:"event";s:9:"check-ham";s:4:"user";s:17:"everything4every1";}]]></wp_meta_value>
			</wp_commentmeta>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>1629</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[b. traven]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[b@crimethinc.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url>http://www.crimethinc.com</wp_comment_author_url>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[71.23.109.102]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2012-05-08 14:58:39]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2012-05-08 21:58:39]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[Thanks for beginning a dialogue about this important subject. You're right, there are democratic organizations without armed personnel. In that regard, the poster is an exaggeration.

But let's look at this in greater depth. If democracy is a mode of governance--the dictionary definition begins by calling it "a system of government"--then it has to have a way to impose decisions. A democratic process without such a means is de facto anarchist, because there is no way to compel people to do things they don't want to do (for example, things they voted against in a system of majority rule).

WIthout armed personnel, informal or small-scale democratic organizations often attempt to impose these decisions via legitimizing and delegitimizing. The objection that "This wasn't agreed in the general assembly!" implies that action is only legitimate when it proceeds from the democratic process, from one structure that concentrates power (even if those within the structure are "equals" within it). Alternately, we can legitimize self-determination, holding all agreements and associations to be strictly voluntary, but that's not strictly the same as *governance* through democratic process.

There's some good insights about how this question comes up in practice here:

http://www.crimethinc.com/texts/recentfeatures/barc.php]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>2</wp_comment_user_id>
			<wp_commentmeta>
				<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[akismet_result]]></wp_meta_key>
				<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[false]]></wp_meta_value>
			</wp_commentmeta>
			<wp_commentmeta>
				<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[akismet_history]]></wp_meta_key>
				<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[a:4:{s:4:"time";s:13:"1336514319.63";s:7:"message";s:28:"Akismet cleared this comment";s:5:"event";s:9:"check-ham";s:4:"user";s:9:"b. traven";}]]></wp_meta_value>
			</wp_commentmeta>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>1766</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[While the Iron is Hot Part VIII | The Peak Guelph]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url>http://guelphpeak.org/vol52/2012/09/while-the-iron-is-hot-part-viii/</wp_comment_author_url>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[149.47.187.167]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2013-02-04 16:45:26]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2013-02-04 16:45:26]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[[...] democracy of general assemblies, the representative democracy of certain states, or something else, democratic ideals are inherently authoritarian and contrary to projects of liberation. This has been argued [...]]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[pingback]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>2063</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[While the Iron is Hot: anarchist analysis of the revolt in Quebec &raquo; Montréal Counter-information]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url>http://mtlcounter-info.org/while-the-iron-is-hot-anarchist-analysis-of-the-revolt-in-quebec/?lang=en</wp_comment_author_url>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[209.234.253.196]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2015-02-24 12:26:18]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2015-02-24 20:26:18]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[[&#8230;] democracy of general assemblies, the representative democracy of certain states, or something else, democratic ideals are inherently authoritarian and contrary to projects of liberation. This has been argued [&#8230;]]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[pingback]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
			<wp_commentmeta>
				<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[akismet_history]]></wp_meta_key>
				<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[a:4:{s:4:"time";d:1424809578.7758998870849609375;s:7:"message";s:28:"Akismet cleared this comment";s:5:"event";s:9:"check-ham";s:4:"user";s:0:"";}]]></wp_meta_value>
			</wp_commentmeta>
			<wp_commentmeta>
				<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[akismet_result]]></wp_meta_key>
				<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[false]]></wp_meta_value>
			</wp_commentmeta>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>2080</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[Demokratie heißt&#8230; Poster-Serie &laquo; crimethInc.]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url>http://crimethinc.blogsport.de/?p=83</wp_comment_author_url>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[188.40.80.244]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2015-06-04 03:16:54]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2015-06-04 10:16:54]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[[&#8230;] Wir stellen euch hier eine Reihe von Postern des CrimethInc. Kollektives zur freien Verfügung. Die Originale finden sich auf crimethinc.com [&#8230;]]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[pingback]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
			<wp_commentmeta>
				<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[akismet_history]]></wp_meta_key>
				<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[a:4:{s:4:"time";d:1433413014.7196700572967529296875;s:7:"message";s:28:"Akismet cleared this comment";s:5:"event";s:9:"check-ham";s:4:"user";s:0:"";}]]></wp_meta_value>
			</wp_commentmeta>
			<wp_commentmeta>
				<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[akismet_result]]></wp_meta_key>
				<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[false]]></wp_meta_value>
			</wp_commentmeta>
		</wp_comment>
	</item>