<item>
		<title>Review: War on Misery #s 1-2</title>
		<link>http://www.crimethinc.com/blog/2007/04/21/review-war-on-misery-s-1-2/</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 21 Apr 2007 22:38:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc_creator><![CDATA[peter p]]></dc_creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crimethinc.com/blog/2007/04/21/review-war-on-misery-s-1-2/</guid>
		<description/>
		<content_encoded><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.crimethinc.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2007/04/waronmisery_big.jpg" title="waronmisery_big.jpg" class="smallitem"><img src="http://www.crimethinc.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2007/04/waronmisery.jpg" alt="waronmisery.jpg" /></a>“Mindless violence is getting up each day and being complacent. Self-destructive behavior is worshipping routine for its security and praying to the market for happiness or adventure.”

After the presidential inauguration of 2005, nationwide mass mobilizations died down in the United States. Everyone from anarchists to liberals had rightly given up the idea that the Iraq war could be stopped by symbolic mass actions—smashing windows is no less symbolic than a candlelight vigil, unless you come back to smash them again the following week—and without the anti-globalization movement or the election circus to focus on, there wasn’t much left to mobilize people on a national scale besides the standard fare of ecological crises, labor struggles, disaster relief, and defendant support. Activists had to make good on all the rhetoric that had been thrown around about the shortcomings of summit-hopping by finally taking the time to focus on their local communities. In some areas, this has resulted in a lot of great community-based organizing—the recent proliferation of Really Really Free Markets brings to mind the spread of Food Not Bombs over a decade ago. While the relative quiet on the national scale gives the impression that anarchism is going through a minor recession, we won’t find out whether or not this is true until the next wave of mass actions—which we predict for 2008—shows what anarchists have been brewing in their communities.

<!--more-->

This emphasis on local activity isn’t limited to the organizers of social programs like the aforementioned ’Free Markets—it also extends to insurrectionists such as the publishers of this ’zine. Of course, they never call themselves “insurrectionists” here—we can only infer that perspective from their focus on autonomous acts of anonymous revolt against property and authority. The local emphasis comes through in that the ’zine focuses on activity of a wide range of cultural stripes in one small area, rather than activity of one cultural persuasion across a wide geographical area. The misery referenced in the title doubles as the state, Missouri, from which this publication hails; it is both an emotional space and a physical place—and, as the Dylan quote on the cover of the first issue proclaims, “there must be some kinda way outta here.”

The content is made up of reprints from police reports of vandalism, anti-corporate robbery, and similar criminal activity, supplemented by more thoroughly fleshed out stories of strikes and arsons. This format is an exciting innovation in that it offers an equation for a ’zine that basically writes itself: all the editors have to do is watch the police blotter, copy out everything they like, and add their own commentary. The second issue also includes reports of workplace accidents and a guide to obtaining food stamps as thorough as anything in <em>Recipes for Disaster</em>.

This format is interesting in the way it implies the editors’ political perspectives and sense of who their allies are without these ever having to be stated explicitly. This enables them to avoid subcultural jargon while still emphasizing radical solutions, and with any luck that will make this ’zine intelligible to a wider circle of readers than your average anarchist publication is.

Of course, finding common cause with others of unknown political commitments insofar as they take subversive action is always a tightrope act. On the one hand, it starts from something concrete that spans the superficial differences of language; on the other hand, it risks being unable to move from that starting place towards any more concrete forms of cooperation or solidarity. Your average would-be revolutionary editorial collective seeks to impose an action plan on others on the basis of assumed ideological similarities; this editorial collective instead risks projecting ideological similarities on others on the basis of their actions.

The Situationists used the Watts riots to argue that their ideas were “already in everyone’s heads”; that was a stretch at best, and at worst a way to claim the right to speak for those who could only speak on their own behalf through action. The leap of faith here is that by simply covering actions and literally re-presenting them to the communities that generated them, the editors hope not only to encourage more of them but also help to hone the strategy behind them.

Looking over these two issues, I don’t think they’re publishing this just for the radical cachet; it appears they sincerely aspire to promote insurrection. Given that, I can’t help but question whether this is the most effective format for the broad readership they presumably desire. Photocopied ’zines are common currency in some subcultural circles, but entirely invisible in others. I wonder if this would be more effective in certain communities as a pirate radio show, or set to music on spools of free CDRs outside gas stations.

All these concerns aside, <em>War on Misery</em> is an inspiring, entertaining read. At the very least, it can serve to keep self-identifying anti-authoritarians abreast of manifestations of unrest among the general public, the better to motivate and coordinate their own efforts. When one is trying to build up the morale to act, it always helps to know others are out there throwing down and often getting away with it.

The real payoff of focusing on local projects is that this can produce instantly reproducible models ready to be applied everywhere else. Inspired by <em>War on Misery</em>, we are, in fact, starting our own local publication to cover acts of social resistance in our own fair state. If every medium-sized town can have its own Really Really Free Market—a potential that is far from realized, but which is almost within reach and would do a lot for the anarchist movement—then every state could get its own War on. All that remains is to come up with forty-nine more puns for capitalist oppression.

Diction Quibble: At one point the editors use “fight-back” as a noun, the sort of mutilation of the language I associate with authoritarian socialists. Please, please don’t let this catch on. “Fight back” is much better as a verb, as something we <em>do</em>.

<sub>war_on_misery@hotmail.com</sub>]]></content_encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp_post_id>88</wp_post_id>
		<wp_post_date><![CDATA[2007-04-21 15:38:28]]></wp_post_date>
		<wp_post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2007-04-21 22:38:28]]></wp_post_date_gmt>
		<wp_comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp_comment_status>
		<wp_ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp_ping_status>
		<wp_post_name><![CDATA[review-war-on-misery-s-1-2]]></wp_post_name>
		<wp_status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp_status>
		<wp_post_parent>0</wp_post_parent>
		<wp_menu_order>0</wp_menu_order>
		<wp_post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp_post_type>
		<wp_post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp_post_password>
		<wp_is_sticky>0</wp_is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="read-all-about-it"><![CDATA[Read All About It]]></category>
		<wp_postmeta>
			<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp_meta_key>
			<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp_meta_value>
		</wp_postmeta>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>103</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[Sean Mayhem]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[seanmayhem@riseup.net]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url>http://</wp_comment_author_url>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[189.136.14.104]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2007-04-22 22:53:24]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2007-04-23 05:53:24]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[''While the relative quiet on the national scale gives the impression that anarchism is going through a minor recession, we won’t find out whether or not this is true until the next wave of mass actions—which we predict for 2008—shows what anarchists have been brewing in their communities.''

I apologize in advance for picking out a part of this review that doesn't really deal with the main thrust of it, because I'm not trying to get all worked up about something tangential, but I don't follow the logic in this excerpt. Why will the DNC and RNC demos serve as effective litmus tests for local anarchist organizing? Or maybe you're reference to 2008 is more cryptic than I imagine, and there's some other events that will take place in that year that will serve to display the successes or failures of community-based organizing. But assuming that you're talking about big summit-style protests, I don't quite see how successful or unsuccessful local organizing will or wll not be on display at said events.  In general, I don't see the Black Bloc turn-out at big demos as an effective way to gauge the successes of things like Really Really Free Markets, but maybe you have something else in mind. Do extrapolate.

I'm down with the idea of duplicating this format in many states and communities, and also your suggestions for alternate formats, of which I imagine there are even more possibilities (a wiki site for everyone working on a zine such as this would be a helpful source of links, for instance.) I also appreciate the jargon-free, non-dogmatic approach of this zine; it strikes me as a graceful practical application of the insurrectionary critique of ideology (and if ever a critique of ideology has suffered from too much ideology it is insurrectionism...actually it's primitivism, but nevermind.) I'd love to see a national or even international ''Greatest Hits'' version of this zine compiled from the many local versions that are no doubt in the offing. That'd be sweet.

''Looking over these two issues, I don’t think they’re publishing this just for the radical cachet; it appears they sincerely aspire to promote insurrection.'' Every project that does that is worth its weight in fucking gold. Hail to our disaffected comrades in Missouri!]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>104</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[xdx]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[don@crimethinc.net]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url>http://</wp_comment_author_url>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[75.90.170.180]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2007-04-23 11:31:55]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2007-04-23 18:31:55]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[Go here for a 'pdf file' of 'War On Misery #2':
http://www.stlimc.org/newswire/display/2833/index.php]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>105</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[jack burton]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[burningin5ide@yahoo.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url>http://</wp_comment_author_url>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[128.252.173.123]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2007-04-23 13:10:39]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2007-04-23 20:10:39]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA["Photocopied ’zines are common currency in some subcultural circles, but entirely invisible in others. I wonder if this would be more effective in certain communities as a pirate radio show, or set to music on spools of free CDRs outside gas stations."

This is true, however, I have noticed that the folks in St. Louis have their own newspaper stand boxes for their publication "War On Misery". Such as the ones that you might see local newspapers in, or 'apartment guides' that are usually standing around outisde of restaurants, coffee houses, music venue, or even high schools. And I can't tell if they actually bought their own or merely stole someone else's and used it for their publication.]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>106</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[xdx]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[don@crimethinc.net]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url>http://</wp_comment_author_url>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[71.28.197.206]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2007-04-24 17:33:49]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2007-04-25 00:33:49]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[A sort of similar local newsletter called 'The Bluegrass Insurgent' appeared in Lexington, KY: http://www.redanarchist.org/texts/autpub/bgi/bgi1.pdf

I think that War on Misery and the Bluegrass Insurgent make sense is that they weren't made for the hell of it.  They emerged from social conflict in both areas.  In the case of WoM, a strike that involved actions against scabs and then a string of arsons against development.  In the case of BGI, an escalation of attacks on police, particularly one really brazen attack.

I don't think it would make sense to make a local publication unless it was attached to something like that (even if you made it to talk about a rise of vandalism at your school, social struggle and tensions emerge in non-spectacular ways, not just fire and cop beatings), and I think with any publication there's a dangerous road towards evangelism.]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>107</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[goldynpapa]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[goldynpapa@gmail.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url/>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[75.142.19.75]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2007-05-13 21:07:13]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2007-05-14 04:07:13]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[hey! xdx thanx for the info.]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>108</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[the Raccoon Collective]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[raccooncollective@gmail.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url>http://www.raccooncollective.blogspot.com</wp_comment_author_url>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[192.211.25.9]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2007-05-15 19:37:34]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2007-05-16 02:37:34]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[I just wanted to metion that I feel this blog would be much more helpful to everyone if people besides "crimethinc operatives" or people with in the inner circle of crimethinc had the ability to post content.  Of course appropriate moderation would be necessary but just to have the ability would be nice.

-beware we never hibernate

the raccoons

www.raccooncollective.blogspot.com]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>109</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[pfm]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[pfm@crimethinc.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url>http://crimethinc.com/blog</wp_comment_author_url>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[75.164.165.111]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2007-05-15 21:18:12]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2007-05-16 04:18:12]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[Hey Raccoon. Well, it wouldn't really be "this blog" anymore if that were the case, would it? Anyone is free to make a internet forum or blog, or—anything—in the name of crimethinc. This blog has a very specific purpose (http://crimethinc.com/blog/about/) but we certainly agree that there are both opportunities and the need for high quality anarchist, moderated news and discussions sites. we've got our hands full though—it's up to you!]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>1</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>110</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[Sean Mayhem]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[seanmayhem@riseup.net]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url>http://</wp_comment_author_url>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[189.130.5.109]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2007-05-16 15:52:41]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2007-05-16 22:52:41]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[I think this blog would be more helpful if everyone were as diligent and thoughtful (and respectful) in responding to posts as b. traven. This blog really doesn't accomplish much if there isn't a discussion following the posts. I'm thinking here of the part of the 10 year anniversary self audit in which you folks astutely noted that you hadn't been too good about engaging with the responses crimethinc generates...]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>111</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[pfm]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[pfm@crimethinc.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url>http://crimethinc.com/blog</wp_comment_author_url>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[75.164.157.64]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2007-05-16 16:48:53]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2007-05-16 23:48:53]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[as your response follows mine, i think it might be that you are saying that my reply could have been more "diligent and thoughtful (and respectful)"? IF so, please help me see how that would be possible. I feel like the comments on this blog have made it one of the best comment sections around, so I'm not sure how we could improve it.]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>1</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>112</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[Sean Mayhem]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[seanmayhem@riseup.net]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url>http://</wp_comment_author_url>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[189.130.18.239]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2007-05-20 11:25:13]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2007-05-20 18:25:13]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[My comment was actually intended as a jab at the author of the original post, who has not responded to any of the comments. I think author responses are crucial, so I should have been more explicit: you should be careful that this blog does not operate as a one-way street , as it gives it an imperious air and further creates the impression of an aloof crimethinc elite willing to publish wordy tracts but not engage any of the peons that read them.

I basically agree with what you said, pfm, in response to the raccoon collective, although I think hard and fast rules are generally unhelpful, so if there are good contributions from people not in the ''crimethinc inner circle'' I think they should be posted. I understand your point though: instead of everyone getting on board with your project, they should be encouraged to start their own. But you can tell people to start their own projects without turning them off and making them feel unwelcome and inferior. This a challenge for all closed projects/collectives/affinity groups. How do you say, ''No, you can't join us, but you're free to start your own'' without sounding like a jerk? My answer is this: such situations are opportunities for mutual aid. Instead of just saying, ''No, you can't post here, go do your own thing,'' you could say, ''Can I help you get your own blog off the ground? I have lots of skills and resources and experience, and instead of hoarding them, I will use this opportunity to share them and make a connection with someone with whom I probably have some kind of an affinity, while simultaneously multiplying the number of well-designed anarchist projects in the world.'' I guess I just feel like turning people away completely in situations like that is a missed opportunity.]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>113</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[food not bombs]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[keith@foodnotbombs.net]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url>http://www.foodnotbombs.net</wp_comment_author_url>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[209.188.120.66]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2007-06-26 11:09:22]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2007-06-26 18:09:22]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[I think its possible that Food Not Bombs is growing more today than at any time in the past.  In the last year 40 groups have started in Russia and we now have chapters in China and Columbia.  There is also an interest in Iran and the groups in Africa are really growing.   It seems that over all de-centralized activity based actions are becoming more popular and reaching more people.  I have read a number of places that authors will claim that Food Not Bombs "peaked"in the 1990's or as this article indicates that free store are growing like Food Not Bombs was in the past. Thanks everyone.]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
	</item>