<item>
		<title>Letter to the Egyptian Black Bloc</title>
		<link>http://www.crimethinc.com/blog/2013/02/09/letter-to-the-egyptian-black-bloc/</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2013 18:50:56 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc_creator><![CDATA[pfm]]></dc_creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.crimethinc.com/blog/?p=3776</guid>
		<description/>
		<content_encoded><![CDATA[<p>We present here, in Arabic and in English, an open letter from participants in <a href="http://www.crimethinc.com/texts/pastfeatures/blocs.php">black bloc</a> actions in the United States to participants in <a href="http://www.aljazeera.com/indepth/opinion/2013/02/201322103219816676.html">the Egyptian black bloc</a>, aimed at initiating a dialogue beyond the exchange of youtube videos. This is of interest to everyone around the world struggling for liberation, so please print and distribute widely:</p>

<p><span class="smallimg"><a href="http://www.crimethinc.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/egyptdownloadb.jpg" rel="lightbox"><img src="http://www.crimethinc.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/egyptdownloada.jpg"></a></span>
&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; <strong><a href="http://cloudfront.crimethinc.com/pdfs/egyptblackbloc_english_imposed.pdf">Printable PDF in English [3.5 MB]</a></strong> &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; <strong><a href="http://cloudfront.crimethinc.com/pdfs/egyptblackbloc_arabic_imposed.pdf">Printable PDF in Arabic [3.7 MB]</a></strong></p>

<p>The emergence of the black bloc in Egypt at this time should not surprise us as much as it surprises pacifists and authoritarians. The struggles of the 21st century will not be limited to nonviolent civil disobedience, nor to reformism; they are bound to involve open conflict with the state. Moreover, they will be increasingly international in scope and character. Whenever anyone anywhere around the world stands up for herself or himself—however awkwardly, however humbly—it sets a precedent for the next generation of resistance. Let’s rise to the occasion.</p>

<!--more Full text of letter in English and Arabic after the jump, along with an Egyptian black bloc anthem subtitled in English.-->

<iframe width="485" height="364" src="http://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/TX51X7A3bUQ?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>

<p><em>“Black Anger” by MC Sayed appeared on the two-year anniversary of <a href="http://www.crimethinc.com/blog/2011/02/02/egypt-today-tomorrow-the-world/">the Egyptian uprising</a>. These clumsy subtitles are part of our effort to facilitate intercontinental communication.</em></p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>

<h3>The criticisms of the black bloc in Egypt are all too familiar. Those who have more privilege and power than you accuse you of being spoiled rich kids. Those who are not willing to run the same risks accuse you of cowardice. Those who have different goals than you complain that you are <em>not strategic.</em> Those for whom democracy means the amplification of their own voices insist that you should submit to majority rule in order to silence you. Those who depend on foreign military aid, who bow to foreign political pressure in selling out the people of Egypt, accuse you of importing foreign tactics. You are blamed for the violence of the police, when the police are always precisely as violent as they have to be to maintain their supremacy, and their ongoing violence is only <em>visible</em> because you resist it. Above all, authorities of all kinds do everything they can to isolate you from others who might resist.</h3>

<p>&nbsp;</p>

<h2>To the Egyptian Black Bloc</h2>

<p><em>from “black bloc anarchists” in the US</em></p>

<p><strong><em>You strike the note—it sounds in us.</em></strong></p>

<p>It is an honor to address you on account of your courage in the struggle still unfolding in Egypt.</p>

<p>For a decade and a half, we have participated in black bloc actions in the US and elsewhere around the world. Of course, we do not represent anyone or anything; the black bloc is a tactic, not a group—that is what makes it so frightening to our rulers. But on the basis of our experience with this tactic, we would like to share some of our perspectives in hopes of establishing a more explicit intercontinental dialogue.</p>

<p>We have already been in a kind of dialogue with you, exchanging signals of revolt across the ocean. We’ve circulated reports of your struggle here, and now we are seeing photos and videos of our actions appear in <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fR_ZRGN0Cq0">youtube</a> collages from Egypt. But we want more dialogue than youtube collages allow. We want to be able to discuss strategy as well as tactics, and goals as well as strategy.</p>

<p>First and foremost: you are not alone. You are part of a struggle against oppressive power that is taking place all over the world. The same economy that is plundering Egypt wrecks our lives and land here in the US; the same networks of armed force that tear-gas you in Cairo maintain “order” in New York City. If we are to win anything in this struggle, we can only do so internationally.</p>

<p>It is embarrassing that it took us so long to address you <a href="#arabic">in Arabic</a>—that shows how unprepared we are for the opportunities history is offering. But that may change quickly in the coming years. It will have to.</p>

<p>We have gained our experience with black bloc tactics under what you might call adverse conditions—as a small minority acting against a stable power structure, without much support from the rest of society. The black bloc evolved in that context, and it is interesting to see it appear in a situation of more generalized revolt.</p>

<p>Indeed, the longevity of the black bloc surprises everyone; over and over it has been pronounced dead, yet it keeps coming back. This is because, like Anonymous, it expresses the <a href="http://www.crimethinc.com/blog/2012/02/20/black-bloc-confidential/">spirit of our times</a>. In an era when tremendous disparities are maintained by surveillance and policing, any meaningful movement is bound to involve anonymity and clashes with the authorities.</p>

<p>The black bloc is important because it gives that anonymity and antagonism a political content: it ties specific struggles against oppression to the possibility of a generalized struggle against all oppressive power. It is a coup to “brand” anonymous collective confrontation with the authorities as <em>anarchist</em>—this means that everyone who stands up for himself against the authorities must ask, sooner or later, what his relationship to others’ struggles is.</p>

<p>It is fitting that the black bloc emerged in Egypt on the two-year anniversary of an uprising that only replaced one tyranny with another. The problems caused by capitalism and government cannot be solved by a mere change of regimes. It will take a struggle from the ground up—the emergence of social formations that can <em>defend themselves</em> against government and capitalism. This is not a matter of addressing demands to those in power, and it is not something that can be won simply by attacking presidential palaces. It requires us to oppose the structures of domination everywhere they appear, shifting our strategy from mere <em>protest</em> to the assertion of another way of life.</p>

<p>The criticisms of the black bloc in Egypt are all too familiar to us—we have watched reactionaries read from this same script since 1999. You are blamed for the violence of the police, when the police are always precisely as violent as they have to be to maintain their supremacy, and their ongoing violence is only <em>visible</em> because you resist it. Those who have more privilege and power than you accuse you of being spoiled rich kids. Those who are not willing to run the same risks accuse you of cowardice. Those who have different goals than you complain that you are <em>not strategic.</em> Those for whom democracy means the amplification of their own voices insist that you should submit to majority rule in order to silence you. Those who depend on foreign military aid, who bow to foreign political pressure in selling out the people of Egypt, accuse you of importing foreign tactics. Above all, authorities of all kinds do everything they can to isolate you from others who might resist.</p>

<p>Indeed, in our experience, this is the greatest risk in using the black bloc tactic: in giving an <em>identity</em> to anonymity and struggle, it offers the authorities an opportunity to <a href="http://www.crimethinc.com/texts/recentfeatures/violence.php">make an “other”</a> out of us, to quarantine our revolt and our ideas. It is a mistake to view ourselves as separate from the rest of society. The black bloc is powerful and dangerous only so long as it remains a space of revolt that anyone can flow into—the tip of the iceberg of something much broader. Our rulers do not fear anarchists—they fear that anarchist values and practices will spread.</p>

<p>It is important not to impose a dichotomy between being honest about our goals and participating in movements larger than us. On one hand, we must be clear that we reject all forms of domination; if we do not, everyone will have to learn again and again how little police and the poverty they impose change from one government to the next. This is why we should not hide our values under the same vague banner of <a href="http://www.crimethinc.com/tools/vote/">“democracy”</a> that disguises others’ hunger for power: doing so only legitimizes the structures that will be used against us later. But at the same time, we have to maintain the openness that enables tactics and ideas to circulate. Anarchism is not an identity, it has no meaning in isolation; it is a relationship that must spread.</p>

<p>In the United States, anarchists have erred on both sides of this dichotomy. Often, we have served as shock troops and free labor for liberal causes, taking great risks to advance their agendas while failing to act on our own analysis. We hoped this would connect us to the rest of society, but connections that depend on us hiding our values are meaningless.</p>

<p>Other times, anarchists have acted as though we could accomplish our goals on our own, winding up in a private grudge match with the state that everyone else assumed had nothing to do with them. Certainly, we can’t wait for mass consensus to begin our project of revolt; we can only find others in revolt by rising up ourselves—but the point is <em>to find others.</em> Over and over, we've thought our own dreams too wild to propose, only to see other people enacting them spontaneously. In fact, the time is ripe for us to advance our proposals: capitalism is in crisis around the world, and soon billions will have to choose between totalitarianism and the kind of freedom no government can provide.</p>

<p>If it is true that the state cannot solve our problems, all who wish to wield its authority will discredit themselves once they assume power. The sooner all the Muslim Brotherhoods of the world associate themselves with the state the better: this will clarify things for those who do not yet understand why anyone would be an anarchist. When the opposition parties join the rulers in telling everyone to get out of the street and the streets remain full, this suggests that people are catching on. In this situation, anarchists could help turn regime change into social revolution, a full-scale transformation of everyday life.</p>

<p>The US government needs Egypt to have a government with whom to coordinate the resource extraction necessary for global capitalism. The black bloc scares them because it is not legible in their conception of politics—it offers no one to negotiate with. They want to bring all the political parties into “dialogue” in order to map everything in their structures of power; we want to take the struggle out of the hands of political parties entirely, establishing dialogue among people rather than with parties or governments. We seek to spread struggles in which we communicate with and inspire others directly, as you have inspired us.</p>

<p>We will continue this dialogue in the most meaningful way we can—by continuing to challenge the power structures here in the United States, which underpin those in Egypt and elsewhere around the world. But if any of you can send us reports from your struggles, or translate materials between English and Arabic, we would be glad to hear from you. May we meet in the streets of a stateless world.</p>

<p>rollingthunder @ crimethinc.com</p>

<p><strong>Further Reading</strong></p>

<p><a href="http://riselikelions.net/pamphlets/14/10-points-on-the-black-bloc">10 Points on the Black Bloc</a> [<a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=I6MxpsdXfrE">Video</a>]
<a href="http://www.crimethinc.com/texts/pastfeatures/blocs.php">Introduction to the Black Bloc</a>
<a href="http://www.crimethinc.com/blog/2008/10/11/fashion-tips-for-the-brave/">Black Bloc Safety and Fashion Guide</a>
<a href="http://www.crimethinc.com/blog/2012/09/17/post-debate-debrief-video-and-libretto/">Debate about Black Bloc Tactics</a></p>

<p><a class="overhang" id="arabic" name="arabic"><img src="http://www.crimethinc.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/egyptletter2a.jpg" alt="" title="cathydownload2-a" width="630" height="420" /></a></p>

<div style="font-size: 175%; line-height: 30px !important; direction: rtl; text-align: right !important">
<h2>من "الأناركيين البلاك بلوك" في الولايات المتحدة</h2>
<h3>تدقون النغمة – فيتردد صداها فينا</h3></div>

<div style="font-size: 175%; line-height: 30px !important; direction: rtl; text-align: right !important">إنه لشرف لنا أن نخاطبكم نظرا لشجاعتكم في النضال الذي مازال مفتوحا في مصر.
لقد شاركنا لمدة عِقد ونصف في أعمال البلاك بلوك في الولايات المتحدة وفي غيرها من البلدان حول العالم. بالطبع نحن لا نمثل أحدا ما أو جهة ما؛ فالبلاك بلوك طريقة وليست جماعة – وهذا ما يجعلها مخيفة جدا لحكامنا. لكن بناء على خبرتنا مع هذه الطريقة، نود أن نشارككم بعضا من وجهات نظرنا على أمل تأسيس حوار أكثر وضوحا ما بين القارات.
لقد كنا بالفعل في نوع من الحوار معكم؛ متبادلين إشارات الثورة عبر المحيط. لقد وزعنا تقارير عن نضالكم هنا، والآن نرى صورا وفيديوهات لأعمالنا تظهر في مقاطع على اليوتيوب من مصر. لكننا نريد حوارا أكثر مما تسمح به مقاطع اليوتيوب. إننا نريد أن نتمكن من مناقشة الاستراتيجية بنفس القدر الذي نريد أن نناقش به التكتيكات، وأن نناقش الأهداف بنفس القدر الذي نناقش به الاستراتيجية.
أولا وأخيرا : أنتم لستم وحدكم. أنتم جزء من نضال ضد القوى القمعية يحدث في كل أنحاء العالم. فالاقتصاد الذي ينهب مصر يدمر حياتنا وأرضنا هنا في الولايات المتحدة، ونفس شبكات القوات المسلحة التي تلقي عليكم بقنابل الغاز المسيل للدموع في القاهرة هي التي تحفظ "النظام" في مدينة نيويورك. إذا كان لنا أن نفوز بأي شيء في هذا النضال، فلن يمكننا أن نفعل ذلك إلا دوليا.
إنه لشيء مخجل أن استغرقنا كل هذا الوقت الطويل لمخاطبتكم بالعربية؛ وهو الأمر الذي يكشف كم أننا غير مستعدين للفرص التي يقدمها لنا التاريخ. لكن من المحتمل أن يتغير هذا بسرعة في السنوات القادمة. لابد وأن يحدث هذا.
لقد اكتسبنا خبرتنا بتكتيكات البلاك بلوك تحت ما يمكن أن تسموه بالظروف المعاكسة؛ باعتبارنا أقلية صغيرة تعمل ضد بنية قوة مستقرة، ودون دعم كبير من بقية المجتمع. تطورت البلاك بلوك في هذا السياق، ومن المثير رؤيتها تظهر في موقف ثوري أكثر عمومية.
بالفعل يدهش طول عمر البلاك بلوك الجميع؛ فمرة بعد أخرى يتم الإعلان عن وفاتها، لكنها تستمر في العودة من جديد. ذلك لأنها – مثل مجموعة أنونيموس (المجهولون : وهم مجموعة مستقلة عبر الإنترنت تناضل عبر الاختراق البرامجي) – تعبر عن روح زماننا. في عصر يتم الحفاظ فيه على الفوارق الهائلة عن طريق المراقبة والشرطة، تكون أي حركة لها معنى مضطرة إلى التزام إخفاء الهوية والصدامات مع السلطات.
البلاك بلوك مهمة لأنها تعطي لهذه المجهولية والعداء محتوى سياسيا : فهي تربط نضالات معينة ضد القمع بإمكانية نضال عام ضد كل القوى القمعية. إنها ضربة موفقة أن "نَسِمَ" المواجهة الجماعية مجهولة الأسماء مع السلطات بالأناركية – فهذا يعني أن كل من يقف لمصلحة ذاته ضد السلطات يجب أن يتساءل – عاجلا أو آجلا – ما هي علاقته بنضالات الآخرين.
إنه من المناسب أن ظهرت حركة البلاك بلوك في مصر في الذكرى الثانية لثورة استبدلت فقط حكما استبداديا بآخر. إن المشكلات التي سببتها الرأسمالية والحكومة لا يمكن أن يحلها مجرد تغيير للأنظمة. سيتطلب الأمر نضالا من أسفل إلى أعلى – بظهور تشكيلات اجتماعية يمكنها الدفاع عن نفسها ضد الحكومة والرأسمالية. الأمر ليس له علاقة بتوجيه طلبات لمن هم في السلطة، ولا هو شيء يمكن الفوز به ببساطة عن طريق مهاجمة القصور الرئاسية. يتطلب الأمر منا مقاومة كل كيانات الهيمنة في كل مكان تظهر فيه، وتغيير استراتيجيتنا من مجرد احتجاج إلى تأكيد شكل آخر للحياة.
إن الانتقادات التي توجه إلى البلاك بلوك في مصر مألوفة بشكل زائد عن اللزوم لنا – لقد شاهدنا رجعيين يقرؤون من نفس السيناريو منذ عام 1999. أنتم تُلامون على عنف الشرطة، في الوقت الذي يكون فيه رجال الشرطة عنيفين كما يجب أن يكونوا  بالضبط ليحافظوا على تفوقهم، وعنفهم المستمر يظهر للعيان فقط لأنكم تقاومونه. هؤلاء الذين يملكون امتيازات وقوة أكثر منكم يتهمونكم بأنكم عيال أثرياء مدللون. هؤلاء الذين هم غير راغبين في التعرض لنفس المخاطرات يتهمونكم بالجبن. هؤلاء الذين لديهم أهداف مختلفة عنكم يشتكون من أنكم غير استراتيجيين. هؤلاء الذين تعني الديمقراطية لهم تضخيم أصواتهم يصرون على أنكم يجب أن تخضعوا لحكم الأغلبية لكي يسكتوكم. هؤلاء الذين يعتمدون على المساعدات العسكرية الأجنبية، والذين ينحنون أمام الضغوط السياسية الأجنبية لبيع شعب مصر، يتهمونكم باستيراد تكتيكات أجنبية. قبل كل شيء، تفعل السلطات من كل نوع كل ما يمكنها فعله لعزلكم عن الآخرين الذين من المحتمل أن يشتركوا في المقاومة.
في الحقيقة ومن خلال خبرتنا، تلك هي المخاطرة الأكبر في استخدام تكتيك البلاك بلوك : أي في إعطاء هوية للمجهولية والنضال، فهذا يقدم للسلطات فرصة أن يجعلوا منا "آخر"، أن يحجروا على ثورتنا وأفكارنا. إنه لمن الخطأ أن نرى أنفسنا كجزء منفصل عن بقية المجتمع. تظل البلاك بلوك قوية وخطيرة طالما ظلت مساحة للثورة يمكن لأي شخص أن يدخل في غمارها – قمة جبل الجليد لشيء أكثر اتساعا بكثير. إن حكامنا لا يخافون الأناركيين – إنهم يخافون من أن تنتشر القيم والممارسات الأناركية.
من المهم ألا نفرض انقساما بين كوننا صادقين مع أهدافنا وبين المشاركة في حركات أكبر منا. من ناحية يجب أن نكون واضحين بشأن رفضنا لكل أشكال الهيمنة، إذا لم نفعل ذلك سيضطر الجميع لأن يتعلموا مرة بعد أخرى كيف أن الشرطة والفقر الذي تفرضه نادرا ما يتغيران من حكومة إلى الحكومة التي تليها. هذا هو السبب في أننا لا ينبغي أن نخفي قيمنا تحت نفس لافتة "الديمقراطية" المبهمة التي يتنكر وراءها جوع الآخرين للسلطة؛ فلن يؤدي هذا إلا إلى إضفاء الشرعية على الهياكل التي ستُستخدم ضدنا فيما بعد. لكن في نفس الوقت يجب أن نحافظ على الانفتاح الذي سيمكِّن تكتيكاتنا وأفكارنا من أن تنتشر. الأناركية ليست هوية، وليس لها معنى في حالة العزلة، إنها علاقة يجب أن تنتشر.
لقد أخطأ الأناركيون في الولايات المتحدة على كلا الناحيتين لهذا الانقسام. لقد عملنا كثيرا كقوات صدامية وعمال مجانيين للقضايا الليبرالية، وخضنا مخاطر هائلة للدفع بأجنداتهم قدما مع فشلنا في العمل وفقا لتحليلاتنا الخاصة. كنا نأمل أن يؤدي هذا إلى ربطنا ببقية المجتمع، لكن الروابط التي تعتمد على كوننا نخفي قيمنا هي روابط بلا معنى.
في أوقات أخرى عمل الأناركيون كما لو كان بإمكاننا أن نحقق أهدافنا بالاعتماد على أنفسنا فقط، وانتهى الأمر بنا إلى مباراة خاصة في الضغينة مع الدولة رأى كل من هم خارجها أن لا شأن لهم بها. بالتأكيد لا يمكننا انتظار الإجماع الجماهيري حتى نبدأ مشروع ثورتنا، فلا يمكننا أن نجد آخرين في الثورة معنا إلا بأن نثور بأنفسنا – لكن المهم هو أن نجد آخرين. لقد اعتقدنا مرارا وتكرارا أن أحلامنا أكثر جرأة من أن نعرضها، فقط لنرى أناسا آخرين يفعلونها بشكل عفوي. في الحقيقة لقد حان الوقت لنا كي نقدم مقترحاتنا : إن الرأسمالية في أزمة في كل أنحاء العالم، وقريبا سيضطر المليارات من البشر للاختيار ما بين الشمولية وما بين ذلك النوع من الحرية الذي لا تستطيع أي حكومة أن تقدمه.
إذا كان صحيحا أن الدولة لا تستطيع أن تحل مشاكلنا، فإن كل من يتمنون ممارسة سلطتها سيفقدون مصداقيتهم بمجرد أن يتولوا هذه السلطة. كلما أسرع جميع الإخوان المسلمين في العالم نحو ربط أنفسهم بالدولة كلما كان ذلك أفضل : سيوضح هذا الأمور لهؤلاء الذين لم يفهموا بعد لماذا يصبح المرء أناركيا. عندما تنضم أحزاب المعارضة إلى الحكام في دعوة الجميع لمغادرة الشارع وتظل الشوارع مملوءة فهذا يشير إلى أن الناس بدأوا يدركون الفكرة. في هذا الموقف يمكن للأناركيين أن يسهموا في تحويل تغير النظام إلى ثورة اجتماعية، إلى تحول كامل في الحياة اليومية.
تحتاج حكومة الولايات المتحدة إلى أن تكون لدى مصر حكومة تنسق معها استخراج الموارد الضرورية للرأسمالية العالمية. وتخيفهم البلاك بلوك لأنها ليست واضحة في مفهومهم عن السياسة – فهي لا تقدم أحدا يمكن التفاوض معه. إنهم يريدون أن يجمعوا كل الأحزاب السياسية في "حوار" لكي يرسموا خريطة تفصيلية لكل شيء في هياكل سطوتهم؛ إننا نريد أن ننتزع النضال من أيدي الأحزاب السياسية بشكل كامل، مؤسسين لحوار بين الناس بدلا من الحوار مع الأحزاب أو الحكومات. نحن نسعى لنشر نضالات نتواصل فيها مع الآخرين ونلهمهم بشكل مباشر، مثلما ألهمتمونا أنتم.
سنتابع هذا الحوار بأكثر طريقة لها معنى يمكننا إياها؛ وذلك بالاستمرار في تحدي هياكل القوة هنا في الولايات المتحدة، والتي تدعم مثيلتها في مصر وفي أماكن أخرى حول العالم. لكن إذا كان يمكن لأي أحد منكم أن يرسل إلينا تقارير من نضالاتكم، أو يترجم موادا بين الإنجليزية والعربية، فسيسعدنا أن نتواصل معكم. على أمل بأن نلتقي في شوارع عالم بلا دولة.

نسخة من هذا المقال جاهزة للطباعة على هذا الرابط pdf
www.crimethinc.com/lettertoegypt</div>

<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content_encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp_post_id>3776</wp_post_id>
		<wp_post_date><![CDATA[2013-02-09 18:50:56]]></wp_post_date>
		<wp_post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2013-02-09 18:50:56]]></wp_post_date_gmt>
		<wp_comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp_comment_status>
		<wp_ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp_ping_status>
		<wp_post_name><![CDATA[letter-to-the-egyptian-black-bloc]]></wp_post_name>
		<wp_status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp_status>
		<wp_post_parent>0</wp_post_parent>
		<wp_menu_order>0</wp_menu_order>
		<wp_post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp_post_type>
		<wp_post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp_post_password>
		<wp_is_sticky>0</wp_is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="read-all-about-it"><![CDATA[Read All About It]]></category>
		<wp_postmeta>
			<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp_meta_key>
			<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp_meta_value>
		</wp_postmeta>
		<wp_postmeta>
			<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[_cws_is_markdown]]></wp_meta_key>
			<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp_meta_value>
		</wp_postmeta>
		<wp_postmeta>
			<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[_thumbnail_id]]></wp_meta_key>
			<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[3821]]></wp_meta_value>
		</wp_postmeta>
		<wp_postmeta>
			<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[jumbo]]></wp_meta_key>
			<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[http://www.crimethinc.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/egyptletter1b.jpg]]></wp_meta_value>
		</wp_postmeta>
		<wp_postmeta>
			<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[shorturl]]></wp_meta_key>
			<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[http://cwc.im/lettertoegypt]]></wp_meta_value>
		</wp_postmeta>
		<wp_postmeta>
			<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[_sd_is_markdown]]></wp_meta_key>
			<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp_meta_value>
		</wp_postmeta>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>1769</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[b. traven]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[b@crimethinc.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url/>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[76.182.94.214]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2013-02-20 10:11:12]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2013-02-20 18:11:12]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[Dutch translation: https://www.indymedia.nl/node/13191]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>2</wp_comment_user_id>
			<wp_commentmeta>
				<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[akismet_result]]></wp_meta_key>
				<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[false]]></wp_meta_value>
			</wp_commentmeta>
			<wp_commentmeta>
				<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[akismet_history]]></wp_meta_key>
				<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[a:4:{s:4:"time";d:1361383872.410255908966064453125;s:7:"message";s:28:"Akismet cleared this comment";s:5:"event";s:9:"check-ham";s:4:"user";s:9:"b. traven";}]]></wp_meta_value>
			</wp_commentmeta>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>1822</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[freethinkingaway]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[freethinkingaway@gmail.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url/>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[76.126.65.131]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2013-05-19 10:09:11]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2013-05-19 17:09:11]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[A Letter to North American Anarchists from Radical Beirut:

http://www.ainfos.ca/ainfos336/ainfos55047.html]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>132</wp_comment_user_id>
			<wp_commentmeta>
				<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[akismet_result]]></wp_meta_key>
				<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[false]]></wp_meta_value>
			</wp_commentmeta>
			<wp_commentmeta>
				<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[akismet_history]]></wp_meta_key>
				<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[a:4:{s:4:"time";d:1368983351.789081096649169921875;s:7:"message";s:28:"Akismet cleared this comment";s:5:"event";s:9:"check-ham";s:4:"user";s:16:"freethinkingaway";}]]></wp_meta_value>
			</wp_commentmeta>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>1770</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[Blackbloctunisia]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[spawnlegend@hotmail.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url/>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[197.6.91.226]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2013-02-27 08:26:58]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2013-02-27 16:26:58]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[How can we contact you i m from black bloc tunisia and we need to talke]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>91</wp_comment_user_id>
			<wp_commentmeta>
				<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[akismet_result]]></wp_meta_key>
				<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[false]]></wp_meta_value>
			</wp_commentmeta>
			<wp_commentmeta>
				<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[akismet_history]]></wp_meta_key>
				<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[a:4:{s:4:"time";d:1361982419.0807650089263916015625;s:7:"message";s:28:"Akismet cleared this comment";s:5:"event";s:9:"check-ham";s:4:"user";s:16:"Blackbloctunisia";}]]></wp_meta_value>
			</wp_commentmeta>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>1815</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[Zzzz]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[ihuntyoubuy@gmail.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url/>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[67.188.254.230]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2013-05-03 20:04:56]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2013-05-04 03:04:56]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[The Egyptian government start cracking down on Black bloc Egypt, the other day 12 members were arrested, their destiny is unknown to anyone]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>120</wp_comment_user_id>
			<wp_commentmeta>
				<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[akismet_result]]></wp_meta_key>
				<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[false]]></wp_meta_value>
			</wp_commentmeta>
			<wp_commentmeta>
				<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[akismet_history]]></wp_meta_key>
				<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[a:4:{s:4:"time";d:1367636696.3281629085540771484375;s:7:"message";s:28:"Akismet cleared this comment";s:5:"event";s:9:"check-ham";s:4:"user";s:4:"zzzz";}]]></wp_meta_value>
			</wp_commentmeta>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>1778</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[b. traven]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[b@crimethinc.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url/>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[24.130.83.85]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2013-03-17 10:00:20]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2013-03-17 17:00:20]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[German translation:

https://linksunten.indymedia.org/de/node/81387]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>2</wp_comment_user_id>
			<wp_commentmeta>
				<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[akismet_result]]></wp_meta_key>
				<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[false]]></wp_meta_value>
			</wp_commentmeta>
			<wp_commentmeta>
				<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[akismet_history]]></wp_meta_key>
				<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[a:4:{s:4:"time";d:1363539620.14671802520751953125;s:7:"message";s:28:"Akismet cleared this comment";s:5:"event";s:9:"check-ham";s:4:"user";s:9:"b. traven";}]]></wp_meta_value>
			</wp_commentmeta>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>1768</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[b. traven]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[b@crimethinc.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url/>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[76.182.94.214]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2013-02-11 18:53:41]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2013-02-11 18:53:41]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[Translation into Greek:
http://ferae-naturae-xvx.blogspot.gr/2013/02/blog-post_11.html]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>2</wp_comment_user_id>
			<wp_commentmeta>
				<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[akismet_result]]></wp_meta_key>
				<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[false]]></wp_meta_value>
			</wp_commentmeta>
			<wp_commentmeta>
				<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[akismet_history]]></wp_meta_key>
				<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[a:4:{s:4:"time";s:13:"1360608822.31";s:7:"message";s:28:"Akismet cleared this comment";s:5:"event";s:9:"check-ham";s:4:"user";s:9:"b. traven";}]]></wp_meta_value>
			</wp_commentmeta>
		</wp_comment>
	</item>