<item>
		<title>Convergence Coverage Appetizer</title>
		<link>http://www.crimethinc.com/blog/2007/07/30/convergence-coverage-appetizer/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2007 18:38:47 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc_creator><![CDATA[pfm]]></dc_creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crimethinc.com/blog/2007/07/30/convergence-coverage-appetizer/</guid>
		<description/>
		<content_encoded><![CDATA[In the next week, we'll have our own recollections and coverage from the just completed 2007 CrimethInc. Convergence. For now, <a href="http://www.athensnews.com/issue/article.php3?story_id=28894" target="_blank">here is a report from the Athens News</a>:
<blockquote> An un-permitted parade of more than 150 costumed anarchists and their supporters filled North Court Street Saturday night. They barricaded the West State Street intersection and danced, chanted, climbed light poles, banged on objects and fire danced before police dispersed the crowd, using squad cars and pepper spray.

"We're just having fun," one marcher told a bystander who asked what they were protesting.</blockquote>
<!--more-->
<blockquote>The parade participants were in Athens for the 2007 CrimethInc. Convergence. CrimethInc. is an international underground network made up of anarchists and other radicals.

After the crowd scattered, Athens Police made one arrest for disorderly conduct by intoxication, one for riot, and three for obstructing official business, according to a report released by Police Lt. Randy Gray. The identities of the individuals have not been released.

Gray reported that the Athens Police responded to a call made at 9:42 p.m. and arrived at the intersection to find a large group of people with flaming objects, stones, bricks and improvised drums blocking the street with road signs dragged from a construction site.

The flaming objects, known as "poi," are professionally made chunks of burning rubber on chains used by fire dancers and circus performers for entertainment purposes. To extinguish the flame, poi artists turn from the audience and spin the burning chunks less rapidly while lowering them to the ground, according to one performer who attended the event.

According to the police report, Lt. Gray told one of the performers to extinguish the "burning objects." The female said OK and turned away while continuing to twirl the poi. Gray tried to detain the person while another individual struck him in the back and grabbed his arm. Gray then used pepper spray to fend off other individuals who were converging on him, and further spray was used to disperse "what had become a violent and destructive crowd."

The marchers claimed that the "parade" was intended to be peaceful fun, and police were unnecessarily violent in their reaction. Several people were pepper sprayed in the face from behind as they dispersed eastward, and one anonymous marcher claimed the mace almost hit an infant riding on a woman's shoulder.

"I was standing by the BP talking to three people when Car 902 almost ran into us," said Benjamin Ayer of Michigan. Ayer was documenting the incident from the sidewalk with his camera.

"It swiftly turned into the driveway without warning. Two people fell on me, they were just passersby, they were just asking me what was going on and almost got hit. After that I breathed in pepper gas," said Ayer, who charged that police "gravely overreacted."

After dispersing, many of the marchers gathered at The Wire Community Resource Center on Kern Street, which was promptly put under police surveillance. A local spokesperson for The Wire told police that the center was not involved in the event but was open for a music event and does not turn down people at its doors. (CrimethInc., however, did use The Wire's "free space" as a redirect spot for out-of-towners looking for information on where the Convergence was being held.)

Police searched four cars outside The Wire with a K-9 unit after the event, but no arrests were made.

The parade was an impromptu activity organized by CrimethInc. The group's Convergence was a communal campout that took place northeast of Athens since last Wednesday. The event offered collective workshops on topics ranging from "Nude Theory and Practice" to do-it-yourself shoemaking. Participants traveled from all over North America to attend the event, which was organized with the help of local volunteers.

According to CrimethInc.'s Web site, the group is an "underground network through which we work to realize our daydreams, to take the reigns of our lives and make our history rather than using the same energy to insist we are being made of it."

The network is comprised of scattered collectives, travelers, music acts and publications that are invited to use the CrimethInc. label on their products and activities.

"There is no leader of CrimethInc.; it's a movement on its own," said a participant named Polly who traveled from North Carolina to attend the convergence. "It's a movement comprised of fun and energy."

Other participants said CrimethInc. is dedicated to creating alternative communities.

"I think it's important to foster communities outside of the 'real world,'" said Ben Croya of Illinois. Croya identifies has a "gender queer" and does not claim a specific gender or sexual orientation.

"Here individuals really have a say in there own lives," Croya said.

There is no central location or headquarters for CrimethInc., and no one is quite sure when and where the network originated, though some speculate it has been around since the late 1980s. According to some participants, the ambiguous and decentralized nature of the organization enhances the romantic appeal of its existence and propaganda, which is popular among youth in the punk, anarchist and dropout cultures.

"They live more than the rest have ever dreamt to live," said one participant who identified himself as Mad Fish the Norseman. "Follow those who only mumble, for they are already doing what doesn't need to be said."

CrimethInc. is responsible for several publications advocating an anti-capitalist lifestyle, including "Days of War Nights of Love," "Fighting for Our Lives," "Evasion" and a magazine titled Rolling Thunder, which chronicles the modern North American anarchist movement.</blockquote>]]></content_encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp_post_id>113</wp_post_id>
		<wp_post_date><![CDATA[2007-07-30 11:38:47]]></wp_post_date>
		<wp_post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2007-07-30 18:38:47]]></wp_post_date_gmt>
		<wp_comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp_comment_status>
		<wp_ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp_ping_status>
		<wp_post_name><![CDATA[convergence-coverage-appetizer]]></wp_post_name>
		<wp_status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp_status>
		<wp_post_parent>0</wp_post_parent>
		<wp_menu_order>0</wp_menu_order>
		<wp_post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp_post_type>
		<wp_post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp_post_password>
		<wp_is_sticky>0</wp_is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="from-the-trenches"><![CDATA[From the Trenches]]></category>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>154</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[b. traven]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[b@crimethinc.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url>http://www.crimethinc.com</wp_comment_author_url>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[76.182.58.84]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2007-08-02 23:33:50]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2007-08-03 06:33:50]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[[And as Athens locals themselves tell it:]

A spontaneously organized parade and street party in Athens, OH was attacked by police last night on Saturday, July 28. The Wire, a local infoshop, was also a target of police harassment and intimidation prior to a benefit show to be held that evening.

Athens, OH -- On the night of Saturday, July 28 a parade and street party was spontaneously organized that involved 200 to 300 participants who flooded the streets of the university district and main downtown area. Performers danced through the city, fire spinners awed the crowds who came out of restaurants and bars and onto the sidewalks, and many children and adults wore costumes and silly masks, and created music and noise by singing and playing drums and horns and didgeridoos (while others held signs that read "didgeridon't!").

The festive atmosphere of the parade continued even as a police cruiser arrived at the intersection of N. Court St. and W. State St. An officer jumped out of the car without making any announcements to the crowd and approached a fire spinner, immediately pushing them in an apparent attempt to grab the poi from their hands during a performance.

As the parade continued to move on past the intersection and down towards State and Carpenter, the same officer who attacked the fire spinner then chased after the parade on foot, misting pepper spray into the air and injuring about a dozen people. He then continued pursuit in the police cruiser.

Once the parade reached the intersection of State and Carpenter, police vehicles were seen moving down Mill St. in an attempt to cut up a few blocks and cut off the street party. Participants fearful of further attack broke into a quicker pace and many cut down Grosvenor St. while others continued down Carpenter St. Two police vehicles pulled up on Grosvenor St. and officers got out of the cars and chased participants.

At least one person was arrested, and a handful of others were unaccounted for once people regrouped. Bail was raised by donations from some of the parade participants.

The Wire - Under Attack!
---------------------------------
Following the street party and parade many participants headed for The Wire to attend the ongoing benefit show and dance party.

Upon arrival police cruisers were already parked outside and warning organizers of the benefit show not to exceed legal noise levels. In an effort to placate police demands the benefit show was called off.

Some people chose to drive home at that point and were followed by police. An hour or so later more police showed up with drug sniffing dogs and proceeded to search four or five cars parked in the area outside of The Wire.

Meanwhile people listening in on police scanners heard discussion by officers attempting to obtain a search warrant and organize a raid of the infoshop.

The illegal searches of cars were documented and videotaped. Nothing was found and nobody was ticketed or arrested.

It is still unclear if the police raided The Wire late last night, or if they plan on doing so in the near future.

In addition to previous and current police harassment, The Wire is having financial difficulties staying open, so please think about supporting them in whatever ways possible and helping out!

http://www.athenswire.org/node/25

[To quote another local: "As an aside, The Wire was *not* raided by cops that night. Also, contrary to other reports, officers were not grabbed or assualted, and the pepper spray used by cops was not in self defense. It was *after* the crowd moved on that we were then attacked and sprayed with chemical weapons, *as we were in fact retreating and attempting to avoid confrontation.*"] ]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>2</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>155</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[b. traven]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[b@crimethinc.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url>http://www.crimethinc.com</wp_comment_author_url>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[76.182.58.84]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2007-08-02 23:08:23]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2007-08-03 06:08:23]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[[As the more corporate media tell it:]

A lone anarchist answered to charges of rioting Monday, while about a dozen supporters looked on at an arraignment hearing in municipal court.

John Rushton, of Oklahoma, plead no contest to a misdemeanor charge of rioting. He was arrested Saturday night after police used pepper spray and dispersed a crowd of about 200 people participating in an impromptu gathering on Court Street.

Rushton and those who attended his hearing are members of an anarchist group that participated in a "convergence" this weekend near Athens. The convention was organized by CrimethInc., an underground network of anarchists and other radicals.

Police said they had received a call at about 9:42 p.m. Saturday that the intersection at North Court and State Street was blocked by a large group, and that people were climbing poles and attempting to tear down signs. Lt. Randy Gray and Ptl. Ron Brooks responded to the call and said they found the intersection blocked, with people carrying improvised drums, sticks, rocks and bricks. In addition, some people had dragged a construction barrier from the corner of College and East Union to the corner of Court and West State Street.

Ohio University police, who made the arrest when they were called in to assist, said Rushton was part of the group of people dragging the large "Road Closed" construction sign, and was later asked to put out the flaming torches he was twirling.

After pleading no contest, Rushton said in his defense that the torches, which were at the end of chains, was a performance art. "I don't remember hearing any order to disperse, but as I was arrested, I was dispersing," he said.

Four other arrests were made late Saturday night, but it is unclear if those arrests were related to the anarchist gathering. OUPD arrested three people on obstruction of official business charges, and the Ohio Department of Public Safety enforcement division made one disorderly conduct by intoxication arrest.

Athens Police Capt. Tom Pyle said the pepper spray was not deployed for the purpose of dispersing the crowd, but for the officer's safety, because shortly after stepping out of his car, Lt. Randy Gray was struck in the back and grabbed by the arm while speaking to group members. Pyle pointed out that Athens police sent only two officers to see what was going on, which is not how they would have handled a brewing riot.

The group members who attended the hearing said the event was a celebration, which came together at the end of the convergence. However, the CrimethInc. Web site advocates monitoring of police conduct by citizens to protect against abuse of power, and emphasizes knowing one's rights when in contact with police, including advice on how to document an incident to protect one's legal rights.

Rushton was ordered to pay a $100 fine, and will avoid a 30-day jail sentence as long as he stays out of trouble for two years.

<a href="http://www.athensmessenger.com/main.asp?SectionID=1&SubSectionID=273&ArticleID=4478&TM=35045.77" rel="nofollow">[Original article here]</a>]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>2</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
	</item>