<item>
		<title>Why Break Windows?</title>
		<link>http://www.crimethinc.com/blog/2014/12/10/why-break-windows/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 17:59:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc_creator><![CDATA[b. traven]]></dc_creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.crimethinc.com/blog/?p=5350</guid>
		<description/>
		<content_encoded><![CDATA[<p>From the initial <a href="http://antistatestl.noblogs.org/post/2014/09/18/a-timeline-of-the-ferguson-uprising/">revolt in Ferguson</a> last August to <a href="http://fireworksbayarea.com/featured/we-welcome-the-fire-we-welcome-the-rain/">the demonstrations</a> in Oakland and Berkeley last week, property destruction has been central to a new wave of struggle against police violence. But what does vandalizing businesses have to do with protesting police brutality? Why break windows?</p>

<p>First, as <a href="#furtherreading">countless others</a> have argued, because property destruction is an effective tactic. From the Boston Tea Party to <a href="http://depts.washington.edu/wtohist/Research/documents/black_bloc_communique.htm">the demonstrations</a> against the 1999 World Trade Organization summit in Seattle, property destruction has been an essential part of many struggles. It can pressure or punish opponents by inflicting an economic cost. It can mobilize potential comrades by <a href="http://crimethinc.com/texts/r/bluefuse/">demonstrating that the ruling forces are not invincible</a>. It can force issues that otherwise would be suppressed—we would certainly not be having a nationwide conversation about race, class, and policing were it not for the courageous actions of a few vandals in Ferguson. Finally, it conveys an uncompromising rejection of the prevailing order, opening space in which people may begin to imagine another.</p>

<!--more Continue reading after the jump.-->

<p>Property destruction charges don’t look good on a résumé or in a campaign for city council, but perhaps this is a good thing. It means that political vandalism is usually a selfless act—and even when it isn’t, it has to be its own reward. There is more reason to suspect paid nonprofit activists and aspiring politicians of ulterior motives than to question the motivations of vandals. This may explain why activists and politicians cast such aspersions on them.</p>

<p>Shop windows represent segregation. They are invisible barriers. Like so much in this society, they simultaneously offer a view of “the good life” and block access to it. In a polarizing economy, shop windows taunt the poor with commodities they cannot afford, status and security they will never attain. For millions upon millions, the healthy food, medicines, and other goods they need are the breadth of an entire social class away from them, a gulf they will not cross in a lifetime of hard work—a gulf represented by half an inch of plate glass.</p>

<p>To smash a shop window is to contest all the boundaries that cut through this society: black and white, rich and poor, included and excluded. Most of us have become inured to all this segregation, taking such inequalities for granted as a fact of life. Breaking windows is a way to break this silence, to challenge the absurd notion that the social construct of property rights is more important than the needs of the people around us.</p>

<p>One reactionary argument goes that vandals are wrecking “their own neighborhoods,” but this is a disingenuous way to speak about those whose names do not appear on any deeds. Indeed, when developers speak of “improving” these neighborhoods, they mean the de facto expulsion of the current population. The problem in Ferguson and everywhere like it is not that the economy has been interrupted; the problem is the routine functioning of the economy itself. In a profit-driven society, the more that poor people work and pay rent, the poorer they will end up relative to those who are profiting on their labor—that’s where profit comes from. It is dishonest to blame the victim here, as if more submissiveness could produce a different result. In a pyramid scheme, somebody has to form the bottom tier, and ever since the colonization of the so-called Americas that has always meant black and brown people.</p>

<p>As others have <a href="http://fireworksbayarea.com/featured/we-welcome-the-fire-we-welcome-the-rain/">pointed out</a>, colonization, gentrification, mass incarceration, and police killings are all forms of displacement, of erasure. We have become accustomed to ceaseless, dramatic disruptions of the environments we live in—so long as it is capitalists and police driving them, not poor people. This normalizes an alienated relation to the urban landscape, so whole neighborhoods can be leveled and replaced without anyone batting an eyelid. It normalizes a social system that itself has only been imposed on the earth over the past couple centuries, making the most unsustainable way of life ever practiced seem timeless and eternal. Vandalism demonstrates that both the current disposition of urban space and the social system that determines it are contingent and temporary—that it is possible, even with limited resources, to transform space according to a different logic. Gentrification and vandalism are both forms of intervention in the urban landscape—the difference is that gentrification is top-down, while vandalism is bottom-up.</p>

<p>It is not a coincidence that shop windows have been targeted in protests against police violence. Businesses, be they multinational or local, are the tax base that pays for police, and without police they would not be able to accumulate so much wealth at everyone else’s expense. In this situation, addressing protests directly to the police is oblique, for the police answer to business owners and politicians, not to public opinion. It is much more direct to target their bosses, the capitalists themselves. Cost them enough money in smashed windows, and maybe they’ll think twice about what kind of policing they call for.</p>

<p>“But some poor worker is going to have to clean that up,” sanctimonious <a href="http://www.commondreams.org/views/2011/11/14/throwing-out-masters-tools-and-building-better-house-thoughts-importance">liberals</a> charge whenever they see a protester making free with the avenues of the wealthy. Anyone who has worked a blue-collar job knows that this is pure bunk. Replacing windows or scrubbing graffiti off a façade is no worse than any other kind of work one can get in that pay bracket—it's not as though the workers in question would be doing something pleasant and fulfilling otherwise. If anything, vandalism creates jobs, offering additional work opportunities to service industry employees and construction workers whose labor would not otherwise be required. This means you can’t smash capitalism one storefront at a time—but trying to might at least redistribute a little wealth downward. It is typically liberal for critics to present the poor as the victims of confrontational tactics, when in fact it is their own status and comfort they fear for.</p>

<p>In the more paranoid version of this perspective, liberals who assume that everyone else must be as satisfied with the prevailing order as they are declare that only the police themselves, in disguise of course, would have smashed the windows they are tasked with protecting. Like other conspiracy theories, this attributes all agency to a single nefarious power, denying the existence and strategic sense of those who take action against it.</p>

<p>All this is not to argue that window-smashing is itself enough to change the world. In the final analysis, sabotage and arson are the strategy of a retreating army—of those who know they will not hold a given terrain for long. A movement strong enough to retain the territory it seizes from the police wouldn’t need to break or burn anything, only to transform it. On the other hand, as long as such inequalities persist, people are bound to lash out against them via property destruction as well as other tactics. Anyone who truly desires to see an end to property destruction should hasten to bring about the end of property itself. Then, at last, the only reason to break windows would be thrill seeking.</p>

<p><a id="furtherreading" name="furtherreading"></a></p>

<h2>Further Reading</h2>

<p><strong><a href="http://slog.thestranger.com/slog/archives/2012/05/02/why-all-the-smashy-smashy-a-beginners-guide-to-targeted-property-destruction">A Beginner’s Guide to Targeted Property Destruction</a></strong></p>

<p><strong><a href="http://time.com/3605606/ferguson-in-defense-of-rioting/">In Defense of Rioting</a></strong></p>

<p><strong><a href="http://thenewinquiry.com/essays/in-defense-of-looting/">In Defense of Looting</a></strong></p>

<p><strong><a href="https://www.jacobinmag.com/2014/08/in-defense-of-the-ferguson-riots/">In Defense of the Ferguson Riots</a></strong></p>

<p><strong><a href="http://www.crimethinc.com/texts/atoz/violence.php">The Illegitimacy of Violence, the Violence of Legitimacy</a></strong></p>
]]></content_encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp_post_id>5350</wp_post_id>
		<wp_post_date><![CDATA[2014-12-10 09:59:20]]></wp_post_date>
		<wp_post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2014-12-10 17:59:20]]></wp_post_date_gmt>
		<wp_comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp_comment_status>
		<wp_ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp_ping_status>
		<wp_post_name><![CDATA[why-break-windows]]></wp_post_name>
		<wp_status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp_status>
		<wp_post_parent>0</wp_post_parent>
		<wp_menu_order>0</wp_menu_order>
		<wp_post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp_post_type>
		<wp_post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp_post_password>
		<wp_is_sticky>0</wp_is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="read-all-about-it"><![CDATA[Read All About It]]></category>
		<wp_postmeta>
			<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[_thumbnail_id]]></wp_meta_key>
			<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[5351]]></wp_meta_value>
		</wp_postmeta>
		<wp_postmeta>
			<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp_meta_key>
			<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp_meta_value>
		</wp_postmeta>
		<wp_postmeta>
			<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[jumbo]]></wp_meta_key>
			<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[http://www.crimethinc.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/12/1b.jpg]]></wp_meta_value>
		</wp_postmeta>
		<wp_postmeta>
			<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[_cws_is_markdown_gmt]]></wp_meta_key>
			<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[2014-12-10 21:28:56]]></wp_meta_value>
		</wp_postmeta>
		<wp_postmeta>
			<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[_cws_is_markdown]]></wp_meta_key>
			<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[2]]></wp_meta_value>
		</wp_postmeta>
		<wp_postmeta>
			<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[shorturl]]></wp_meta_key>
			<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[http://cwc.im/breakwindows]]></wp_meta_value>
		</wp_postmeta>
		<wp_postmeta>
			<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[_sd_is_markdown]]></wp_meta_key>
			<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp_meta_value>
		</wp_postmeta>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>2019</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[tseliot]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[dantenen@yahoo.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url/>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[76.124.142.220]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2014-12-15 14:28:17]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2014-12-15 22:28:17]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[How could anyone read this paragraph and not come to the conclusion that you endorse the destruction of local businesses:

"It is not a coincidence that shop windows have been targeted in protests against police violence. Businesses, be they multinational or local, are the tax base that pays for police, and without police they would not be able to accumulate so much wealth at everyone else’s expense. In this situation, addressing protests directly to the police is oblique, for the police answer to business owners and politicians, not to public opinion. It is much more direct to target their bosses, the capitalists themselves. Cost them enough money in smashed windows, and maybe they’ll think twice about what kind of policing they call for."

The idea that the owner of a beauty supply store is "accumulating so much wealth at everyone else's expense" is a good example of ideology trumping reality. Destroying someone's livelihood is no small thing. It is telling that the description of it has to be hidden behind layers of abstraction.

If these store owners are the bosses of the police, why didn't the police defend their stores?

If all the capitalists were to leave Ferguson and there were no more stores there, you would denounce this (see: 'food deserts', etc). Detroit and Newark have enjoyed decades of capital-flight following their own riots in the 60s. Neither city is free from poverty, police violence, or anything else.

I'm curious what the author of this thinks about the specific targeting of businesses owned by Asians. I don't understand why some groups of people are worthy of empathy but others are not.]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>4553</wp_comment_user_id>
			<wp_commentmeta>
				<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[akismet_result]]></wp_meta_key>
				<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[false]]></wp_meta_value>
			</wp_commentmeta>
			<wp_commentmeta>
				<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[akismet_history]]></wp_meta_key>
				<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[a:4:{s:4:"time";d:1418682497.98093891143798828125;s:7:"message";s:28:"Akismet cleared this comment";s:5:"event";s:9:"check-ham";s:4:"user";s:7:"tseliot";}]]></wp_meta_value>
			</wp_commentmeta>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>2029</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[zorroloco]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[jeffaheiman@gmail.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url/>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[98.246.31.55]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2014-12-24 06:58:56]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2014-12-24 14:58:56]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[traven,
"Yet clearly, at least some of the people who have been engaging in vandalism and looting in Ferguson and other places are among the desperately poor. Have you read the statistics about who lives in Ferguson?"

yes - and many were not. i was at the wto protests in seattle way back, and rodney king and iraq protests as well. people broke windows. some were poor and some not. false connection.

"it’s still strange to read you and tseliot referring to the property owners whose windows were broken as the “victims,” but not saying anything about the hundreds killed every year by police, nor their families, ..."

right. and i have not heard you say a word about starving children in honduras nor ebola victims in guinea. for a reason - they are unrelated to this conversation. i have not mentioned the victims of police brutality because there is no real connection between police brutality and breaking windows. you could walk around and break windows to protest war, economic inequality, lack of health care, etc., etc.... but that does not make them equivalent. look... this is not about police brutality - it is about justifying vandalism in one's community. straw man.

"One more thing–you’ve said a couple times now that vandalism is somehow inherently “undisciplined” and “unfocused”"

yes. and i stand by this. while the organizers may have well thought out plans and be disciplined, the very nature and intent of public protests is to get MANY people involved - and that means most participants will just be undisciplined angry people who easily get out of control (remember reginald denny?), and some will be thugs looking for an opportunity for personal gain.

"It sounds to me like you have a stereotype in your head of the “wild rioter” who is not able to make rational decisions."

lol. dude - i suspect i was in the streets when you were not even a twinkle. maybe you are older than you sound, but i was pulled out of 3rd grade by my mom to attend anti-vietnam protests in 1970. i am not basing this on an establishment induced stereotype!

"For some people, breaking windows is their equivalent of monkeywrenching."

yes. i engaged in this in my youth. but this is not what you were defending. you are talking about vandalism in the context of public protests. can't you see that this is almost always going to get out of hand? broken windows lead to looting. looting leads to people getting shot. 

"To be silent while the police go on killing is to open the door for more murders of the black and poor, regardless of whether rioting will bring down capitalism."

who said we should be silent? not breaking windows somehow equates to not doing anything in your mind???

sorry man, your heart is in the right place but you lack logic. your theoretical defense of vandalism falls flat against the reality of life. you really think some cop in san diego is going to "think twice" before shooting because of broken windows in ferguson?]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>4554</wp_comment_user_id>
			<wp_commentmeta>
				<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[akismet_result]]></wp_meta_key>
				<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[false]]></wp_meta_value>
			</wp_commentmeta>
			<wp_commentmeta>
				<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[akismet_history]]></wp_meta_key>
				<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[a:4:{s:4:"time";d:1419433136.7572300434112548828125;s:7:"message";s:28:"Akismet cleared this comment";s:5:"event";s:9:"check-ham";s:4:"user";s:9:"zorroloco";}]]></wp_meta_value>
			</wp_commentmeta>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>2013</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[Amory]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[ohpmodeling@gmail.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url/>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[70.196.66.69]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2014-12-10 16:06:47]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2014-12-11 00:06:47]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[Looting a small coffee house or hair salon owned by one of the poor residents of the community is good because it creates jobs for another blue collar worker? Are you fucking kidding me? I agree with a lot of the sentiment here, but this completely ignores the most glaring critique of looting local business by insulating itself with ad hominem attacks ("sanctimonious liberals"). If a poor person from an oppressed racial group in an area with very limited economic opportunities tries to make her living by opening a small place to style the hair of the community, risks the little money she has saved to buy a ramshackle shed in the area, works hard to clean it up and build the sign, passes out fliers to advertise the opening, hires a neighbor or two whom she knows are especially exploited by their current employers....

Saying stealing the money she has earned from the register and burning her store down is just liberal charlatanism to maintain their bourgeois comforts? You preach a vainglorious gospel from a ivory soapbox. Telling people that ransacking the independent bookstore is as good for "smashing capitalism" as burning down the courthouse. You would have the movement cannibalize itself by new years.]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>4550</wp_comment_user_id>
			<wp_commentmeta>
				<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[akismet_result]]></wp_meta_key>
				<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[false]]></wp_meta_value>
			</wp_commentmeta>
			<wp_commentmeta>
				<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[akismet_history]]></wp_meta_key>
				<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[a:4:{s:4:"time";d:1418256408.1189060211181640625;s:7:"message";s:28:"Akismet cleared this comment";s:5:"event";s:9:"check-ham";s:4:"user";s:5:"Amory";}]]></wp_meta_value>
			</wp_commentmeta>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>2014</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[ret marut]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[ret@crimethinc.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url/>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[174.99.73.34]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2014-12-11 01:20:00]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2014-12-11 09:20:00]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[Amory--

Let's imagine, just for the sake of dignified discussion, that you are not intentionally misrepresenting the above arguments--that you are genuinely concerned that someone will read this text and rush out to target the smallest and most precarious business they can find. That's absurd, of course--but if you need to see this written out for you, no, no one is arguing that it is important to loot independent bookstores or burn down ramshackle sheds. I hope you feel better now?

Anyway, if you're seriously concerned about "friendly fire" vandalism, you can put your money where your mouth is and donate to assist a couple Bay Area small businesses that have been damaged in the course of the recent protests:

https://villagecraft.org/e/f46475b9-raise-funds-to-repair-windows-end-racism-not-local-businesses

I fear, however, that you are more invested in grandstanding than in actually helping those in need. Please prove me wrong!]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>3</wp_comment_user_id>
			<wp_commentmeta>
				<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[akismet_result]]></wp_meta_key>
				<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[false]]></wp_meta_value>
			</wp_commentmeta>
			<wp_commentmeta>
				<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[akismet_history]]></wp_meta_key>
				<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[a:4:{s:4:"time";d:1418289611.778995990753173828125;s:7:"message";s:28:"Akismet cleared this comment";s:5:"event";s:9:"check-ham";s:4:"user";s:9:"ret marut";}]]></wp_meta_value>
			</wp_commentmeta>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>2015</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[Amory]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[ohpmodeling@gmail.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url/>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[70.196.66.69]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2014-12-11 12:44:30]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2014-12-11 20:44:30]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[This article EXPLICITLY condones looting local businesses, numerous times, and for all its proselytizing is conveniently silent on addressing the local independent businesses that actually were razed. YOU tell ME why this only chooses to glorify neighborhood property destruction when many of the fires are something the KKK would have done.  You seem oblivious to the incarnate and symbolic connections between the looting of Natalie Dubose's cake store and the incineration of both Juanita's Fashion Boutique and the body of DeAndre Joshua, all among the Ferguson rioting. 

It is sickeningly disingenuous for you to defend the article's scholarship by discrediting those who criticize its message with accusations of "grandstanding". I created an account because this issue matters. Your response was almost entirely dismissive on what is both a valid an urgent point of stasis in the discussion of what is happening. Again, YOU tell ME, why the violence done to the opportunity of the poor isnt mentioned in the article advocating the looting of poor neighborhoods. Sure, fuck the oppressive businesses. But why is it silent on the burning of Juanitas Fashion Boutique and only defending straw man "sanctimonious liberal" voices suggesting to destroy the DAs office instead of the black-owned local cake shop?]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>4550</wp_comment_user_id>
			<wp_commentmeta>
				<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[akismet_result]]></wp_meta_key>
				<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[false]]></wp_meta_value>
			</wp_commentmeta>
			<wp_commentmeta>
				<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[akismet_history]]></wp_meta_key>
				<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[a:4:{s:4:"time";d:1418330670.5290129184722900390625;s:7:"message";s:28:"Akismet cleared this comment";s:5:"event";s:9:"check-ham";s:4:"user";s:5:"Amory";}]]></wp_meta_value>
			</wp_commentmeta>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>2016</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[jaakkima]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[enggopah@gmail.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url/>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[108.220.49.133]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2014-12-11 22:27:23]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2014-12-12 06:27:23]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[Amory-

B.S. I read that article in between all the lines and it never speaks about what you are speaking about.]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>4551</wp_comment_user_id>
			<wp_commentmeta>
				<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[akismet_result]]></wp_meta_key>
				<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[false]]></wp_meta_value>
			</wp_commentmeta>
			<wp_commentmeta>
				<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[akismet_history]]></wp_meta_key>
				<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[a:4:{s:4:"time";d:1418365645.8961980342864990234375;s:7:"message";s:28:"Akismet cleared this comment";s:5:"event";s:9:"check-ham";s:4:"user";s:8:"jaakkima";}]]></wp_meta_value>
			</wp_commentmeta>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>2017</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[jaakkima]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[enggopah@gmail.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url/>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[108.220.49.133]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2014-12-11 22:36:06]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2014-12-12 06:36:06]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[By which I mean addressing local businesses explicitly. Granted it doesn't address local poor businesses that have been hurt. But neither did it intend to. If this silence is the extent of what you would become 'sickened' by about this article about, well... if I were you, I would write something myself about the need to make those accounts. In general, I think it is a concern that is distinct from the basic purpose of this article.]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>4551</wp_comment_user_id>
			<wp_commentmeta>
				<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[akismet_result]]></wp_meta_key>
				<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[false]]></wp_meta_value>
			</wp_commentmeta>
			<wp_commentmeta>
				<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[akismet_history]]></wp_meta_key>
				<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[a:4:{s:4:"time";d:1418366166.51377201080322265625;s:7:"message";s:28:"Akismet cleared this comment";s:5:"event";s:9:"check-ham";s:4:"user";s:8:"jaakkima";}]]></wp_meta_value>
			</wp_commentmeta>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>2018</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[ret marut]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[ret@crimethinc.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url/>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[204.85.209.205]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2014-12-11 23:03:36]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2014-12-12 07:03:36]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[Amory--like you, I earnestly desire to have this conversation. I appreciate you setting up an account and sharing your perspective.

The only problem is that it's hard to believe you're looking at the same article as I am. You say "This article EXPLICITLY condones looting local businesses, numerous times," but the word "local" only appears once in the entire text, and not in a sentence endorsing anything. As for the jab about "sanctimonious liberals," there is a link conveying precisely who and what that refers to. [I wish Rebecca Solnit were urging people to "destroy the DAs office" rather than Black-owned businesses, but she most certainly is not.]

There are plenty of people who have ulterior motives to obscure the issue whenever property destruction comes up for discussion. I remember Bill Clinton describing the courageous people who engaged in politically targeted vandalism during the WTO protests in Seattle as having smashed up mom 'n' pop businesses--a dishonest maneuver to discredit them. I was hesitant to believe that your first comment was in earnest, because you seemed to be performing a similar rhetorical operation.

I agree with you that it is important to discuss what kinds of property targeting are ethical, as well as strategic. That is simply outside the scope of the above text, which focuses only on the reasons that people sometimes engage in property destruction. I also agree that it is paramount to talk about how poor and targeted folks can protect each other from the violence of autonomous vigilantes and plunderers as well as the police, especially during periods of urban chaos. Unfortunately, that is also outside the frame of the above text. It would be lovely to be able to skip directly to that conversation, instead of endlessly repeating the most basic points about why anyone would break a window in the first place, but the problem is that the discussion about political property destruction is always derailed before it can be concluded.

Case in point.]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>3</wp_comment_user_id>
			<wp_commentmeta>
				<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[akismet_result]]></wp_meta_key>
				<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[false]]></wp_meta_value>
			</wp_commentmeta>
			<wp_commentmeta>
				<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[akismet_history]]></wp_meta_key>
				<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[a:4:{s:4:"time";d:1418367816.6809570789337158203125;s:7:"message";s:28:"Akismet cleared this comment";s:5:"event";s:9:"check-ham";s:4:"user";s:9:"ret marut";}]]></wp_meta_value>
			</wp_commentmeta>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>2020</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[zorroloco]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[jeffaheiman@gmail.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url/>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[98.246.26.94]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2014-12-15 16:41:46]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2014-12-16 00:41:46]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[what a crock of purest bunk. those windows, in many cases, are owned by community members, as amory points out. let us be very clear - you are not talking about monkey wrenching, with a long and glorious, if somewhat checkered, past. you are promoting and defending the wanton destruction of your neighbors' stuff - different in no substantive way from me coming over to your house and smashing it up. you are stealing from these people.

vandalism in the context of political action is, by its nature, unfocused. you cannot pick the windows that belong to the evil corporations and spare those owned by the family down the street. do you think collateral damage in war is acceptable too?

i notice also that the author has completely ignored the very salient point that many, if not most, of the windows being broken were done so in acts of hooliganism, often related to looting, not as acts of political protest. this is very important because it dramatically weakens the political message - in fact, it destroys any such message which was intended. sad, but true. to fail to acknowledge this is silly.

the only 'political statement' you are making when you support these actions is that you lack basic human decency and common sense. it is an ineffective, immoral, and ignorant way to make a statement and/or effect change. sorry... i just find this to be a very poorly thought out stance. what if it was your aunties shop?]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>4554</wp_comment_user_id>
			<wp_commentmeta>
				<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[akismet_result]]></wp_meta_key>
				<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[false]]></wp_meta_value>
			</wp_commentmeta>
			<wp_commentmeta>
				<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[akismet_history]]></wp_meta_key>
				<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[a:4:{s:4:"time";d:1418690506.924602031707763671875;s:7:"message";s:28:"Akismet cleared this comment";s:5:"event";s:9:"check-ham";s:4:"user";s:9:"zorroloco";}]]></wp_meta_value>
			</wp_commentmeta>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>2021</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[tseliot]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[dantenen@yahoo.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url/>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[76.124.142.220]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2014-12-16 13:42:58]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2014-12-16 21:42:58]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA["what if it was your aunties shop?"

Ah, well this is a stance that is predicated on moral disengagement (dehumanizing victims to prevent empathy).]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>4553</wp_comment_user_id>
			<wp_commentmeta>
				<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[akismet_result]]></wp_meta_key>
				<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[false]]></wp_meta_value>
			</wp_commentmeta>
			<wp_commentmeta>
				<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[akismet_history]]></wp_meta_key>
				<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[a:4:{s:4:"time";d:1418766179.255014896392822265625;s:7:"message";s:28:"Akismet cleared this comment";s:5:"event";s:9:"check-ham";s:4:"user";s:7:"tseliot";}]]></wp_meta_value>
			</wp_commentmeta>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>2022</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[zorroloco]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[jeffaheiman@gmail.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url/>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[98.246.26.94]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2014-12-16 16:08:11]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2014-12-17 00:08:11]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[ts

"Ah, well this is a stance that is predicated on moral disengagement (dehumanizing victims to prevent empathy)."

exactly! yes it is. that is why i compared it to 'collateral damage,'another dehumanizing term.]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>4554</wp_comment_user_id>
			<wp_commentmeta>
				<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[akismet_result]]></wp_meta_key>
				<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[false]]></wp_meta_value>
			</wp_commentmeta>
			<wp_commentmeta>
				<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[akismet_history]]></wp_meta_key>
				<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[a:4:{s:4:"time";d:1418774891.2895700931549072265625;s:7:"message";s:28:"Akismet cleared this comment";s:5:"event";s:9:"check-ham";s:4:"user";s:9:"zorroloco";}]]></wp_meta_value>
			</wp_commentmeta>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>2024</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[tseliot]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[dantenen@yahoo.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url/>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[76.124.142.220]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2014-12-16 20:06:57]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2014-12-17 04:06:57]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[I should also add that I am very glad that there are not riots where I live, and I cannot bring myself to wish something upon others that I would not want to happen to me.]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>4553</wp_comment_user_id>
			<wp_commentmeta>
				<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[akismet_result]]></wp_meta_key>
				<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[false]]></wp_meta_value>
			</wp_commentmeta>
			<wp_commentmeta>
				<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[akismet_history]]></wp_meta_key>
				<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[a:4:{s:4:"time";d:1418789218.1002559661865234375;s:7:"message";s:28:"Akismet cleared this comment";s:5:"event";s:9:"check-ham";s:4:"user";s:7:"tseliot";}]]></wp_meta_value>
			</wp_commentmeta>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>2025</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[b. traven]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[b@crimethinc.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url/>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[174.99.73.34]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2014-12-17 01:01:52]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2014-12-17 09:01:52]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[zorroloco and tseliot--

It's fascinating how, as soon as any person or text speaks a bit about why someone might choose to engage in politicized vandalism--no matter how desperate the situation of the vandal in question--everyone immediately commences humanizing the ones whose property was damaged, depicting them as vulnerable little startup businesses (even if the majority of the targets were large corporations), while ignoring and erasing the grievous situation that would drive one to commit politicized vandalism. This implicitly dehumanizes the vandals.

And this maneuver should not be surprising to us, because in the US, on a deep, unconscious level, we tend to see people as human only to the extent to which they own property. We regard property as the physical manifestation of a person's interests--with the implication that a person who owns nothing has no interests to be violated. The laws that afford protection to people's property according to how much it is worth show that the rich are valued more than the poor: it is a misdemeanor to break or steal something cheap, but a felony if it is expensive. And those laws afford no protection whatsoever to those who have had everything stolen from them by a systematically racist and exploitative system. If you have no property, there are very few laws to protect you, and the system of legal enforcement is biased against you as well.

In this situation, it can be revolutionary and transformative to look at the situation from the vandal's point of view, for once, rather than from the perspective of the property owners. We needn't endorse vandalism, necessarily, but we absolutely must try to understand it. Otherwise, we continue to render the exploited and oppressed invisible, becoming complicit in their suffering. This is not to endorse *every* act of property destruction, or to say that only poor or desperate people engage in vandalism and looting, but *you* are the ones trying to change the subject away from why people do this to how terrible it is. You should question what it is in you that makes you so eager to do that.

Watching you get outraged about a discussion of why vandals use vandalism to call attention to their plight, I see that same capitalist value system in place. Once again, the property owners are real people with whom we should sympathize, but the desperately poor are monsters whose behavior must be denigrated as immoral, criminal, etc. Seriously, we probably would not be having the nationwide conversation about race and policing that we are today if protesters in Ferguson hadn't smashed and burned shops there--similar protests about police murders (only with less vandalism and looting) had occurred in various cities for years, without ever getting into the national spotlight. To object to the actions of the courageous vandals in Ferguson is to suggest that it would be better if we never heard the name of Michael Brown, because in this racist, corporate media-dominated society, we damn sure weren't going to hear about it if people didn't act out--he would just have been another of the unknown Black men killed every 28 hours or so by police.

And yes, there is a racial dimension to this. We are talking about a society in which color lines and property lines have historically been identical. To identify more with the humanity of those who own property is to be structurally racist. 

To quote Willie Osterweil (http://thenewinquiry.com/essays/in-defense-of-looting/):

“In America, property is racial. It always has been. Indeed, the idea of blackness was invented simultaneously with American conceptions of property: via slavery."

"The earliest working definition of blackness may well have been “those who could be property” ... For most of America’s history, one of the most righteous anti-white supremacist tactics available was looting. The specter of slaves freeing themselves could be seen as American history’s first image of black looters."

"The mystifying ideological claim that looting is violent and non-political is one that has been carefully produced by the ruling class because it is precisely the violent maintenance of property which is both the basis and end of their power. Looting is extremely dangerous to the rich (and most white people) because it reveals, with an immediacy that has to be moralized away, that the idea of private property is just that: an idea, a tenuous and contingent structure of consent, backed up by the lethal force of the state. When rioters take territory and loot, they are revealing precisely how, in a space without cops, property relations can be destroyed and things can be had for free."

I agree absolutely with you that we should do as little harm to each other as we possibly can in the course of struggling against the systemic forms of harm imposed by capitalism and white supremacy. I care about small shop owners, and even about corporate bigwigs, in that they are all human beings. I want no one to suffer gratuitously. But until someone has a better and more effective plan for how to force the issue of white supremacy and abolish capitalism, it will be a higher priority for me to understand and defend the courageous actions of the oppressed than it will be to sympathize with those who own property and wealth.

This is not dehumanizing, but humanizing the outsiders, the exploited, those whose suffering is constantly normalized and rendered invisible.

If you wish to have a strategic conversation about how vandalism is targeted, you must acknowledge that that is a distinct issue, and that in this case you have been trying to change the subject. Please, please think about this.]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>2</wp_comment_user_id>
			<wp_commentmeta>
				<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[akismet_result]]></wp_meta_key>
				<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[false]]></wp_meta_value>
			</wp_commentmeta>
			<wp_commentmeta>
				<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[akismet_history]]></wp_meta_key>
				<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[a:4:{s:4:"time";d:1418806919.57250690460205078125;s:7:"message";s:28:"Akismet cleared this comment";s:5:"event";s:9:"check-ham";s:4:"user";s:9:"b. traven";}]]></wp_meta_value>
			</wp_commentmeta>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>2027</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[zorroloco]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[jeffaheiman@gmail.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url/>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[98.246.31.55]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2014-12-19 17:09:35]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2014-12-20 01:09:35]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[well you make some good point, particularly, "We needn’t endorse vandalism, necessarily, but we absolutely must try to understand it." unfortunately, you really did sound as if you were endorsing vandalism. 

i take some issue with, "Once again, the property owners are real people with whom we should sympathize, but the desperately poor are monsters whose behavior must be denigrated as immoral, criminal, etc." it is a nice trick to switch out 'looters and vandals' with 'the desperately poor.' 

as for bringing down the capitalist behemoth, good luck. it does not need you - it will collapse all on its own. i remain unconvinced that rioting and vandalism and looting will foster the changes you seek. you must either choose a violent confrontational means to the end - monkey wrenching and armed insurgency, or a peaceful means - education and community building. but both of these are disciplined. rioting and vandalizing is undisciplined. it is understandable, but that does not make it efficacious nor morally justifiable. 

instead of breaking windows, start a community garden, convince your neighbors to shop locally, teach kids. or fight back strategically. breaking the neighbors windows makes them poorer, enriches you not at all, makes your community worse, adds to anger/strife/violence in the world, and sends no message you really want to send.]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>4554</wp_comment_user_id>
			<wp_commentmeta>
				<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[akismet_result]]></wp_meta_key>
				<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[false]]></wp_meta_value>
			</wp_commentmeta>
			<wp_commentmeta>
				<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[akismet_history]]></wp_meta_key>
				<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[a:4:{s:4:"time";d:1419037775.491075992584228515625;s:7:"message";s:28:"Akismet cleared this comment";s:5:"event";s:9:"check-ham";s:4:"user";s:9:"zorroloco";}]]></wp_meta_value>
			</wp_commentmeta>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>2028</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[b. traven]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[b@crimethinc.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url/>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[174.99.73.34]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2014-12-19 22:55:36]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2014-12-20 06:55:36]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[Zorroloco--

Thanks for continuing this conversation.

I understand what you're saying about the rhetorical trick in the sentence about the difference between vandals and property owners. Yet clearly, at least some of the people who have been engaging in vandalism and looting in Ferguson and other places are among the desperately poor. Have you read the statistics about who lives in Ferguson? And if you were to compare the class status of vandals, taken as a whole, against the class status of property owners, there would be a big gap. Do you think if people could hire a fancy lawyer or field a candidate for office, they would be breaking windows? A riot, to quote Martin Luther King, is the language of the unheard.

That's not to say that wealthy capitalists and police never engage in vandalism. But most of the vandalism in protest against police violence since the murder of Michael Brown has obviously been carried out by the poor and angry.

Speaking of who gets humanized and who doesn't, it's still strange to read you and tseliot referring to the property owners whose windows were broken as the "victims," but not saying anything about the hundreds killed every year by police, nor their families, nor the millions of poor people who are prevented from getting the basic things they and their families need by constant police threats and violence. Who are the "victims" here? We are only having this conversation at all because courageous black and brown folks who were already at tremendous risk from police pushed the police murders into the public eye, by means of vandalism as well as other tactics. To change the subject to the poor window owners, calling them victims as if *they* were the ones suffering the tragedy here, is typical of the structural racism and classism that comes with the institution of property itself. The real tragedy is that people had to risk their lives and their freedom just to draw attention to this situation, and that they're being vilified now for what they did. Personally, I find their courage inspiring.

One more thing--you've said a couple times now that vandalism is somehow inherently "undisciplined" and "unfocused"--you even said "you cannot pick the windows that belong to the evil corporations and spare those owned by the family down the street." That's just not true--I'm sure that in situations like this, there are reasons for what gets broken. "You" can aways be conscientious in what you choose to do, even if you are breaking things. Vandalism is not inherently any less disciplined or targeted than other forms of sabotage.

It sounds to me like you have a stereotype in your head of the "wild rioter" who is not able to make rational decisions. This stereotype was invented by the rich and powerful to hide the very sensible reasons why poor people riot. Let's not accept this racist, classist stereotype. For some people, breaking windows is their equivalent of monkeywrenching. Just because they do it without a press release (the way good mostly-white NGO activists from Greenpeace do) doesn't mean it's any less rational or targeted.

Finally, we don't know for a fact that the people who broke windows in Ferguson didn't also (as you recommend) teach children, tend a community garden, and shop "locally" (whatever that means when your community doesn't own anything). Maybe they did all those things. But none of those would have been enough to call attention to the murder of Michael Brown, and I think they did the right thing to make sure we heard about it. To be silent while the police go on killing is to open the door for more murders of the black and poor, regardless of whether rioting will bring down capitalism. Cheers to all who dare--may the police think twice next time.

Thanks for your consideration.]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>2</wp_comment_user_id>
			<wp_commentmeta>
				<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[akismet_result]]></wp_meta_key>
				<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[false]]></wp_meta_value>
			</wp_commentmeta>
			<wp_commentmeta>
				<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[akismet_history]]></wp_meta_key>
				<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[a:4:{s:4:"time";d:1419058538.15841007232666015625;s:7:"message";s:28:"Akismet cleared this comment";s:5:"event";s:9:"check-ham";s:4:"user";s:9:"b. traven";}]]></wp_meta_value>
			</wp_commentmeta>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>2030</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[b. traven]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[b@crimethinc.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url/>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[99.42.116.32]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2014-12-26 00:21:40]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2014-12-26 08:21:40]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[Zorroloco--

I'll begin with your last and strongest arguments. It's not that not breaking windows equals silence, but rather that previous protests against police brutality failed to produce nationwide dialogue until the rioting, vandalism, and looting that occurred in Ferguson. That much is practically incontrovertible. If you believe there is another way to catalyze dialogue and bring about the end of police killings, by all means demonstrate it; otherwise, the least you can do is stop criticizing those who have made a little headway.

As for whether broken windows can actually impact police conduct, I'll offer a single anecdote: in the course of a few months in 2013, the police of Durham, North Carolina were responsible for the deaths of four different young men of color. After the fourth--a teenager--lost his life in police custody, protesters marched to the police headquarters and smashed out its windows in a sober, targeted action. The Durham police have not killed anyone since.

Besides that objection, you make claims about who broke windows in Ferguson based on what you experienced in other states over a decade ago. You change the subject from why those who protest police murders would break windows to bewail the dreadful suffering of the poor "victims" of those protests, and then cry straw man when I remind you that we are having this conversation because police are murdering people. Above all, you are deeply invested in a slippery slope argument (another common fallacy), though you also find it difficult to resist ad hominems. But surely it is not you who lacks logic!

The main thing that I'm taking away from this is that you don't want to talk about race and class. Fine, then, we don't have to have this conversation at all--but we really can't discuss tactics (or their legitimacy and effectiveness) without discussing the context in which they occur, a context inescapably inflected by race, class, and other hierarchies. 

Thanks for taking the time to discuss this; I hope you'll take some time to reflect on it.]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>2</wp_comment_user_id>
			<wp_commentmeta>
				<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[akismet_result]]></wp_meta_key>
				<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[false]]></wp_meta_value>
			</wp_commentmeta>
			<wp_commentmeta>
				<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[akismet_history]]></wp_meta_key>
				<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[a:4:{s:4:"time";d:1419582102.1815578937530517578125;s:7:"message";s:28:"Akismet cleared this comment";s:5:"event";s:9:"check-ham";s:4:"user";s:9:"b. traven";}]]></wp_meta_value>
			</wp_commentmeta>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>2031</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[tseliot]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[dantenen@yahoo.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url/>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[75.89.168.57]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2014-12-28 12:09:01]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2014-12-28 20:09:01]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[traven,

I've been thinking a lot about what you said - that humanizing the victims of looting and arson "implicitly dehumanizes the vandals." I worry about where this principle leads.

As far as I can tell, what you are saying is that looting/vandalism/etc are not good in themselves. Rather, it is a question of who/whom. If, for example, wealthy people decided to burn and to loot, rather than poor people, you would not be enthusiastic about it. (And what about the poor people who lost their livelihoods when the places they worked were destroyed? Oh well.) In your moral universe, actions are to be judged on an ad hominem basis. What is the limiting principle? Is there one? Or is this prefiguring the apologia for the guillotine, once the revolution begins and it's time to liquidate the enemy class?

The thing that confuses me the most about this, however, is that idea that anarchists would celebrate 'national dialogues' (that is, journalism and the speeches of politicians and politicians-to-be) about anything. It seems to me that policing killing anyone, of any color, is merely epiphenomenal to the real concern of anarchists: namely, society itself. Unless you've taken up the old Trotskyist line about 'intermediate demands', it seems dishonest to pretend that anarchists are for 'police reform' or 'dialogues about police killings' or whatever else. If police were not racist and never killed anyone, you would still oppose them (indeed, police in some places in the world rarely kill anyone).

Why are you always riding the coattails of the big story in the news?]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>4553</wp_comment_user_id>
			<wp_commentmeta>
				<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[akismet_result]]></wp_meta_key>
				<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[false]]></wp_meta_value>
			</wp_commentmeta>
			<wp_commentmeta>
				<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[akismet_history]]></wp_meta_key>
				<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[a:4:{s:4:"time";d:1419797341.8114540576934814453125;s:7:"message";s:28:"Akismet cleared this comment";s:5:"event";s:9:"check-ham";s:4:"user";s:7:"tseliot";}]]></wp_meta_value>
			</wp_commentmeta>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>2032</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[tseliot]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[dantenen@yahoo.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url/>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[75.89.168.57]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2014-12-28 12:26:10]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2014-12-28 20:26:10]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[As for your Durham example, which is weak, let's look at the aftermath of the riots in Detroit and Newark decades ago, which were larger and more intense than anything happening now. Can anyone say that the consequence of those riots has been less police brutality or corruption? Or anything good for the poor living there?

I think that if one wants to support rioting, it does not make sense to appeal to immediate efficacy. The argument is a more abstract one about the justice of violence by the poor, regardless of immediate or material consequences (which historically have been increased impoverishment).

It's also interesting that gentrification keeps coming up. Whatever is happening in Ferguson, gentrification is not the right word. In 1970, Ferguson's residents were nearly all white. By 2000, the split was 40% white and 50% black. Today Ferguson is 30% white and 67% black. Those numbers do not tell us much, but it's absurd to say that black residents are being displaced from the city!]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>4553</wp_comment_user_id>
			<wp_commentmeta>
				<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[akismet_result]]></wp_meta_key>
				<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[false]]></wp_meta_value>
			</wp_commentmeta>
			<wp_commentmeta>
				<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[akismet_history]]></wp_meta_key>
				<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[a:4:{s:4:"time";d:1419798370.1344621181488037109375;s:7:"message";s:28:"Akismet cleared this comment";s:5:"event";s:9:"check-ham";s:4:"user";s:7:"tseliot";}]]></wp_meta_value>
			</wp_commentmeta>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>2033</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[b. traven]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[b@crimethinc.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url/>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[174.99.73.34]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2014-12-28 22:51:30]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2014-12-29 06:51:30]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[TSEliot--

As you know, I didn't just say that humanizing the targets of politicized vandalism "“implicitly dehumanizes the vandals.” I said that "ignoring and erasing the grievous situation that would drive one to commit politicized vandalism" dehumanizes vandals. It's stunning how determined many people are to turn a blind eye to poverty, oppression, and desperation in this society. Try to start a conversation about that situation and the tactics it engenders, and watch people do anything they can to change the subject.

I still have the impression that you don't want to focus on why people commit politicized vandalism. Is it because you are uncomfortable looking at this world from the point of view of those who feel they have nothing to lose in rejecting it? Like any property owner quoted in the corporate media, you would rather talk about the poor property owners, not the poor who have nothing to lose--or, if absolutely necessary, you'll change the subject to how poor people suffer from looting, as if the constant imposition of business as usual isn't a far more grievous source of suffering to the poor. To cry that poor people are losing their livelihoods when the places they work are destroyed (seriously, how many places are we talking about here, that were actually "destroyed" in the last two months?) when people were rioting on account of much more structural factors stealing their livelihoods and lives on a much larger scale... well, that is yet another example of changing the subject, of continuing to identify with the perspective of the powerful and privileged. On a structural level, this redirects the conversation from the fundamental problems we face and the reasons people take radical action to try to solve them, back to questions of how to maintain order in the current paradigm.

This is not to say that I want to see the guillotine brought back--I don't. We're anarchists, not Bolsheviks or Jacobins. As soon as all the voices of the privileged and powerful (and everyone who isn't, but identifies with them) fall silent in defense of the humanity of the rulers and property owners, I'll raise my voice in their defense, calling for mercy and the peaceable resolution of conflict, should it be possible. But with all the politicians, television stations, and middle-class activists leaping to their defense right now, it is irresponsible not to focus first on those whose voices and actions are drowned out.

Regarding "dialogue," of course you knew already that I didn't mean dialogue with the state, or with the police, or with "civil society," or through the corporate media. Rather, I mean dialogue of the kind you and I are having--autonomous, grassroots, and decentralized--but more than that, the dialogue of *action* that has been taking place around the country since November, as thousands of people experiment with various tactics to interrupt the functioning of the society that depends on lethal policing and erases the deaths of its victims. Ordinarily, when the collective imagination is not open to new ideas and tactics, one may still pose questions (in words and deeds), but it's an uphill battle. Sometimes, however, a window opens, and it is suddenly possible to meet many new people on a new footing.

Perhaps this also answers your jab about "riding the coattails of the big story in the news." Now, CrimethInc. has been publishing material about policing, white supremacy, and direct action tactics for two decades. During some of those years, it was decidedly untimely. Finally, we have arrived at a time when many people are interested in joining in a discourse of deeds and ideas around this subject. It would be foolish to stand aside during it.

As for whether opposing the police here and now, and specifically trying to create a disincentive to their murdering folks of color, can be reduced to a matter of making "intermediate demands" ... once again, you know already that we have not hidden our opposition to all hierarchical power in the course of speaking on this issue, nor have we presented any demands to those in power. But to be an anarchist is not simply to express verbal opposition to "everything that is" (under some meaninglessly vague category like "society") and wait for a revolution to sweep them all away at once. Rather, it is to take concrete action to fight against all the mechanisms that impose oppression and suffering, even if doing so is unlikely to bring about the immediate abolition of the state, capitalism, white supremacy, patriarchy, etc. We try to struggle with an eye to opening a revolutionary horizon, but even if that is impossible, it is still worthwhile in itself to strike a blow against those who seek to dominate. The point of such immediate struggle is not to fix or stabilize the prevailing order--and I believe you and I agree that no amount of rioting, on its own, could abolish the social order that demands lethal policing. But surely you would also agree that if we could discourage police from taking black lives lightly, without somehow relegitimizing the police in the process, it would be a good thing.

Finally, about gentrification... that framework is more immediately relevant in Oakland than in Ferguson--that's why the link in that paragraph directs the reader to an article from Oakland. At the same time, surely there is some gentrification going on somewhere in Missouri, for the black population of Ferguson to have exploded in the way it has. 

Forgive the impatient tone of this response, written hastily before something else could replace it on my to-do list for the evening. As irascible as my tone sounds, I hope it comes across that I am interested in dialogue here.]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>2</wp_comment_user_id>
			<wp_commentmeta>
				<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[akismet_result]]></wp_meta_key>
				<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[false]]></wp_meta_value>
			</wp_commentmeta>
			<wp_commentmeta>
				<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[akismet_history]]></wp_meta_key>
				<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[a:4:{s:4:"time";d:1419835891.35976696014404296875;s:7:"message";s:28:"Akismet cleared this comment";s:5:"event";s:9:"check-ham";s:4:"user";s:9:"b. traven";}]]></wp_meta_value>
			</wp_commentmeta>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>2035</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[tseliot]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[dantenen@yahoo.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url/>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[50.153.237.5]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2015-01-01 08:08:49]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2015-01-01 16:08:49]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[I live in a place that is similar demographically to Ferguson, so I don't have a choice about turning a blind eye on poverty and all the rest. But paying attention to poverty does not necessarily lead to endorsing looting and arson. My neighbors do not burn down buildings, nor do most poor people (including those living in suburban Missouri). It's not clear that poverty causes rioting and arson at all (see: college party riots).

It is also simply not true that people have nothing to lose. Presumably, people have friends and family. Deandre Joshua certainly had friends and family, though nobody wants to talk about him.

re: national dialogue, you wrote the following:

"...if protesters in Ferguson hadn’t smashed and burned shops there–similar protests about police murders (only with less vandalism and looting) had occurred in various cities for years, without ever getting into the national spotlight. To object to the actions of the courageous vandals in Ferguson is to suggest that it would be better if we never heard the name of Michael Brown, because in this racist, corporate media-dominated society, we damn sure weren’t going to hear about it if people didn’t act out–he would just have been another of the unknown Black men killed every 28 hours or so by police."

You affirm 'grassroots dialogue', but when you say "national spotlight" and the rest, you must be referring to media coverage and 'civil society'. The implication of that paragraph is that the riots were good because they caused lots of corporate media coverage ('national spotlight'). I am not sure that's how the timeline of events went (there was lots of coverage before escalation of riots), but if the result of rioting/etc is a 'national spotlight' and its attendant 'dialogue', I'm not sure why those are good things, from an anarchist perspective. (It's also interesting that so many outlets of the corporate media that you decry have been broadcasting messages about Ferguson that are very similar to your own, as your approving link to Time Magazine demonstrates)

What distinguishes your politics on these issues from that of someone like Ta-Nehisi Coates (or the articles linked from Jacobin and Time Magazine)? Why do anarchists always become indistinguishable from the left, broadly conceived, when talking about race?]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>4553</wp_comment_user_id>
			<wp_commentmeta>
				<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[akismet_result]]></wp_meta_key>
				<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[false]]></wp_meta_value>
			</wp_commentmeta>
			<wp_commentmeta>
				<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[akismet_history]]></wp_meta_key>
				<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[a:4:{s:4:"time";d:1420128530.1152260303497314453125;s:7:"message";s:28:"Akismet cleared this comment";s:5:"event";s:9:"check-ham";s:4:"user";s:7:"tseliot";}]]></wp_meta_value>
			</wp_commentmeta>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>2073</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[carley]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[carendersbe@gmail.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url/>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[129.19.136.112]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2015-04-04 09:13:04]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2015-04-04 16:13:04]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[I have to disagree with this article, simply on a historical basis. Rarely has any political movement been successful by harming those that are neutral and just caught in the crossfire. 

Perhaps the greatest push for emancipation of slaves in the US was the persecution of Northern whites who refused to turn in slaves but didn't actively support them. And simultaneously, peaceful movements are widely cited as being the most powerful forces of change in history because they can create supporters in a way violence can't. 

I guarantee you that every shopkeeper who might have supported a new system and had their window broken now has a terrible view of anarchism being all about looting and burning the homes of innocents, and will be too concerned about the stability the police provided in trying to rebuild their lives to want change.

I am a supporter of most anarchist movements, but if I believe that my life is being threatened by  looters, I will not hesitate to shoot, and will revoke all support.]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>4591</wp_comment_user_id>
			<wp_commentmeta>
				<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[akismet_result]]></wp_meta_key>
				<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[false]]></wp_meta_value>
			</wp_commentmeta>
			<wp_commentmeta>
				<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[akismet_history]]></wp_meta_key>
				<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[a:4:{s:4:"time";d:1428163985.5051510334014892578125;s:7:"message";s:28:"Akismet cleared this comment";s:5:"event";s:9:"check-ham";s:4:"user";s:6:"carley";}]]></wp_meta_value>
			</wp_commentmeta>
		</wp_comment>
	</item>