<item>
		<title>Announcing To Change Everything!</title>
		<link>http://www.crimethinc.com/blog/2015/01/15/announcing-to-change-everything/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2015 20:12:24 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc_creator><![CDATA[pfm]]></dc_creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.crimethinc.com/blog/?p=5397</guid>
		<description/>
		<content_encoded><![CDATA[<p>After months of labor and coordination, we are proud to present our most ambitious effort yet. <a href="http://crimethinc.com/tce/"><em>To Change Everything</em></a> is a new multimedia overview of the anarchist project, updated for the 21st century. It is a primer for the curious, a polemic for the entrenched, a point of departure for everyone who longs for another world.</p>

<p><em>To Change Everything</em> includes a free full-color 48-page print publication, a video by <a href="http://www.submedia.tv/">Submedia.tv</a>, a responsive website featuring the text in 6 languages (with 14 more to come), and a sticker and poster campaign. Collectives in 19 countries across five continents have prepared two dozen different versions of the project, each tailored to match the local context.</p>

<p>Order copies to give out at events—distribute them around your neighborhood, college campus, community center, or workplace—leave one as your calling card when you interrupt business as usual. Put the <a href="http://store.crimethinc.com/x/index.html#qr">sticker</a> up on public transportation and anywhere else people might notice it. Circulate the website and video online, too!</p>

<p><a href="http://crimethinc.com/tce/"><strong>Visit the website</strong></a>
<strong>Order print copies : <a href="http://crimethinc.com/tce/get/#order">English</a> - <a href="http://crimethinc.com/tce/espanol/get/#order">Español</a></strong></p>

<p>Another page, <a href="http://www.crimethinc.com/texts/r/begin/"><strong>The Secret Is to Begin</strong></a>, offers an array of further resources as a next step for readers.</p>

<p>It’s high time for a project like this. All around the world, conflict is intensifying between human beings and authoritarian systems. We’re seeing uprisings from Bosnia to Brazil, autonomous zones in Greece and Rojava, fascist parties entering European parliaments. In the United States, successive waves of dispossession and injustice have swept new sectors of society into revolt one after another. The <a href="http://www.crimethinc.com/texts/recentfeatures/march4.php#bayarea">student movements</a> of 2009, the <a href="http://www.crimethinc.com/blog/2011/10/07/dear-occupiers-a-letter-from-anarchists/">Occupy</a> movement of 2011, the unrest that spread from <a href="http://antistatestl.noblogs.org/post/2014/09/18/a-timeline-of-the-ferguson-uprising/">Ferguson</a> in 2014—all of these have produced a population hungry for new visions. With faith in government, capitalism, policing, and all the other authoritarian institutions of our day at an all-time low, the time is ripe to open the way to liberation—and if we don’t seize the opportunity, <a href="http://crimethinc.com/texts/ux/ukraine.html">others</a> will exploit the situation for their own nefarious ends. <em>To Change Everything</em> steps into the breach.</p>

<p>When <a href="http://www.crimethinc.com/blog/2014/10/07/new-project-to-change-everything/">we first pitched this project</a>, we promised to make 100,000 copies. We swiftly recognized that wouldn’t be enough. Supporters donated over $22,000 via <a href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/crimethinc/to-change-everything">Kickstarter</a>, and a few generous comrades contributed over $10,000 more. Thanks to them, we’ve been able to deliver more than we originally envisioned. We’ve helped collectives in Brazil, Argentina, Romania, and Slovenia fund their print versions; we’ve earmarked 3000 copies for prisoner support groups to send to prisoners in the US; and we made almost <em>twice as many</em> print copies ourselves as we proposed to.</p>

<p><strong>Altogether, we printed 175,000 copies for North America: 150,000 in English and 25,000 in <a href="http://crimethinc.com/tce/espanol/">Spanish</a>.</strong> <a href="http://www.activedistributionshop.org/shop/">Active Distribution</a> printed 10,000 more in English to distribute throughout the UK and Europe. The <a href="http://www.black-mosquito.org/index.php/crimethinc-alles-verandern.html">TCE group in Germany</a> made 10,000 copies for their first print run; the <a href="paramudartudo.com">group in Brazil</a> has already gone through 4000 copies. Release events have taken place in Brazil, Argentina, Canada, Germany, Croatia, and Slovenia, as well as the US.</p>

<p>All this is thanks to 100% volunteer labor. We extend our deepest appreciation to Submedia, Active Distribution, the dozens of translators and designers and publishers who crafted their own versions of this project, the hundreds of donors who sponsored them, and <strong>you</strong> for distributing them.</p>

<p>We still have some loose ends to tie up. We have at least 14 more languages to add to the website. The <a href="http://www.crimethinc.com/podcast/">Ex-Worker</a> is about to release an audio version. Please <a href="mailto:rollingthunder@crimethinc.com">send us photos</a> of <em>To Change Everything</em> in action to illustrate our updates!</p>

<p>We’re still seeking translators and publishers to prepare additional versions of this project. We would love <a href="mailto:rollingthunder@crimethinc.com">to hear from comrades</a> in Indonesia, Japan, Australia, and elsewhere. The idea is for you to craft a version of <em>To Change Everything</em> adapted to your context and your ideas. Also, prisoner support groups may <a href="mailto:rollingthunder@crimethinc.com">request copies</a> postage-free while supplies last. To invite a delegation to present <em>To Change Everything</em> where you are, or to speak on anarchist ideas and strategy in general, <a href="mailto:rollingthunder@crimethinc.com">contact us</a>.</p>
]]></content_encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp_post_id>5397</wp_post_id>
		<wp_post_date><![CDATA[2015-01-15 12:12:24]]></wp_post_date>
		<wp_post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2015-01-15 20:12:24]]></wp_post_date_gmt>
		<wp_comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp_comment_status>
		<wp_ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp_ping_status>
		<wp_post_name><![CDATA[announcing-to-change-everything]]></wp_post_name>
		<wp_status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp_status>
		<wp_post_parent>0</wp_post_parent>
		<wp_menu_order>0</wp_menu_order>
		<wp_post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp_post_type>
		<wp_post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp_post_password>
		<wp_is_sticky>0</wp_is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="read-all-about-it"><![CDATA[Read All About It]]></category>
		<wp_postmeta>
			<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp_meta_key>
			<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp_meta_value>
		</wp_postmeta>
		<wp_postmeta>
			<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[_cws_is_markdown_gmt]]></wp_meta_key>
			<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[2015-01-16 18:27:09]]></wp_meta_value>
		</wp_postmeta>
		<wp_postmeta>
			<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[_cws_is_markdown]]></wp_meta_key>
			<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[2]]></wp_meta_value>
		</wp_postmeta>
		<wp_postmeta>
			<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[_thumbnail_id]]></wp_meta_key>
			<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[5405]]></wp_meta_value>
		</wp_postmeta>
		<wp_postmeta>
			<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[jumbo]]></wp_meta_key>
			<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[http://www.crimethinc.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/1b.jpg]]></wp_meta_value>
		</wp_postmeta>
		<wp_postmeta>
			<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[shorturl]]></wp_meta_key>
			<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[http://cwc.im/tceannounce]]></wp_meta_value>
		</wp_postmeta>
		<wp_postmeta>
			<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[_sd_is_markdown]]></wp_meta_key>
			<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp_meta_value>
		</wp_postmeta>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>2046</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[jd3162]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[jd3162@hotmail.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url/>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[181.1.29.106]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2015-01-26 09:56:14]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2015-01-26 17:56:14]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[Very excited about this project, but a few of the links in the "The Secret is to Begin" section are not functioning. I found the link to contact someone set up a speaking event, and the link labeled surveillance to both result in a "page not found error". Overall, a good collection of introductory materials, just though y'all should know.
Cheers.]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>4570</wp_comment_user_id>
			<wp_commentmeta>
				<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[akismet_result]]></wp_meta_key>
				<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[false]]></wp_meta_value>
			</wp_commentmeta>
			<wp_commentmeta>
				<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[akismet_history]]></wp_meta_key>
				<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[a:4:{s:4:"time";d:1422294974.6085948944091796875;s:7:"message";s:28:"Akismet cleared this comment";s:5:"event";s:9:"check-ham";s:4:"user";s:6:"jd3162";}]]></wp_meta_value>
			</wp_commentmeta>
		</wp_comment>
	</item>