<item>
    <title>The Miss Rockaway Armada Takes on Middle America</title>
    <link>http://www.crimethinc.com/blog/2006/08/15/the-miss-rockaway-armada-takes-on-middle-america/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2006 18:17:12 +0000</pubDate>
    <dc_creator><![CDATA[ret marut]]></dc_creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">http://crimethinc.com/blog/2006/08/15/the-miss-rockaway-armada-takes-on-middle-america/</guid>
    <description/>
    <content_encoded><![CDATA[<a href="#"class="smallitem"><img alt="model_back.jpg" id="image22" src="http://www.crimethinc.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2006/08/model_back.jpg" class="legacyimage"/></a>This August, <a target="_blank" href="http://www.missrockaway.org">we are taking a homemade floating monstrosity down the Mississippi</a>. When we started we didn’t know much about boats or rivers, and we didn’t have any money. (We know this is craziness, but if the idea makes your eyes glow like coals then you understand!) For several months we met, made phone calls, held benefits, and drew up blueprints. We collected scrap wood from all over and hammered it together piece by piece. We had benefit parties and socked away brown rice and dented cans. We organized mostly out of New York because that’s where we live, but we were joined by folks on the West coast as well as in the Midwest.

We met in Minneapolis in late July with sections of our raft in tow. We pieced together our pontoons and filled them with salvaged blocks of foam. We tie on anything that floats, adding it to our junk armada, our anarchist county fair, our fools ark. Our precious cargo is everything we hold dear: pieces and parts of the culture we are already creating. Our ’zines and puppets, sewing projects and poster campaigns. Our Nothing to Lose Navy musical review and amateur(!) variety show. Plus our thoughts and dreams and irrepressible energy.

<!--more-->

Our flotilla is built as green as we could muster with precycled materials, biodiesel, and solar. We’ve got a floating garden, a wind-powered movie theater, and a bicycle-propellered raft-lette. We want to steal hippie technology from the hippies.

We are a small group of people with extensive experience making big insane projects. In the past we have taken twenty-person bands to Mexico, pulled off town-square-sized guerrilla theater in Berlin, and fed hundreds of people with garbage and love. We know this idea is ridiculous and impossible. That’s why we’re obsessed with it.

We’ve just left Minneapolis (August 9) and are currently coasting down the Mississippi, but dates are hard—we don’t know how fast we’ll be moving. Follow our path on <a target="_blank" href="http://www.missrockaway.org">www.missrockaway.org</a>, or, better yet, get in contact with us by phone or by email. Between Minneapolis and St. Luis, we’re looking for places to play, shores to pull up to, people to eat with.]]></content_encoded>
    <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
    <wp_post_id>21</wp_post_id>
    <wp_post_date><![CDATA[2006-08-15 11:17:12]]></wp_post_date>
    <wp_post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2006-08-15 18:17:12]]></wp_post_date_gmt>
    <wp_comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp_comment_status>
    <wp_ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp_ping_status>
    <wp_post_name><![CDATA[the-miss-rockaway-armada-takes-on-middle-america]]></wp_post_name>
    <wp_status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp_status>
    <wp_post_parent>0</wp_post_parent>
    <wp_menu_order>0</wp_menu_order>
    <wp_post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp_post_type>
    <wp_post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp_post_password>
    <wp_is_sticky>0</wp_is_sticky>
    <category domain="category" nicename="calling-all-anarchists"><![CDATA[Calling All Anarchists]]></category>
    <wp_postmeta>
      <wp_meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp_meta_key>
      <wp_meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp_meta_value>
    </wp_postmeta>
    <wp_comment>
      <wp_comment_id>5</wp_comment_id>
      <wp_comment_author><![CDATA[thevillagemagazine]]></wp_comment_author>
      <wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[thevillagemagazine@yahoo.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
      <wp_comment_author_url>http://</wp_comment_author_url>
      <wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[70.226.226.112]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
      <wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2006-08-15 19:42:13]]></wp_comment_date>
      <wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2006-08-16 02:42:13]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
      <wp_comment_content><![CDATA[This sounds amazing.  My spouse saw something about this on a Progressive Islam site, and immediately thought, crimethinc!

I wish you all the good fortune in the bioregion.  I've been a river rat forever.  If you feel like sailing up the Illinois, up the unnavigable Sangamon, to the capitol of Illinois, we'd be glad to put you up for the night, and feed you some good grub.  There's nothing like floating down the muddy river.

sharqi]]></wp_comment_content>
      <wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
      <wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
      <wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
      <wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
    </wp_comment>
    <wp_comment>
      <wp_comment_id>6</wp_comment_id>
      <wp_comment_author><![CDATA[Jean Bonnot]]></wp_comment_author>
      <wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[open.vein@gmail.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
      <wp_comment_author_url>http://</wp_comment_author_url>
      <wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[70.107.64.194]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
      <wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2006-09-03 17:54:33]]></wp_comment_date>
      <wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2006-09-04 00:54:33]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
      <wp_comment_content><![CDATA[This is pathetic. Meet the new hippies. Well-funded avant garde artists do something unconventional. Stop the presses.]]></wp_comment_content>
      <wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
      <wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
      <wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
      <wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
    </wp_comment>
    <wp_comment>
      <wp_comment_id>7</wp_comment_id>
      <wp_comment_author><![CDATA[pfm]]></wp_comment_author>
      <wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[pfm@crimethinc.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
      <wp_comment_author_url>http://crimethinc.com/blog</wp_comment_author_url>
      <wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[65.102.21.146]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
      <wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2006-09-03 18:37:48]]></wp_comment_date>
      <wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2006-09-04 01:37:48]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
      <wp_comment_content><![CDATA[I agree, totally pathetic. They should be at home posting negative comments about other people's projects on other people's blogs. One more useless comment Jean, and that's it. Please only comment when you have something to contribute to the site.]]></wp_comment_content>
      <wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
      <wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
      <wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
      <wp_comment_user_id>1</wp_comment_user_id>
    </wp_comment>
    <wp_comment>
      <wp_comment_id>8</wp_comment_id>
      <wp_comment_author><![CDATA[Jean Bonnot]]></wp_comment_author>
      <wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[open.vein@gmail.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
      <wp_comment_author_url>http://</wp_comment_author_url>
      <wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[70.107.5.73]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
      <wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2006-09-03 22:46:59]]></wp_comment_date>
      <wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2006-09-04 05:46:59]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
      <wp_comment_content><![CDATA[Fine, I will offer constructive criticism.

Here are the problems I have with this project:

1) This group raised tens of thousands of dollars by selling hipster art to yuppies in New York. They then spent the money on a vacation for themselves. This is an essentially capitalist venture, and fundamentally partakes of the bourgeois leisure life-style.

2) It is presumptious for a group of trendy Brooklynites to think they are needed to bring culture to the supposedly ignorant and vacant middle part of the country. I find it condescending.

3) This project is explicitly apolitical. It makes no attempt at any kind of radicalism either in methodology or message. When people describe Crimethinc (and post-left anarchy generally) as "life-style politics" they are usually wrong; in this case they would be correct and the accused would not even bother to disagree.

4) This project reinforces rather than challenges mainstream cultural production. Rather than attacking a vulgar culture of representation, they only seek to spread it. They would rather make it into the MoMA (and they have), than tear it down.

I offer these thoughts, and my previous criticism, because post-left anarchy is in danger of becoming a parody of itself. If projects like this one are uncritically applauded everything will turn into Burning Man.  Whatever happened to "Live Dangerously"?]]></wp_comment_content>
      <wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
      <wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
      <wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
      <wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
    </wp_comment>
    <wp_comment>
      <wp_comment_id>9</wp_comment_id>
      <wp_comment_author><![CDATA[pfm]]></wp_comment_author>
      <wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[pfm@crimethinc.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
      <wp_comment_author_url>http://crimethinc.com/blog</wp_comment_author_url>
      <wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[65.102.21.146]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
      <wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2006-09-03 23:03:02]]></wp_comment_date>
      <wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2006-09-04 06:03:02]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
      <wp_comment_content><![CDATA[Jean, thanks for the explanation, glad to know that a little prodding can lead to better discussion. I don't feel like spending time to defending a project I am not involved with, but your comments are appreciated for their potential for provoking discussion and analysis.]]></wp_comment_content>
      <wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
      <wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
      <wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
      <wp_comment_user_id>1</wp_comment_user_id>
    </wp_comment>
    <wp_comment>
      <wp_comment_id>10</wp_comment_id>
      <wp_comment_author><![CDATA[someburke]]></wp_comment_author>
      <wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[someburke@yahoo.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
      <wp_comment_author_url>http://</wp_comment_author_url>
      <wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[129.72.74.130]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
      <wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2006-09-21 09:43:49]]></wp_comment_date>
      <wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2006-09-21 16:43:49]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
      <wp_comment_content><![CDATA[I've had some good conversations with some of the artists involved with this project and been pleasantly impressed. Also, I'm from the midwest originally, and spent a lot of time on the river there. In response to Jean's post, not all of them are from Brooklyn so the assumption that they are all trendy Brooklynites is off base. Second, I'm still fairly well connected to the area and I can say with conviction that nothing like  Miss Rockaway happens in central IL.  Calling it bringing culture to the ignorant, vacant part of the midwest does sound condescending, Jean. Sharing a rolling, enjoyable artwork which is an opportunity for people to connect with something new and pick up inspiration, perhaps, is something different.

Anyway, if you have any experience with the jumping carp in that area, they ARE living dangerously.]]></wp_comment_content>
      <wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
      <wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
      <wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
      <wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
    </wp_comment>
  </item>