<item>
    <title>NO PEACEFUL TRANSITION</title>
    <link>http://www.crimethinc.com/blog/2016/11/11/no-peaceful-transition/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2016 17:03:57 +0000</pubDate>
    <dc_creator><![CDATA[b. traven]]></dc_creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.crimethinc.com/blog/?p=6529</guid>
    <description/>
    <content_encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>&#35;DisruptJ20: Call for a bold mobilization against the inauguration of Donald Trump on January 20, 2017</strong></p>

<p>On Friday, January 20, 2017, Donald Trump will be inaugurated as President of the United States. We call on all people of good conscience to join in disrupting the ceremonies. If Trump is to be inaugurated at all, let it happen behind closed doors, showing the true face of the security state Trump will preside over. It must be made clear to the whole world that the vast majority of people in the United States do not support his presidency or consent to his rule. </p>

<p>Trump stands for tyranny, greed, and misogyny. He is the champion of neo-nazis and white Nationalists, of the police who kill the Black, Brown and poor on a daily basis, of racist border agents and sadistic prison guards, of the FBI and NSA who tap your phone and read your email. He is the harbinger of even more climate catastrophe, deportation, discrimination, and endless war. He continues to deny the existence of climate change, in spite of all the evidence, putting the future of the whole human race at stake. The KKK, Vladimir Putin, Golden Dawn, and the Islamic State all cheered his victory. If we let his inauguration go unchallenged, we are opening the door to the future they envision.</p>

<p>Trump’s success confirms the bankruptcy of representative democracy. Rather than using the democratic process as an alibi for inaction, we must show that no election could legitimize his agenda. Neither the Democrats nor any other political party or politician will save us—they just offer a weaker version of the same thing. If there is going to be positive change in this society, we have to make it ourselves, together, through direct action.</p>

<p>From day one, the Trump presidency will be a disaster. #DisruptJ20 will be the start of the resistance. We must take to the streets and protest, blockade, disrupt, intervene, sit in, walk out, rise up, and make more noise and good trouble than the establishment can bear. The parade must be stopped. We must delegitimize Trump and all he represents. It's time to defend ourselves, our loved ones, and the world that sustains us as if our lives depend on it—because they do. </p>

<h3>In Washington, DC </h3>

<p>DC will not be hospitable to the Trump administration. Every corporation must openly declare whether they side with him or with the people who will suffer at his hands. Thousands will converge and demonstrate resistance to the Trump regime. Save the date. A website will appear shortly with more details. #DisruptJ20</p>

<h3>Around the US</h3>

<p>If you can’t make it to Washington, DC on January 20, take to the streets wherever you are. We call on our comrades to organize demonstrations and other actions for the night of January 20. There is also a call for a general strike to take place. Organize a walkout at your school now. Workers: call out sick and take the day off. No work, no school, no shopping, no housework. #DisruptJ20</p>

<h3>Around the World</h3>

<p>If you are living outside the US, you can take action at US embassies, borders, or other symbols of neocolonial power. Our allegiance is not to “making America great again,” but to all of humanity and the planet. #DisruptJ20</p>

<p>Spread the word. Join the fight. #DisruptJ20
Facebook: <a href="http://tinyurl.com/disruptj20">http://tinyurl.com/disruptj20</a></p>

<p><em>Signed,</em></p>

<p>Agency
CrimethInc. Workers’ Collective
It's Going Down
subMedia
Earth First! Journal
AK Press
PM Press
Indigenous Action
New York Anarchist Action
The Base
NYC Anarchist Black Cross
Pittsburgh Autonomous Student Network
Pittsburgh Student Solidarity Coalition 
NightShade Pittsburgh
Pitt Against Debt
Pitt Students for a Democratic Society
Steel City (A) Team
UNControllables
Antifa Seven Hills
WNC Antifa
Asheville Anti-Racism
Black Rose Book Distro St. Louis
Resonance: An anarchist audio distro
Rose City Antifa
Torch Antifa Network
Central Oklahoma Black/Red Alliance (COBRA)
Sprout Distro
New Wave Army
Puget Sound Anarchist Black Cross
Four Corners Antifa
killedbypolice.net
Chicago Anarchist Black Cross
NYC Anarchist Book Fair
NYC ANARKOARTLAB
Autonomous Actions Against Prisons—Seattle
Antifa United
Denver Anarchist Black Cross
Loughborough Labour Party
Words as Weapons
Hackerñol
Stinney Distro
The Roosevelt Group
LeftSec/AnonAnarchistAction - i2p Darknet anarchohacker collective
Hispagatos - International hacking collective
Shades of Silence
Wildfire Anarchist Prison Newsletter
Students Without Borders
Solidarity Houston
South Florida Smash HLS
Students Against State Violence
Bloomington Solidarity Network
Anarquismo en PDF
Burning River Anarchist Distro
Lehigh Valley Vanguard
UNIDOS POR LA REFORMA
Rocky Mountain Antifa
Hudson Valley Anarchist Network
Proletarian Liberation Front
Agência de Notícias Anarquistas-ANA (Brazil)
Morgantown Ultra Left Network
New Brunswickers against Fracking
Art Haus of Albany
Black Powder Press
WorkersAssemble
Stand Up Fight Back
CopWatch Patrol Unit
Revolutionary Security Corps
L.I.F.E.E. Organization
Anonymous NYC
Mutiny Antarsya Tempe
Flatirons Anarchist Alliance
Redneck Revolt
Anarchist Initiative Ljubljana (Slovenia)
Hampton Roads Justice Network
Sword of Spartacus
Olympia General Membership Branch of the IWW
gROUPSELF Kollektive
Firestorm Books and Café
The Autonomous Womyn's Front
Revolutionary Road Radio show
Revolutionary Caucus of Tampa Bay
The Refuge
wakeATL
St. Louis Antifa
SkrubSec
Direct Action Monterey Network
Ottawa Antifa
Black Rose Federation
International of Anarchist Federations (IAF-IFA)
SUB-ANTIFA (Indonesia)
Black Autonomy Federation
(Anti-)German CrimethInc. Cell
Black Mosquito (Germany)</p>

<p>If you endorse this call, sign your name at the bottom of this list and circulate it. Email <a href="mailto:disruptj20@riseup.net">disruptj20@riseup.net</a> to be included in the above list.</p>

<div name="video" id="video" style="width: 630px; display: block; float: left; clear: both; margin: 0px 0px 0px -145px !important; padding: 5px 0px 15px 0px !important;">
<iframe src="//player.vimeo.com/video/191197865" width="630" height="354" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div>
]]></content_encoded>
    <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
    <wp_post_id>6529</wp_post_id>
    <wp_post_date><![CDATA[2016-11-11 09:03:57]]></wp_post_date>
    <wp_post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2016-11-11 17:03:57]]></wp_post_date_gmt>
    <wp_comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp_comment_status>
    <wp_ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp_ping_status>
    <wp_post_name><![CDATA[no-peaceful-transition]]></wp_post_name>
    <wp_status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp_status>
    <wp_post_parent>0</wp_post_parent>
    <wp_menu_order>0</wp_menu_order>
    <wp_post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp_post_type>
    <wp_post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp_post_password>
    <wp_is_sticky>0</wp_is_sticky>
    <category domain="category" nicename="calling-all-anarchists"><![CDATA[Calling All Anarchists]]></category>
    <wp_postmeta>
      <wp_meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp_meta_key>
      <wp_meta_value><![CDATA[2]]></wp_meta_value>
    </wp_postmeta>
    <wp_postmeta>
      <wp_meta_key><![CDATA[_sd_is_markdown]]></wp_meta_key>
      <wp_meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp_meta_value>
    </wp_postmeta>
    <wp_postmeta>
      <wp_meta_key><![CDATA[_thumbnail_id]]></wp_meta_key>
      <wp_meta_value><![CDATA[6531]]></wp_meta_value>
    </wp_postmeta>
    <wp_postmeta>
      <wp_meta_key><![CDATA[jumbo]]></wp_meta_key>
      <wp_meta_value><![CDATA[http://www.crimethinc.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/1b-2.jpg]]></wp_meta_value>
    </wp_postmeta>
  </item>