<item>
		<title>CrimethInc. ex-Workers’ Collective Humbly Requests Clearance to Resume Activity</title>
		<link>http://www.crimethinc.com/blog/2007/11/09/crimethinc-ex-workers-collective-humbly-requests-clearance-to-resume-activity/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Nov 2007 17:36:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc_creator><![CDATA[b. traven]]></dc_creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.crimethinc.com/blog/2007/11/09/crimethinc-ex-workers%e2%80%99-collective-humbly-requests-clearance-to-resume-activity/</guid>
		<description/>
		<content_encoded><![CDATA[<em>submitted by CWC supernumerary B. Traven, on behalf of the Far East cell</em>

Inveterate comrades and enemies—

It’s been a full three years since our last <a href="http://www.crimethinc.com/books/rfd.html">outlandishly ambitious project</a>, and you may be wondering what became of us. Sure, we started <a href="http://www.crimethinc.com/rt/">a magazine</a> and did a couple <a href="http://www.greenscare.org/" target="_blank">Green Scare</a> benefit projects, but that hardly compares to the high-water mark of our activity in the past. Have we finally accepted that we will not change the world? Are we out of ideas?

We’re excited to report that over the past year, while we seemed to be slowing down, we were actually preparing a new wave of activity—which will commence at the end of this month with the publication of our next book. The projects we are about to debut are by far our most ambitious yet… but first, let’s discuss what happened last time we initiated a wave of activity.

Remember the <a href="http://www.infoshop.org/inews/article.php?story=02/09/20/5450990&amp;type=article&amp;order=ASC&amp;mode=nested&amp;page=2" target="_blank">bitter and messy controversies</a> of 2001-2003? Every CrimethInc. project that appeared was greeted by thoughtless accolades and torrents of abuse. CrimethInc. was a herd of trust fund brats bent on draining all content from the anarchist movement, an army of wastrels wrecking radical institutions from one coast to the other, a bunch of street thugs determined to endanger peaceful protesters, a single sexist middle class white boy who had apparently never heard the word “privilege” before. The defenses this slander provoked from the party faithful were often just as off-base. All you had to do was say the word “dumpster” and the aspersions commenced flying.

<!--more-->

There are several ways to interpret all this negativity. Maybe it was the inevitable turn to infighting that followed the decline of the anticapitalist movement, or the consequence of a new influx of inexperienced participants into the anarchist struggle, or backlash from stodgy veterans who feared they were being outshined. Perhaps it’s inevitable that those who offer themselves to the public as a projection screen receive every kind of unconstructive criticism and misdirected praise.

With the benefit of hindsight, it was a tempest in a teapot—a waste of energy. Those who wished to pull us kicking and screaming from the stage of history only made us more notorious; people who had much more important things to do were dragged into the fray; and we, who wished to use all our time and creativity to contest hierarchy, squandered them defending ourselves from fellow would-be revolutionaries. Internal critique and debate are essential to building communities of resistance, but name-calling and misinformation are equally disabling.

Let’s hope it’s easier to discuss this now that the smoke has cleared and tempers have cooled. Stalwarts who were as loath to accept us into the anarchist fold as we were to join it have now become our friends; others are at least resigned to putting up with us. We’ve learned a great deal, no thanks to all that drama, and perhaps everyone else has, too. Who knows what drama awaits us ahead—such is our doom, having chosen this path. But while there’s still time, here’s one more effort to clarify our basic goals, lest our new efforts again be mistaken as attempts to hijack The Anarchist Movement or glorify ourselves at everyone else’s expense.

Our essential project is to nurture anti-authoritarian consciousness and desires outside the traditional sites of workplace organizing and identity politics. This does not mean we consider those sites unimportant, or that we wish for everyone to prioritize the sites we have chosen based on our own specific circumstances and means. We’re not convinced we have the most or only effective approach; on the contrary, we are grateful others are undertaking other experiments in other settings—it frees us to focus on the ones we’ve chosen.

If we have any criticism to offer our comrades, it is only that we seem to have been so much more successful in our context than some of them have in theirs. This is strange, given that other contexts should lend themselves to a hundred times more activity than ours does—we’re hardly reaching every potential dropout and rioter, but we fear we are doing better at this than others are at spreading anarchist commitments to the entire working class. We leave it to them to sort out how to improve their efforts, and hope our modest achievements can spur them to more impressive ones.

But this is not a contest. If you feel what we’re doing is a mistaken use of our apparently inexhaustible energies, please offer useful criticism, while trusting that we’re best situated to know what makes sense for us. We are revolutionary anarchists determined to bring about the seizure of the means of production and the abolition of all hierarchy, not bourgeois “lifestylists” as our foes have disingenuously charged. Friendly, constructive criticism will greatly aid us in being better allies to others who desire the same things. The best way to approach this is by making suggestions as to how we could better work towards our professed goals that take into account our capabilities and preferences.

The constructive critiques we’ve received thus far have been instrumental in improving our efforts. Unfortunately, there are still many things we would like to focus on that we are not yet equipped to do justice to; if we remain silent on some topics, it is generally because we feel others are doing a better job than we could. We ask that comrades interpret the many glaring absences in our activities simply as endorsements of others’ efforts—and work to make up for our omissions where they see fit.

But what if you’re the sort of critic who has nothing constructive to offer? In that case, you’re welcome ignore us—if you really think we are a scourge that must be eradicated, don’t give us free publicity. If you absolutely can’t resist stooping to attacks, please don’t sic novices on us <a href="http://www.anarkismo.net/newswire.php?story_id=3664" target="_blank">who can neither read nor spell, who build and tear apart straw men the way others play with toy soldiers</a>. If such screeds must be written, we request the task be entrusted to Wayne Price from NEFAC, whose intelligent analyses have impressed us—though Wayne obviously has better things to do, as all of you should.

It might also be a good idea to double-check the accuracy of statements before printing them—when making claims about the demographics and nationalities involved in CrimethInc. activity, for example. It beggars belief that people who cannot even be troubled to do a Google search feel entitled to brush off not only the efforts of hundreds around the world, but also the possibility that they even exist—in the course of purporting to represent their interests, no less!

For our part, we don’t aim to “represent” anyone. We understand that, given our disproportionate access to the media, many would like to see us tell their stories or focus on their chosen issues, but we maintain that it would be a mistake to saddle any publisher with the responsibility of even-handedly representing the entire anarchist milieu. To take on this task would only trap us in a role we could not possibly fill—that no one could ever fill, if our critique of representational politics is correct—and effectively prevent us from filling any other role, as well. We are anarchists—we believe in self-determination, not representation, and the only way to secure that for all is to radically decentralize the means of expression. This demands the abolition of mass media as we know it, including most of the formats we have used thus far—not collectives like ours becoming mediators that choose who gets to speak and for how long. In the meantime, we renew our offer to assist anyone with the process of self-publishing.

Likewise, we’re not interested in attempting to capture reality—we’re not theorists who think we’ve worked out The Truth and have to explain it to everyone else. As far as we’re concerned, such a thing is neither possible nor desirable, and purporting to do so only entraps a person in endless debates with subscribers to other Truths. Anarchist theory as a cockfight with our critiques as extensions of our egos does not interest us. That kind of ideological sparring doesn’t seem to aid the participants in bringing about their own liberation—unless reactionaries are correct that one can recognize a zone of freedom by the pointless internecine warfare going on within it. Worst of all, it tends to reduce the discussion of anarchist possibilities to private grudge matches carried out in an inaccessibly abstruse jargon few can—or desire to—understand.

Our sole aim, our raison d'être, is to create situations that have liberatory potential. That is the purpose of all the books and posters and convergences. In and of themselves, they are worthless, irrelevant—but if they enable people to live moments of freedom, whether individually for instants or together over the course of decades, then we have succeeded. We ask to be judged by this criterion alone.

<strong>Appendix: <em>Evasion’s</em> Biggest Fan</strong>

The following is a true story, though you’ll have to take our word for it as we are not authorized to name the protagonists. A certain dedicated class war anarchist, who distinguished himself in local organizing and mass mobilizations around the turn of the century, was among that era’s most outspoken critics of CrimethInc. projects. In his chapter of a well-known anarchist federation, he told his comrades that it was up to them to fight CrimethInc. for the future of the anarchist movement.

Years later, he admitted to one of us that he’d secretly obtained a copy of <em>Evasion</em> when it was published in book form and, though he considered it politically execrable, became obsessed with it. He’d bought it to study the propaganda of the enemies of the working class, but it turned out it was one of the most thrilling action stories he’d ever read! Worse yet, he passed it around to friends, and they all had similar reactions—they became a sort of secret reading group, since they had to hide their passion for the book from their anarcho-communist comrades. At one point they even got themselves into a messy situation trying to imitate the narrator of the book, when they attempted a heist from a grocery store without abiding by any of the security tips that pervade CrimethInc. literature.

The ex-worker to whom all this was confided found it perplexing, to say the least. In his view, <em>Evasion</em> was not particularly well-written or exciting; the humor compensated for the lack of plot and character development, but the subject matter was positively banal. The point of printing it had been to undermine materialism and timidity in a readership infected with bourgeois values, not to produce a great work of literature—let alone offer a universal model for anarchist struggle, as the anti-CrimethInc. camp framed things. The class war anarchist’s urgent inquiries as to when an <em>Evasion</em> sequel might be published were amusing—wasn’t this the same person who had decried the book with such vitriol?

This is a funny anecdote, but at second glance it reads like heavy-handed allegory. Human beings are attracted to forbidden things; nothing is more seductive than transgression. The class war anarchists in question, doubly bound by the repressive property laws of capitalist society and the moral and theoretical prescriptions of their organization, could not help but be drawn to <em>Evasion</em>—just as the dropout who had helped publish it regarded it as utterly mundane. Because they never dealt with the political implications of their fascination with the book, their lives remained comically divided into competing sectors: permissible versus impermissible, responsible versus pleasurable, public versus private.

Such divisions are redolent of the Protestant morality that has propped up capitalism for so long. If the class warriors had been able to affirm the excitement they experienced in reading <em>Evasion</em> and find ways to make their political work similarly seductive to others, would that not have been better for everyone? Far be it from us to argue that embracing CrimethInc. literature is the solution to every class war anarchist’s difficulties—the point is simply that it doesn’t pay to heap up prohibitions and antagonisms. We would like to see more overcoming of divisions in the anarchist community generally, in hopes that it will help us ultimately bring down capitalism and Protestant morality alike. It is in that spirit that we initiate our new round of activity.]]></content_encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp_post_id>153</wp_post_id>
		<wp_post_date><![CDATA[2007-11-09 10:36:37]]></wp_post_date>
		<wp_post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2007-11-09 17:36:37]]></wp_post_date_gmt>
		<wp_comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp_comment_status>
		<wp_ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp_ping_status>
		<wp_post_name><![CDATA[crimethinc-ex-workers-collective-humbly-requests-clearance-to-resume-activity]]></wp_post_name>
		<wp_status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp_status>
		<wp_post_parent>0</wp_post_parent>
		<wp_menu_order>0</wp_menu_order>
		<wp_post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp_post_type>
		<wp_post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp_post_password>
		<wp_is_sticky>0</wp_is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="read-all-about-it"><![CDATA[Read All About It]]></category>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>270</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[brib]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[blackredisbeautiful@gmail.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url>http://brib.wordpress.com</wp_comment_author_url>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[84.62.132.190]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2007-11-09 11:42:27]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2007-11-09 18:42:27]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[Iam an hardcore class-war syndicalist and got all crimethinc books in my bookshelf, love them and translate them into my native language. Of course I don't agree with everything but I don't agree with all class-war/syndicalist postions either ;)]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>271</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[crudo]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[modanarcho@yahoo.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url>http://www.geocities.com/anarcho209</wp_comment_author_url>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[130.17.62.238]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2007-11-09 16:59:05]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2007-11-09 23:59:05]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[Jesus Christ people can be stupid. 

"Fight crimethinc for the anarchist movement?"  

As a "class war anarchist", my response to this is a serious rolling of the eyes.  

Personally I don't see how you can be an anarchist and not be "class war", since I see anarchism as striving for the creation of a stateless and class society.  

I think Crimethink's success to two fold. 

First, the stuff that they produce people like to read.  They also produce stickers and multimedia stuff, thus making the project even more noticeable.  I was on the road the other day and I saw some guys work truck and it had a crimethinc sticker on it.  I about shit myself and started laughing.  He kind of gave me a weird look; didn't look like a punk or traveler or whatever. 

Second, there's a lot of crimethinc stuff out there.  Every anarchist has it.  There's a lot floating around.  Like the crimethinc post on infoshop said, crimethinc has become the pole that the rest of the anarchist movement revolves around.  

I think some anarchists take this as an attack on 'real anarchism' when they seem to be missing the point that regular people actually often like crimethinc.  Often class war politics have become "boring as fuck", when they could be exciting, rough and tough, and funny, (take for instance, the UK newspaper and ground, Class War).  I think a lot of 'class war' anarchists, (who often come from priveledged backgrounds themselves) can't stand the thought that regular people actually like stuff that goes against platformist or syndicalist lines.  For instance, I would wager, that a publication like Green Anarchy, with a circulation of around 6-8,000, and a subcription to 800 prisoners, probably is read by more working class people than perhaps most of the 'class war' anarchist publications.  Same might be said about Rolling Thunder.  

When I was getting into anarchism, as were a lot of my working/lower middle class peers, crimethinc and punk rock were both big influences. 

The problem is not crimethinc fucking up class war politics and thus fucking up anarchism, the problem is class war anarchists having a hard time being able to articulate their ideas to a large audience in the same way that crimethinc is able to.  

Another point I'd like to bring up is the point about dropping out and class struggle.  Most the anti-authoritarian, anti-state communist, anarchist 'heroes' were drop outs, travelers, and rebels.  Get over it!  The difference between Evasion and most of the other anarchist drop outs is that they used their free time to fight the rich, not just eat well.]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>272</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[everything4every1]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[hadda.b.playin@gmail.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url/>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[58.179.238.168]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2007-11-09 19:20:53]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2007-11-10 03:20:53]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA["Evasion was not particularly well-written or exciting; the humor compensated for the lack of plot and character development, but the subject matter was positively banal."

Amen. I love a lot of what Crimethinc does but this book was boring. I have friends who loved it, but to me it seemed like nothing happened. Plus the amount of privilege possessed by the author(s) was problematic for me. I thought it was going to be a story of someone who worked out how to survive on their own. Which to a degree he did, but the amount of times he relied on support from family or free houses from wealthy friends made it infinitely less inspiring. I know people who've responded to this criticism like "yeah, I don't want to be bum, I just don't want to pay rent." I feel like, no shit? Nobody wants to pay rent, even (perhaps especially) the people who let you sleep on their couch while you contributing nothing in return. 

So for me the book was uninspiring, slightly depressing and banal. That said, I feel like Crimethinc's other projects are very important. I love the crap out of the DVD and the Cookbook. Which brings me to the point made about “self-determination, not representation”, but I think that's a politically loaded way to represent what could otherwise be characterized as sharing. For instance you've got Vol.2 of the DVD coming out. 

I would love to see two things on this DVD. 
1. A film with a woman narrating or featuring heavily. There are few women in any of the films of volume one and the narration on the short film about the people locked themselves in that warehouse to make instruments is painful to listen to due to the amount of times the male narrators cut of the woman narrator. 
2. Something about Sherman Austin and the whole RaiseTheFist incident. I don't live in the US so it's hard to tell but it seems like this was/is one of the biggest Anarchist of Colour stories happening. Sherman’s doing great stuff with a cop-watch program now which would be useful to make the story seem a bit fresher. 

I chose these two things to address the white male dominance in Crimethinc's literature. I would not think of this as trying to represent People of colour or Women, but to share some of the resources your privileges have allowed Crimethinc to acquire. It didn’t seem like Crimethinc were the main people involved in all the videos on Vol. 1 either, particularly the Miami Model. So it seems to me that whether you admit it or not you are already “mediators that choose who gets to speak and for how long.” Denying this does not make it disapear, it only serves to conceal the privileges you hold. 

Oooh, plus I just remembered, I loved the community garden part of the Miami model, and think there should be more of that next time.]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>273</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[WapsiWilly]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[WapsiWilly@gmail.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url/>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[207.177.64.252]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2007-11-09 20:25:02]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2007-11-10 03:25:02]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[I'm a construction worker from a long line of proles and lumpen, with an almost instinctive distaste for the wealthy and a soul-to-skin hatred for the parasitic-attack-dog-house-nigger/judenrat pieces of shit who exist to remove people like me from their scenic backdrops, and I had never even heard of "class war" anarchism until I met a bourgeois college student who identified himself as such. Nice guy though. He told me that from the circles he debates in the main criticism of CrimethInc is that it doesn't appeal to the working class. Probably because most Crimethinc texts avoid the academic trap of talking about "the working class" as an abstract thing as if we are not part of the damn conversation.

I should however submit the constructive criticism that A) a lot of propaganda(and some discussions) romanticizing traveling, squating, etc. gives me the some hollow longing for the fulfillment of desires that are not my own that I got back in the day when I watched tv and was bombarded with images of happy people buying useless shit. 
And B) Being cold hungry and unemployed is probably way more fun when you choose it.

I don't want to travel the world and not work, I want to kick this gift economy off. I want to bust my ass on projects I care about for people I love and fall asleep with aching muscles softly saying 'you've done wel and are stronger for it,'  the red light of a setting sun on my face and the smell of dirt in my nose.]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>274</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[impact]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[electriczer0@yahoo.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url>http://</wp_comment_author_url>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[71.139.43.36]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2007-11-10 14:55:14]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2007-11-10 21:55:14]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[here here wapsi. With a hammer in one hand and a rifle in the other lets see what kind of world we can make.]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>275</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[xdx]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[yoshomon@yahoo.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url>http://printxculture.blogspot.com</wp_comment_author_url>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[74.140.149.31]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2007-11-11 21:54:49]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2007-11-12 04:54:49]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[Evasion is a glowing testament to the joy and beauty of the vegan straightedge,  the best book Crimethinc has published, and a shining light to drug-free criminal youth everywhere.  The storm is coming...]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>276</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[xdx]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[yoshomon@yahoo.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url>http://printxculture.blogspot.com</wp_comment_author_url>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[207.246.115.13]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2007-11-16 10:39:20]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2007-11-16 17:39:20]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[Responses to this article on libcom:

http://libcom.org/forums/crimethinc-hit-back-me-libcom-years-later-16112007]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>277</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[Sewer]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[evilmonkeys23@gmail.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url/>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[71.179.114.30]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2008-09-09 05:55:23]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2008-09-09 12:55:23]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA["I've never been detached enough to recognize the sound so exactly before.  It's a raw-throated sound, a grating, insistent sound, a sound born out of all the insults swallowed, the battles lost, out of all the smothered dreams and desires.  Three thousand collective years of frustration in the room, turning inward, a *cancer* of frustration.  It's the sound of parents brawling each other because they can't feed their kids, the sound of prisoners preying on each other because the guards are out of reach, the sound of a terribly deep despair.  No quiet desperation for us, not while we have a voice left.  Over an hour it lasts, the sniping, the shouting, the accusations and countercharges.  I want to eat.  I want to go home.  I want to cry."

--from The Anarchists' Convention by John Sayles


Perhaps that passage can help to explain why so much of our energy goes into bickering and squabbling with each other.  

Me, well, I'm a die-hard, card-carrying class warrior with politics so boring-as-fuck they'd make Kropotkin proud.  I have been ever since the tender age of 11, when I met a Bangladeshi woman whose son had been shot and killed because she tried to organize a union in her factory.  That jolted my ass awake like a foreman's slap in the face.  I've knew I wanted to be part of the labor movement ever since.

During my limited experience in the anarchist scene, I've made a lot of friends who love CrimethInc and say their lives were forever changed by Days of War (it was a pleasure getting locked up with you in St. Paul, by the way...you know who you are.)  I've also befriended a lot of fellow class struggle reds.  This, as you might expect, has earned me a copious amount of shit-talking from both sides of the aisle.  Which is unfortunate, because I think each group could learn something from the other.

No pack of lefties--not even NEFAC, and we've got the sage wisdom of Grandaddy Wayne Price behind us--has been as prolific, poetic, and entertaining with their writings as y'all have.  I'm sure you're well aware of that, and your cries of "outdo us!" are appreciated.  As a friend of mine wrote, "whatever your opinion of Crimethinc's politics, you have to give them credit for helping revitalizing two very vital traditions of radical writing: on the one hand, they've kicked out enough all-encompassing, no-holds-barred, just barely still prose polemical manifestos to make Guy Debord proud, on the other hand, they've also produced some stunning personal narratives of living free in the boxcars and margins of late capitalism."

The Reds, however, understand one very obvious yet exceedingly important thing, something I believe you have often declared without fully grasping its implications: anarchy is for EVERYONE!  Our ideals are too vital to the struggle for human freedom to be the exclusive domain of people who want to be part of a particular social phenomenon; to quit work, hop trains, and make record players out of old bikes.  We need to be wherever the embers of social conflict start to burn, voicing our ideas as we fight alongside people who may not identify as anarchists.  Maybe this critique sounds hackneyed and trite by now, but I think it's still valid.  I don't know if I'm being unfair to CrimethInc anarchists from areas other than mine, but throughout all my activism (with workers struggling to win more control over their lives through labor unions, with homeless-led groups fighting to keep a shelter open, and with high-schoolers who started the biggest student strike in my city's history) it's always been my black &amp; red comrades who were there to support me, motivate me, cheer on the victories beside me, and comfort me through the losses.  I am also constantly amazed by how eager people involved in these fights are to talk and dream about revolution.  Anarchy is too important to be left to the anarchists.]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
	</item>