<item>
		<title>“Expect Resistance” Stickers Retired</title>
		<link>http://www.crimethinc.com/blog/2007/11/18/expect-resistance-stickers-retired/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2007 00:04:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc_creator><![CDATA[b. traven]]></dc_creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.crimethinc.com/blog/2007/11/18/%e2%80%9cexpect-resistance%e2%80%9d-stickers-retired/</guid>
		<description/>
		<content_encoded><![CDATA[“Look, we can’t name it that—we already printed how many fucking stickers with that on them? If we use that for the book, too, it’ll seem like we’re out of ideas.”

“And do you have a better idea? That’s the only name any of us have been able to agree on, and we’ve been arguing for months. If I’m not going to live to see anarchist revolution, let’s at least finish this book. We’ve already had this conversation. I really think it’s the only good option we have.”

“If you’re serious, hear me out about the stickers.”

“Go ahead.”

<!--more-->

“It’s going to seem like they were a marketing ploy all along: ‘You read the sticker—now buy the book!’ When we made them, we weren’t talking about a fucking book—they’re supposed to go up next to smashed windows, or in high schools before walkouts. It’s insulting to people who used the stickers in good faith to retroactively turn them into a promotional campaign. I don’t want anyone to feel like a dupe.”

“Don’t think that hasn’t occurred to me—and sure, it sucks. But we don’t have any other titles for this, at least nothing that would work. And really, it sounds like you’re concerned about our ‘good name.’ We’re doing this as CrimethInc., not some earnest political party seeking converts. Everything we do is propaganda—better that’s obvious, so people approach us with a healthy suspicion and consider the ideas on their merits alone.”

“I’m not convinced. I agree that if we position ourselves as 'representatives' of our ideas, so we're responsible for selling them with our own irreproachable conduct, we’ll end up as incapable and inauthentic as fucking politicians. At the same time, I fear the kind of ‘branding’ that would result from naming the book after that sticker could undercut our ability to say anything at all. Corporations are already far ahead of us in that regard, and it just breeds cynicism, not healthy suspicion. If ‘resistance’ refers to a mass-produced book rather than unique acts of defiance, it’s that much more difficult to begin the conversation about what there is beyond books.”

“When I think about it, it’s ironic you’re worried about ruining a sticker with a book, rather than the other way around! I’d think a book could only improve on a sticker, not empty it of meaning.”

“You’re thinking that a book is better than a sticker because a lot of words can fill out a few words. But you can’t give meaning to words with more words—only actions can do that. This is the internet era—everyone in the US is totally debilitated by all that empty free speech. The higher the proportion of action to words, the better.”

“But you know we can’t act ‘as CrimethInc.’—especially not with all the scrutiny we’re under right now. CrimethInc. has always been a false front to put ideas out there that have to be filled out by the actions of real people. You can’t possibly be saying we shouldn’t publish this book, that we should just make stickers!”

“We’re getting off the subject. I think we should do the book—I’m just not convinced it’s a good idea to use that title, however perfect it is for the content.”

“You know you’re the only holdout, right? We’re going to have harder decisions than this ahead.”

“If there’s no other way, I’ll stand aside—but on one condition: we'd have to stop making those stickers.”

“I’m sure everybody would be OK with that. We'll send out all the one's we've already made and then no more. You write the announcement and we can put it up when the book’s done.”]]></content_encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp_post_id>161</wp_post_id>
		<wp_post_date><![CDATA[2007-11-18 17:04:05]]></wp_post_date>
		<wp_post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2007-11-19 00:04:05]]></wp_post_date_gmt>
		<wp_comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp_comment_status>
		<wp_ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp_ping_status>
		<wp_post_name><![CDATA[expect-resistance-stickers-retired]]></wp_post_name>
		<wp_status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp_status>
		<wp_post_parent>0</wp_post_parent>
		<wp_menu_order>0</wp_menu_order>
		<wp_post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp_post_type>
		<wp_post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp_post_password>
		<wp_is_sticky>0</wp_is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="internal-memos"><![CDATA[Internal Memos]]></category>
		<wp_postmeta>
			<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[_thumbnail_id]]></wp_meta_key>
			<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[3310]]></wp_meta_value>
		</wp_postmeta>
		<wp_postmeta>
			<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp_meta_key>
			<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp_meta_value>
		</wp_postmeta>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>295</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[Jean Bonnot]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[open.vein@gmail.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url>http://</wp_comment_author_url>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[24.189.14.89]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2007-11-19 00:12:10]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2007-11-19 07:12:10]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[What's with all the wordy, self-reflective essays lately?

You manufactured a secretive, superhero aura for yourselves over years of behind the scenes work, which amplified and complimented your propaganda marvelously, and now you've voluntarily pulled back the curtain to reveal something like an anarchist version of Woody Allen. Stop worrying so much about your critics. People like you; calm down.]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>296</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[rk]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[2600denver@gmail.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url>http://</wp_comment_author_url>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[75.71.157.234]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2007-11-19 00:38:55]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2007-11-19 08:38:55]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[I happen to love all of the self-reflective business. I agree with the decision to pull the stickers, although it's unfortunate to lose these stickers. I loved them. I assume you still have a big stash laying around. I'm about to put in an order for some other, I can contribute $5-$10 for some of the leftovers. Maybe it would have been a good idea to ask people on the blog what a good title would be. I had a few I could have added. But whatever, keep doing your good work. It's amazing and always has been.
Comrade RK]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>297</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[rechelon]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[rechelon@riseup.net]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url>http://williamgillis.blogspot.com/</wp_comment_author_url>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[141.140.120.129]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2007-11-19 14:56:45]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2007-11-19 21:56:45]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[This is pretty much the quintessential discussion process that makes anarchists anarchists.  You can read all the pretty books you like, ride the rails clear across the americas and wear the most hardcore of class war patches, but this sorta conversation is the beating heart of the anarchist experience.  Anyway, I laughed.  But it's always nice when Crimethinc breaks the facade and shows an honest moment.  The self-critique released after the last convergence gave me a bit of pride in the whole project, and this was nice too.

...Although it DOES totally suck that long-lasting stickers I put up have now transformed from declarations of insurrection to book advertisements.]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
		<wp_comment>
			<wp_comment_id>298</wp_comment_id>
			<wp_comment_author><![CDATA[WapsiWilly]]></wp_comment_author>
			<wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[WapsiWilly@gmail.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
			<wp_comment_author_url/>
			<wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[207.177.64.252]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
			<wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2007-11-19 18:24:38]]></wp_comment_date>
			<wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2007-11-20 01:24:38]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
			<wp_comment_content><![CDATA[This is OK but if the "They don't give a fuck about you" stickers go then I go. And could you sell those in bulk? I have a hard time finding places they don't belong.]]></wp_comment_content>
			<wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
			<wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
			<wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
			<wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
		</wp_comment>
	</item>