<item>
    <title>Fighting for Our Lives in Action</title>
    <link>http://www.crimethinc.com/blog/2007/11/23/fighting-for-our-lives-in-action/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2007 18:15:58 +0000</pubDate>
    <dc_creator><![CDATA[ret marut]]></dc_creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.crimethinc.com/blog/2007/11/23/fighting-for-our-lives-in-action/</guid>
    <description/>
    <content_encoded><![CDATA[<em>Here's a testimonial of sorts, demonstrating the proper use of a copy of </em><a href="/tools/ffol.html">Fighting for Our Lives</a><em>. There are 500,000 of them in print, which really isn't that many when you consider that there are over 26,000 active nuclear warheads worldwide. Please make every single copy count!

While we are about to release a book to be followed shortly by a new issue of our journal, it will be some months before we are able to debut any new free material. In the meantime, </em>Fighting for Our Lives<em> is still available <a href="http://store.crimethinc.com/x/free.html">free of charge</a>, individually or in bulk.</em>

In the fall, there was a secret cafe at Station 40. I worked as a server with my housemates, carrying amazing food through a crowded room of friends watching performers in a burlesque show. It was one of those nights where all the familiar faces that you haven't seen for a while appear, and everyone has an expression like "Why don't we all hang out like we used to anymore?'' When things were almost over, I ran into Darci—an old friend I've known off and on for almost six years. She's the kind of friend who's unpredictable in that way that's almost always incredibly exciting, but which would probably become frustrating if she were a bigger part of my life. We caught up on where we'd been, what our hopes were, and everything that had gone wrong for us since we last saw each-other. She introduced me to her friends Chelsea and Tracy, and invited me to come back over to the East Bay with them for a party.

<!--more-->

So we got on the BART, and I sat down in one of the bike seats with Darci--our bikes resting on our legs--while Chelsea and Tracy sat down in the bike seat on the opposite side of the aisle.

I looked down and noticed a copy of <em>Fighting For Our Lives</em> on our seat. I picked it up and asked "Hey, is this yours?" to the people who had just gotten up and were on their way out. They looked at me, shook their heads, mumbled something, then disappeared out the door. I showed it to Darci, saying "Can you believe that I just found a copy of <em>Fighting For Our Lives</em> on the seat? There are probably more copies of these than people in the world." She looked over and asked "What is it?"

"Wait, you've never seen this?" I replied. She shook her head.

I held it up to Tracy and Chelsea across the aisle, "Have you guys seen this before?"

"Nope" they both responded.

I handed it to Darci, and she opened it to the "Overture" on the first page. She read the first aphorism loudly and enthusiastically to Chelsea and Tracy across the way: "We dropped out of school, got divorced, broke with our families and ourselves and everything we'd known!" She paused, and I jumped in to read the next aphorism aloud: "We quit our jobs, violated our leases, threw all our furniture out on the sidewalk, and hit the road!" We read a few of these back and forth, then realized that we were probably being obnoxious and stopped. I looked up, and noticed that everyone on our half of this very crowded BART car was looking at us in silence. One guy sitting a little ways away broke the silence and spoke up: "Keep reading!"

So Darci and I read the entire overture back and forth. I ended up reading the last bit pretty enthusiastically: "I'm speaking, of course, of anarchists ... When we fight, we're fighting for our lives!" And at that, almost everyone on our half of the BART car suddenly broke out into loud applause. Some people even cheered. Some stood up to clap.

A middle-aged guy walked over and asked "What was that paper you were reading?" "Oh, it's a CrimethInc. paper called <em>Fighting For Our Lives</em>. Have you heard of CrimethInc.?" "No, I haven't." "Well, they have a website - crimethinc.com." "I need to write that down, I don't think I'll remember it," he said while fruitlessly patting his pockets.

I reached into my pocket, but instead of a pen, all I found was a sharpie marker. I opened it and wrote "C R I M E T H I N C . C O M" across the length of his forearm in big letters. He smiled and thanked me. As he walked away, I saw another guy walk up to him, look at what I'd written on his forearm, take out a pen, and write crimethinc.com on his own hand as well.

Spontaneity always has a way of surprising you by being more effective than calculated planning ever could.]]></content_encoded>
    <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
    <wp_post_id>163</wp_post_id>
    <wp_post_date><![CDATA[2007-11-23 11:15:58]]></wp_post_date>
    <wp_post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2007-11-23 18:15:58]]></wp_post_date_gmt>
    <wp_comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp_comment_status>
    <wp_ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp_ping_status>
    <wp_post_name><![CDATA[fighting-for-our-lives-in-action]]></wp_post_name>
    <wp_status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp_status>
    <wp_post_parent>0</wp_post_parent>
    <wp_menu_order>0</wp_menu_order>
    <wp_post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp_post_type>
    <wp_post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp_post_password>
    <wp_is_sticky>0</wp_is_sticky>
    <category domain="category" nicename="read-all-about-it"><![CDATA[Read All About It]]></category>
    <wp_comment>
      <wp_comment_id>299</wp_comment_id>
      <wp_comment_author><![CDATA[pika_pik]]></wp_comment_author>
      <wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[unmatchableman@hotmail.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
      <wp_comment_author_url>http://</wp_comment_author_url>
      <wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[76.230.249.182]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
      <wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2007-11-23 14:11:38]]></wp_comment_date>
      <wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2007-11-23 21:11:38]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
      <wp_comment_content><![CDATA[Today some of us in Milwaukee dressed up as zombies, and handed out anti-capitalist literature at the mall near us while we moaned and wandered around until we were kicked out by security.]]></wp_comment_content>
      <wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
      <wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
      <wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
      <wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
    </wp_comment>
    <wp_comment>
      <wp_comment_id>300</wp_comment_id>
      <wp_comment_author><![CDATA[smileya]]></wp_comment_author>
      <wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[staineddesires@gmail.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
      <wp_comment_author_url>http://</wp_comment_author_url>
      <wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[69.114.60.167]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
      <wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2007-11-23 17:14:02]]></wp_comment_date>
      <wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2007-11-24 00:14:02]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
      <wp_comment_content><![CDATA[That's great.  Nice inspirational story.]]></wp_comment_content>
      <wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
      <wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
      <wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
      <wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
    </wp_comment>
    <wp_comment>
      <wp_comment_id>301</wp_comment_id>
      <wp_comment_author><![CDATA[rkamens]]></wp_comment_author>
      <wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[2600denver@gmail.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
      <wp_comment_author_url>http://</wp_comment_author_url>
      <wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[75.71.157.234]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
      <wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2007-11-23 21:13:03]]></wp_comment_date>
      <wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2007-11-24 04:13:03]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
      <wp_comment_content><![CDATA[inspiring story. Thanks for sharing. Also protested Starbucks today in the cold. Below freezing. They still felt the heat ; )]]></wp_comment_content>
      <wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
      <wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
      <wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
      <wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
    </wp_comment>
    <wp_comment>
      <wp_comment_id>302</wp_comment_id>
      <wp_comment_author><![CDATA[runrevolt]]></wp_comment_author>
      <wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[urbanwings@hotmail.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
      <wp_comment_author_url/>
      <wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[74.142.33.196]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
      <wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2007-11-24 09:18:03]]></wp_comment_date>
      <wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2007-11-24 16:18:03]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
      <wp_comment_content><![CDATA[I've had similar experiences with found copies of Rolling Thunder and Days of War. It's amazing how inspirational propaganda gets around and the lasting effect it has.

to respond to comments. i didn't zombie or protest. but i did buy a latte at starbucks. symbolism is nothing. taking more than you give is all that matters.]]></wp_comment_content>
      <wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
      <wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
      <wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
      <wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
    </wp_comment>
    <wp_comment>
      <wp_comment_id>303</wp_comment_id>
      <wp_comment_author><![CDATA[pika_pik]]></wp_comment_author>
      <wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[unmatchableman@hotmail.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
      <wp_comment_author_url>http://</wp_comment_author_url>
      <wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[65.30.183.39]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
      <wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2007-11-25 14:18:34]]></wp_comment_date>
      <wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2007-11-25 21:18:34]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
      <wp_comment_content><![CDATA[I wouldn't say symbolism is nothing, but it action is limited to it.  There's value in simply having fun and being ridiculous in such an absurd day.  Our action obviously wasn't going to end all domination and exploitation, but it might create dialog.

http://mke.indymedia.org/en/2007/11/208730.shtml]]></wp_comment_content>
      <wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
      <wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
      <wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
      <wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
    </wp_comment>
    <wp_comment>
      <wp_comment_id>304</wp_comment_id>
      <wp_comment_author><![CDATA[casey]]></wp_comment_author>
      <wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[newcasey@gmail.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
      <wp_comment_author_url>http://forestandcrag.com</wp_comment_author_url>
      <wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[72.71.212.233]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
      <wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2007-11-26 07:56:40]]></wp_comment_date>
      <wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2007-11-26 14:56:40]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
      <wp_comment_content><![CDATA[This is a great story. I still have a box of papers I am waiting to distribute up here in the mountains of NH. I would love to see a list of places that people have had success dropping and distributing these. Ive been leaving them around at cafes but seem to disappear rather quickly (either taken or tossed). I'd like to get creative about spreading the good word.]]></wp_comment_content>
      <wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
      <wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
      <wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
      <wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
    </wp_comment>
    <wp_comment>
      <wp_comment_id>305</wp_comment_id>
      <wp_comment_author><![CDATA[b. traven]]></wp_comment_author>
      <wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[b@crimethinc.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
      <wp_comment_author_url>http://www.crimethinc.com</wp_comment_author_url>
      <wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[74.60.183.29]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
      <wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2007-12-02 10:48:10]]></wp_comment_date>
      <wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2007-12-02 17:48:10]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
      <wp_comment_content><![CDATA[You can find an entertaining and informative how-to video for making a free literature display stand here:

http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WXoAVAIX5gA]]></wp_comment_content>
      <wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
      <wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
      <wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
      <wp_comment_user_id>2</wp_comment_user_id>
    </wp_comment>
    <wp_comment>
      <wp_comment_id>306</wp_comment_id>
      <wp_comment_author><![CDATA[troubadour-to-door]]></wp_comment_author>
      <wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[jmg07@hampshire.edu]]></wp_comment_author_email>
      <wp_comment_author_url>http://</wp_comment_author_url>
      <wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[66.251.27.54]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
      <wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2008-02-11 12:32:33]]></wp_comment_date>
      <wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2008-02-11 20:32:33]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
      <wp_comment_content><![CDATA[Just today, at lunch, a friend of mine and I started talking politics. He was the kind of guy who was not very political, but still did not like the way that the government is running things, but when he started talking about the kind of community he'd like to live in (a simple, agrarian commune), I asked him "have you ever heard of Crimethinc?" He responded that he hadn't, and so I pulled out a copy of Fighting For Our Lives, which I had been keeping on hand hoping for just this kind of miracle. He opened it, read the introduction, asked about which president had been killed by an anarchist, we dialogued a bit about anarchism, and he went back to the text. "You may already be an anarchist," he read &amp; then he looked at me and said, "you know what, I might be..." It made my day.]]></wp_comment_content>
      <wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
      <wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
      <wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
      <wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
    </wp_comment>
    <wp_comment>
      <wp_comment_id>307</wp_comment_id>
      <wp_comment_author><![CDATA[thebadguy]]></wp_comment_author>
      <wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[fightdrinkfight@gmail.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
      <wp_comment_author_url/>
      <wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[180.131.210.8]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
      <wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2009-11-22 05:32:13]]></wp_comment_date>
      <wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2009-11-22 13:32:13]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
      <wp_comment_content><![CDATA[this short, amazing, true story always gives me hope that things can change.  i would love to see the effects firsthand.]]></wp_comment_content>
      <wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
      <wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
      <wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
      <wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
    </wp_comment>
    <wp_comment>
      <wp_comment_id>308</wp_comment_id>
      <wp_comment_author><![CDATA[sgssl3]]></wp_comment_author>
      <wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[auto570180@hushmail.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
      <wp_comment_author_url/>
      <wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[67.180.248.206]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
      <wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2009-11-24 15:53:49]]></wp_comment_date>
      <wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2009-11-24 23:53:49]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
      <wp_comment_content><![CDATA[amazing video here http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WXoAVAIX5gA
so anyone know OTHER vids like so? til then i'll keep searching...........]]></wp_comment_content>
      <wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
      <wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
      <wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
      <wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
    </wp_comment>
    <wp_comment>
      <wp_comment_id>309</wp_comment_id>
      <wp_comment_author><![CDATA[GCheetah88]]></wp_comment_author>
      <wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[GCheetah88@triad.rr.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
      <wp_comment_author_url>http://www.myspace.com/peaceloveanarchy</wp_comment_author_url>
      <wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[174.98.64.29]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
      <wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2009-12-24 11:27:53]]></wp_comment_date>
      <wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2009-12-24 19:27:53]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
      <wp_comment_content><![CDATA[The other day, I went into the gas station to get change to get into the newspaper stand and stash FFOL in with the advertisements and publications in the middle of the local papers and ended up getting into a convo about politics with the gas station attendant.  We talked about how important independent media is and, conversely, how biased and false corporate agendas are, the fallacy of the two-party system, and the value of independent parties and candidates.  I proceeded to rag on capitalism and representative democracy in general.  I said to him, "You look like a man who would appreciate some free literature," and he said, "Absolutely."  So I gave him my last copy.  Leaving a piece of literature for someone to find, read, and hopefully treasure is one thing, but engaging them on a personal level and then delivering it directly into their hands can be SO much more effective, at least if you're dealing with more outgoing types of people.  Some people might prefer to just happen upon FFOL rather than engage in dialogue with a complete stranger, but most people seem to respond best to person-to-person dialogue.]]></wp_comment_content>
      <wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
      <wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
      <wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
      <wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
    </wp_comment>
  </item>