<item>
    <title>On Darren Thurston’s Statement, “Fired Back”</title>
    <link>http://www.crimethinc.com/blog/2007/12/22/on-darren-thurstons-statement-fired-back/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 23 Dec 2007 01:51:44 +0000</pubDate>
    <dc_creator><![CDATA[ret marut]]></dc_creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.crimethinc.com/blog/2007/12/22/on-darren-thurston%e2%80%99s-statement-%e2%80%9cfired-back%e2%80%9d/</guid>
    <description/>
    <content_encoded><![CDATA[<em>It is never acceptable to give information about any other person without his or her express consent. </em>It cannot be emphasized enough that informing to the government is always a serious matter, whether it is a question of a high profile defendant snitching on his comrades or an acquaintance of law-abiding activists answering a seemingly harmless question. The primary goal of the government in any political case is not to put any one defendant in prison but to obtain information with which to map radical communities, with the ultimate goal of repressing and controlling those communities. The most minor piece of trivia may serve to jeopardize a person’s life, whether or not they have ever broken any law.

On December 21, Operation Backfire cooperating defendant Darren Thurston released <a href="http://freedarren.org/wp-content/uploads/2007/12/firedback.pdf" target="_blank">a lengthy statement</a> presenting the history of Operation Backfire as he sees it and laying out what he apparently considers to be extenuating circumstances connected to his decision to inform. He insists that he does not condone snitching, but claims that he didn’t share any information that was harmful to others; unfortunately, as Thurston has chosen to withhold from the public both his plea agreement and the debrief documents that detail his cooperation with investigators, it’s impossible to verify this claim.

<!--more-->

In contrast, non-cooperating Operation Backfire defendants have made their plea agreements public in their entirety. Thurston explains that he has not done the same because in his case the materials “were not completely indicative of my cooperation and would be easily misunderstood by the majority of those who would hear about them,” but as his cooperation is already a matter of intense controversy, it could hardly make matters worse for him to follow their example.

At the conclusion of his statement, Thurston offers “his closest comrades” a limited apology for his decision to inform, admitting it “set a bad example” but placing responsibility for his choice on others’ shoulders: others cooperated first and made the case “unwinnable,” the government divided communities by spreading rumors, activists abandoned and vilified the cooperating defendants before they’d even decided whether or not to cooperate, and so on. He also casts aspersions on non-cooperating defendants without ever specifying which ones he means, and on their legal support groups as well. If this is not a matter of passive-aggressive self-justification but of serious concerns about their conduct, he owes it to the activist community to be more explicit.

Thurston states that Operation Backfire defendants were facing “guaranteed life sentences” until they cooperated. In contrast to those who attribute the considerably shorter sentences the non-cooperating defendants received to the vigorous efforts of their defense teams, he credits his partner and fellow informant Chelsea Dawn Gerlach with helping to arrange merciful plea agreements for the non-cooperating defendants—an account that is sure to be controversial. He also mentions uncritically that by the time he and Gerlach were able to communicate after their arrests, she had already informed to the government not only about his involvement in the actions for which he was charged but also about a great deal of other illegal activity he had participated in.

No doubt Thurston experienced a more frightening period of months following his arrest than most of us can possibly imagine. But this alone cannot justify a decision to inform; the fact that other defendants did not do the same shows that other options were possible. In his statement, he talks about “healing our movements and making them stronger,” but that can only occur on the foundation of a commitment to unconditionally and transparently refusing to inform on each other; any supposed solidarity that does not proceed from this premise is a sham that will crumble beneath the first onslaught of government repression. Addressing the question of what constitutes acceptable conduct is not infighting and backstabbing, but an essential element of healing and strengthening our communities. As Thurston points out, we should not take the state at its word as to who is informing—but now that he has signed a sealed agreement to inform, the burden of proof is on him to show the limits of that informing. Those who read Thurston’s statement should not take his analysis—or any analysis, including this one—at face value, since the perspectives of everyone who comments on Operation Backfire are inevitably colored by their own motives; the question is which motives are most likely to facilitate a useful analysis.

Thurston is in a difficult place, but there is still much he can do to facilitate the healing and strengthening of which he speaks. He can start by disclosing the full texts of his plea agreement and cooperation debriefing, and accepting complete personal accountability for his decision to inform. The state can do anything to us—isolate us, threaten us with life sentences, even, in some extremes, turn our loved ones against us. The only thing it cannot take from us, upon which any anti-authoritarian struggle must be founded, is our determination to abide by our principles come what may, thus retaining our freedom and dignity. Individual heroics cannot win a revolutionary struggle—only supportive communities can do that; but we can only form such communities by personally standing by our commitments, regardless of what other individuals do.

We can commend Thurston for the actions he once took in defense of animals and the environment, but the most important round of struggle takes place not in the streets but in the interrogation chamber—it is there, when the commitments and trust that form its backbone are put to the ultimate test, that a struggle lives or dies. The courage of all who refuse to assist the state demonstrates that such a struggle can live—that, in fact, it <em>does live.</em>]]></content_encoded>
    <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
    <wp_post_id>175</wp_post_id>
    <wp_post_date><![CDATA[2007-12-22 17:51:44]]></wp_post_date>
    <wp_post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2007-12-23 01:51:44]]></wp_post_date_gmt>
    <wp_comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp_comment_status>
    <wp_ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp_ping_status>
    <wp_post_name><![CDATA[on-darren-thurstons-statement-fired-back]]></wp_post_name>
    <wp_status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp_status>
    <wp_post_parent>0</wp_post_parent>
    <wp_menu_order>0</wp_menu_order>
    <wp_post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp_post_type>
    <wp_post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp_post_password>
    <wp_is_sticky>0</wp_is_sticky>
    <category domain="category" nicename="read-all-about-it"><![CDATA[Read All About It]]></category>
    <wp_comment>
      <wp_comment_id>359</wp_comment_id>
      <wp_comment_author><![CDATA[xdx]]></wp_comment_author>
      <wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[yoshomon@yahoo.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
      <wp_comment_author_url>http://printxculture.blogspot.com</wp_comment_author_url>
      <wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[207.246.115.13]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
      <wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2007-12-23 13:34:50]]></wp_comment_date>
      <wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2007-12-23 21:34:50]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
      <wp_comment_content><![CDATA[To quote Sadie and Exile (who have read many of the court documents not released to the public):  "...it has come to our attention that perhaps through naivete and perhaps through the deliberate spreading of misinformation, there has been some confusion over who amongst the indictees is worthy of prisoner support; meaning to us: who has NOT made statements implicating others, as the purpose of such statements is the further prosecution and imprisonment of others. Let us make this clear: all those amongst the indictees who have been apprehended, other than Ms. Waters, Mr. McGowen, Mr. Paul, obviously the authors of this piece; the so-called Ms. Zacher and Mr. Block, and sadly Mr. Rodgers, have dishonored themselves, their families and the very lineage of struggle which they themselves were once an integral part of, by becoming vicious traitors and handmaids of the state. To actively support these indictees who have been apprehended but not aforementioned is to support not only our incarceration but to wish that same fate upon many others currently living as fugitives or being sought similarly. If there are those amongst you reading this who feel the need to make excuses for those responsible for our imprisonment, we would ask you to refrain from offering a Janus-faced 'support' to us also, as it is completely antithetical to the reasons for our captivity."

Even if you read the publicly available plea deal that Thurston signed ( http://greenscare.org/pdfs/ThurstonRedactedPlea.pdf ) it contains information about Rubin and Dibee, which Thurston puts his signature on being true.  He is a snitch and is only attempting to spread misinformation so that he can get support while he is in prison - support which he should NOT receive, no matter how many times he apologizes or "comes clean".  His statement is essentially bullshit.]]></wp_comment_content>
      <wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
      <wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
      <wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
      <wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
    </wp_comment>
    <wp_comment>
      <wp_comment_id>360</wp_comment_id>
      <wp_comment_author><![CDATA[erling]]></wp_comment_author>
      <wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[steph@vcn.bc.ca]]></wp_comment_author_email>
      <wp_comment_author_url/>
      <wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[64.46.20.74]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
      <wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2007-12-23 17:04:10]]></wp_comment_date>
      <wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2007-12-24 01:04:10]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
      <wp_comment_content><![CDATA[You know, if you want to say that Thurston has no credibility, fair enough.  But that you have chosen to do so by generating the absurd fiction that he is making everything up to generate prison support - when he already has prison support and is serving out the last year of his sentence - unfortunately leaves you with no credibility to speak of either.]]></wp_comment_content>
      <wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
      <wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
      <wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
      <wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
    </wp_comment>
    <wp_comment>
      <wp_comment_id>361</wp_comment_id>
      <wp_comment_author><![CDATA[ret marut]]></wp_comment_author>
      <wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[ret@crimethinc.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
      <wp_comment_author_url>http://</wp_comment_author_url>
      <wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[71.236.26.226]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
      <wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2007-12-23 17:53:34]]></wp_comment_date>
      <wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2007-12-24 01:53:34]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
      <wp_comment_content><![CDATA[It's not entirely clear what Thurston's motives are, and I suggest we are cautious in speculating.

The center of gravity here is that when a person signs an agreement with the state, the burden of proof to show that they are not collaborating with the state (or else to show the limits of that collaboration) falls on them. For the reasons stated above, we cannot be certain of the extent of Thurston's informing--some of the information is available to the public, some is not.

This is a complex matter, for sure, and it's important that we are very intentional about the ways we discuss it as well as the positions we take. I want to emphasize that the above statement comes not from a self-righteous desire to vilify anyone, but rather from a consciousness of our responsibility to take this matter seriously. It doesn't serve us to sling accusations or call names, but we also cannot afford to brush off the question of collaboration with the state.

xdx is right to direct us to the plea agreement, in which Thurston signs on to a statement implicating two as-yet unapprehended defendants. I believe that, by any conventional definition of "collaborating" or "informing," this alone demonstrates that Thurston is an informant.

Informing is a breach of consent, the same as sexual assault. We don't accept it when a sexual assaulter blames his/her conduct on others or circumstances. There are a few competing trains of thought regarding how to handle sexual assaulters in our communities--exclusion, rehabilitation, etc.--but the most widely accepted principle is that we should abide by the wishes of the survivor. In this case, the survivors would include Exile and Sadie.]]></wp_comment_content>
      <wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
      <wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
      <wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
      <wp_comment_user_id>3</wp_comment_user_id>
    </wp_comment>
    <wp_comment>
      <wp_comment_id>362</wp_comment_id>
      <wp_comment_author><![CDATA[xdx]]></wp_comment_author>
      <wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[yoshomon@yahoo.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
      <wp_comment_author_url>http://printxculture.blogspot.com</wp_comment_author_url>
      <wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[74.140.149.31]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
      <wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2007-12-23 19:59:57]]></wp_comment_date>
      <wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2007-12-24 03:59:57]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
      <wp_comment_content><![CDATA[Erling, the danger of Darren's statement is not that it is a complete work of fiction.  He surrounds his fiction - that he is not an informant - with facts to make him sound legit (just as his supporter links to ecoprisoners.org and other websites that denounce Thurston, in order to make the free darren site look 'legit').  I will retract my speculation about his motives because his motivation is irrelevant.  The rest of my comment stands.

I don't think that sexual assault and informing on others are entirely the same, nor do I think they should be treated the same.  If the survivor of an informant for someone reason thought the informant should be welcomed back and trusted, I would hope that this wish would not be respected.  In practical terms, most informing plea deals require that the informant cooperate in all future cases and grand juries they're called for (a good example of this is the plea deal of Zachary Jenson - http://www.indybay.org/uploads/2006/07/20/zachplea.pdf ).  Snitching is a breach of consent that cannot be rehabilitated or forgiven, whereas friends of mine who have been sexually assaulted have confronted and reconciled with people who've sexually assaulted them.

Posing informing in terms of 'consent' is useful, but the metaphor with sexual assault only goes so far.  There is also the question of multiple survivors having conflicting wishes, and in the case of informants, the informant posing a clear danger to many people other than the survivor of their actions.  Another problem is that people in prison cannot so easily say exactly what they want to happen to the person who snitched on them, and even on the outside one is not really able to say what one wants to say.

Good to talk about these things.]]></wp_comment_content>
      <wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
      <wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
      <wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
      <wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
    </wp_comment>
    <wp_comment>
      <wp_comment_id>363</wp_comment_id>
      <wp_comment_author><![CDATA[xdx]]></wp_comment_author>
      <wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[yoshomon@yahoo.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
      <wp_comment_author_url>http://printxculture.blogspot.com</wp_comment_author_url>
      <wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[74.140.149.31]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
      <wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2007-12-23 20:06:31]]></wp_comment_date>
      <wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2007-12-24 04:06:31]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
      <wp_comment_content><![CDATA[Another note - I think a lot of these questions would become clearer if people who are interested in these cases and want to make up their own minds read the plea deals and other documents that are available to the public (they are available on ecoprisoners.org, greenscare.org, portland indymedia, and other sites).  Gumby Cascadia's court hearing notes are also good and having sat through a number of the plea hearings myself, I can attest to their credibility.  Darren's supporter even linked to Gumby's court hearing notes for Darren's sentencing, even though Gumby makes it clear in them that Darren is an informant!

I am glad that Thurston finally released this statement because he's been promising it for a long time, and it turns out to a lot of hot air.  His continued unwillingness to release the full details of his plea speaks volumes.]]></wp_comment_content>
      <wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
      <wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
      <wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
      <wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
    </wp_comment>
    <wp_comment>
      <wp_comment_id>364</wp_comment_id>
      <wp_comment_author><![CDATA[root]]></wp_comment_author>
      <wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[alastairmcgowan@btopenworld.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
      <wp_comment_author_url>http://usofc.blogspot.com</wp_comment_author_url>
      <wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[86.128.33.249]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
      <wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2008-01-14 11:21:10]]></wp_comment_date>
      <wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2008-01-14 19:21:10]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
      <wp_comment_content><![CDATA[You may be interested in a fresh view of things, my first visit since the site was revived. My first impression is of how much energy is being dissipated by this conflict - and thinking how much the hierarchy must be gloating over it and feeding from it. That some courageous people may have buckled under fear should be accepted by all of us as just one more of the consequences of the arsenal we all face every day. Somehow we have to rise above censure.]]></wp_comment_content>
      <wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
      <wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
      <wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
      <wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
    </wp_comment>
    <wp_comment>
      <wp_comment_id>365</wp_comment_id>
      <wp_comment_author><![CDATA[ret marut]]></wp_comment_author>
      <wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[ret@crimethinc.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
      <wp_comment_author_url>http://</wp_comment_author_url>
      <wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[71.23.109.102]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
      <wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2010-08-11 09:43:27]]></wp_comment_date>
      <wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2010-08-11 17:43:27]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
      <wp_comment_content><![CDATA[This is an article about Megan Adam, coordinator for Darren Thurston's support campaign getting disrupted and shut down at Under the Volcano, an annual music and politics fest in North Vancouver, B.C. Ironically, she was speaking on a panel about the past 20 years of resistance in Vancouver and B.C.

http://vancouver.mediacoop.ca/blog/lyn-highway/4412]]></wp_comment_content>
      <wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
      <wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
      <wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
      <wp_comment_user_id>3</wp_comment_user_id>
    </wp_comment>
  </item>