<item>
    <title>Fired for Plagiarizing Plagiarism</title>
    <link>http://www.crimethinc.com/blog/2008/02/12/fired-for-plagiarizing-plagiarism/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2008 21:13:13 +0000</pubDate>
    <dc_creator><![CDATA[b. traven]]></dc_creator>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.crimethinc.com/blog/2008/02/12/fired-for-plagiarizing-plagiarism/</guid>
    <description/>
    <content_encoded><![CDATA[Here’s a story from a correspondent in Texas, who was canned for running material from <a href="/books/days.html"><em>Days of War, Nights of Love</em></a> in a newspaper column—a humorous illustration of the hypocrisy and pettiness common in universities. Apparently, it is acceptable to argue in favor of plagiarism, but not to actually plagiarize anything; it is unacceptable to use text without citing sources, but it is perfectly standard to print outright falsehoods and censor the parties thus injured. We trust the erstwhile columnist, blessed with such absurd adversaries, is headed for finer things and brighter pastures.

<!--more His story after the jump.-->
<blockquote>I work for the <em>Daily Toreador</em>, the official newspaper of my college campus, Texas Tech University.  Two days ago as of writing this, I was fired for supposedly plagiarizing <a href="http://last-straw.net/2006/06/plagiarism-and-intellectual-loot/" target="_blank">a certain Christiaan Briggs</a>, allegedly taking material from his weblog concerning an article supporting plagiarism.

My cousin sent me the book <em>Days of War, Nights of Love</em>, and I read it cover to cover in less than a week.  It inspired me greatly, and I decided to find some sort of medium through which to spread these ideals.  After all, the book claims that CrimethInc. encourages the plagiarism of their concepts, even suggesting several ways to do so.  These include the broadcasting of readings over pirate radio, the reprinting of ideas in unwary newspapers, and complete republication of the book under a different name.  So I took that idea and ran with it.

I published several articles, talking about living life to the fullest (and not behind a desk), morality and how everyone should establish their own moral code, mainstreams and their devastating effect on society, and the natural “sidelines” phenomenon, among other subjects.  All was fine and good until I published a two-piece entry on plagiarism.  It encouraged plagiarism in the name of spreading revolutionary ideas to everyone, with no emphasis on who owns the ideas or where they come from.  I defamed intellectual property rights, brazenly stating their obvious defects.  I tried to rebuke the negative aura surrounding plagiarism, though NOT the lazy plagiarism of students turning in other papers as their own or mimicking those around them, rather the plagiarism in the context of an understanding of the work and the passing on of ideas.

Anyway, it turns out that Briggs beat me to the punch and published almost the same exact article that I did, both of us apparently relying heavily on the book’s words.  That's cool with me, he's doing what I'm trying to do and probably reaching many more people.  I certainly approve of both our actions.  Unfortunately, because Briggs posted his article first, things got a little twisted, and I was accused of plagiarizing not the book, but Briggs' article supporting plagiarism.

The editor informed me that they have a strict policy on citing work.
“Why didn't you attribute your information to this other guy?”
“Because I didn't get any of my information from this guy.  I got it from a book, and so did he.”
“Why didn't you attribute the book?”
“Because the book doesn't want to be attributed.  It encourages plagiarism and is not copyrighted.  I'll bring it to you if you want.”
“Don't bother.”
“So I'm fired?”
“Yeah, this makes me sick to my stomach.  We'll be publishing an article retracting your work and stating an apology, also the reason why we fired you.”
“Wow, that's awesome and totally necessary.  Thanks.”

I understand that the newspaper staff feels a need to cover its own ass, and that the editor is getting a lot of pressure from faculty members to chop someone's head off, specifically mine.  I understand all of that, but I don't understand why they need to publicly humiliate me in a paper that thousands of people read.  The actual article they wrote listed my full name and the actions I performed.  Despite what I told them about what my source was, they retained the opinion that I plagiarized from Briggs and published this opinion as a fact.  I know it shouldn't shock me, but I was stunned at the absolute nerve they had, talking about integrity and maintaining a strict honesty policy, when in fact they knowingly did not publish the entire story.

In addition, I was not a paid writer.  I voluntarily wrote articles for this paper using my own time and my own freedom.  I was providing the newspaper a service, and the paper could not run without contributions from writers such as myself.  Despite these dynamics, the editors did not hesitate to completely bury me in the mud.

After several polite requests directed at the editors to allow me to publish my side of things, or perhaps some sort of explanation, I was met with one response: “Absolutely not.”  When I emailed them each again, asking why they blatantly lied about what had happened, or at least had passed off their opinions of the situation as truth, I received no reply whatsoever.

I don't care at all that I've been fired, and I believe I made my point.  I stood for what I believed to be write, and did my best to walk the CrimethInc. walk.  I will certainly find a way to get my side of the story out there, hopefully along with more revolutionary material.  As long as I was able to get a few people on campus to think though, even in this painfully conservative town, then I'm happy.

P.S. This story was not plagiarized.</blockquote>]]></content_encoded>
    <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
    <wp_post_id>195</wp_post_id>
    <wp_post_date><![CDATA[2008-02-12 13:13:13]]></wp_post_date>
    <wp_post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2008-02-12 21:13:13]]></wp_post_date_gmt>
    <wp_comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp_comment_status>
    <wp_ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp_ping_status>
    <wp_post_name><![CDATA[fired-for-plagiarizing-plagiarism]]></wp_post_name>
    <wp_status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp_status>
    <wp_post_parent>0</wp_post_parent>
    <wp_menu_order>0</wp_menu_order>
    <wp_post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp_post_type>
    <wp_post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp_post_password>
    <wp_is_sticky>0</wp_is_sticky>
    <category domain="category" nicename="from-the-trenches"><![CDATA[From the Trenches]]></category>
    <wp_comment>
      <wp_comment_id>436</wp_comment_id>
      <wp_comment_author><![CDATA[d]]></wp_comment_author>
      <wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[ambitioushedonism@riseup.net]]></wp_comment_author_email>
      <wp_comment_author_url>http://</wp_comment_author_url>
      <wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[64.149.246.2]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
      <wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2008-02-13 07:28:21]]></wp_comment_date>
      <wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2008-02-13 15:28:21]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
      <wp_comment_content><![CDATA[Bummer.

On a more positive note, I plagiarized an entire conclusion to a college final paper from DOWNOL's section on morality. Instead of taking a couple hours to rehash the same ol' argument against heteronormativity, I stole from the book and spent an afternoon in the sun having a picnic and cheating on my partner.]]></wp_comment_content>
      <wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
      <wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
      <wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
      <wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
    </wp_comment>
    <wp_comment>
      <wp_comment_id>437</wp_comment_id>
      <wp_comment_author><![CDATA[pfm]]></wp_comment_author>
      <wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[pfm@crimethinc.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
      <wp_comment_author_url>http://crimethinc.com/blog</wp_comment_author_url>
      <wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[75.164.164.99]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
      <wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2008-02-13 08:26:06]]></wp_comment_date>
      <wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2008-02-13 16:26:06]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
      <wp_comment_content><![CDATA[That sucks for your partner. It's too bad you didn't develop better communication before violating their trust.]]></wp_comment_content>
      <wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
      <wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
      <wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
      <wp_comment_user_id>1</wp_comment_user_id>
    </wp_comment>
    <wp_comment>
      <wp_comment_id>438</wp_comment_id>
      <wp_comment_author><![CDATA[d]]></wp_comment_author>
      <wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[ambitioushedonism@riseup.net]]></wp_comment_author_email>
      <wp_comment_author_url>http://</wp_comment_author_url>
      <wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[64.149.246.2]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
      <wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2008-02-13 08:42:00]]></wp_comment_date>
      <wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2008-02-13 16:42:00]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
      <wp_comment_content><![CDATA[It was a pretty fucked up relationship in general. But just as I went from crass plagiarism to more creative re-use of ideas, I went from mere adultery to a much better situation. Yay, half-revolutions!]]></wp_comment_content>
      <wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
      <wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
      <wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
      <wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
    </wp_comment>
    <wp_comment>
      <wp_comment_id>439</wp_comment_id>
      <wp_comment_author><![CDATA[Pseudonym]]></wp_comment_author>
      <wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[mtx7669@juno.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
      <wp_comment_author_url>http://</wp_comment_author_url>
      <wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[70.94.40.138]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
      <wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2008-02-13 15:07:50]]></wp_comment_date>
      <wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2008-02-13 23:07:50]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
      <wp_comment_content><![CDATA[Sorry buddy, though I agree with b. traven - brighter pastures ahoy!

Additionally, if you're looking for a silver lining, perhaps the controversy surrounding your departure will elevate the interest in the original story far more than it ever could on its own.  Plus, you've already  got the sympathy of the other students - it's not as If anyone chafes more at being indoctrinated into the anti-plagiarism society than college students.  Your story is pretty newsworthy for students though.  If possible, contact another paper (possibly the other campus paper?) or even a local TV station and see if they'll interview you and run a story  where you attribute the 'real' source as D.O.W.N.O.L. and inspire a whole other lot to read the book.  Making a stink about first amendment rights and/or threatening libel/defamation/false light usually draws attention in the academic world.  After all, you said yourself that the paper is painting you in a false light which is defamatory to your character.  According to Wikipedia (and it's different even within regions of the US): In law, defamation (also called vilification, slander, and libel) is the communication of a statement that makes a false claim, expressively stated or implied to be factual, that may harm the reputation of an individual, business, product, group, government or nation. Most jurisdictions allow legal actions, civil and/or criminal, to deter various kinds of defamation and retaliate against groundless criticism.

This is not to say you ACTUALLY want to pursue a case as they can be humiliating and expensive, but a convincing threat would sure roust up some controversy if you've got the energy and will to pursue such ends.

Many folks are desperate for ideas that can help them break into a new world but haven't a clue that they already exist.  Perhaps you can help to change that.

Best of luck in your future endeavors!]]></wp_comment_content>
      <wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
      <wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
      <wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
      <wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
    </wp_comment>
    <wp_comment>
      <wp_comment_id>440</wp_comment_id>
      <wp_comment_author><![CDATA[Reynard]]></wp_comment_author>
      <wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[theninthcloud@gmail.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
      <wp_comment_author_url>http://</wp_comment_author_url>
      <wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[69.65.206.162]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
      <wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2008-02-14 03:03:58]]></wp_comment_date>
      <wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2008-02-14 11:03:58]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
      <wp_comment_content><![CDATA[Haha, thanks everyone.  Yeah, I'm the guy who was fired from this newspaper.  I've considered many suggestions, like flyers, radio shows, and legal action.  Several lawyers I've talked to claim that I have a case for defamation of character, perhaps even libel.  Unfortunately, my article was so similar to Briggs that it would ultimately come down to a case of my word against theirs.

It has been a stressful and taxing situation that made me quite angry, but in the end, I've realized that I'd rather expend my energies pursuing something productive and meaningful.  I'd rather use my time finding those who agree with me, rather than endlessly quibbling with those who never will.

I haven't completely ruled out going to another media outlet, though I am quite willing to just let it go.  I expected to face resistance, for we are fighting the status quo itself here, I just didn't think it would be this...haha, well, unfair.

Anyway, thanks for calling attention to this CWC, and for listening to my side of the story.  Fortunately, this provides me a way to intertwine myself with this community further.]]></wp_comment_content>
      <wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
      <wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
      <wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
      <wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
    </wp_comment>
    <wp_comment>
      <wp_comment_id>441</wp_comment_id>
      <wp_comment_author><![CDATA[Christiaan]]></wp_comment_author>
      <wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[christiaan@last-straw.net]]></wp_comment_author_email>
      <wp_comment_author_url/>
      <wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[82.35.232.13]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
      <wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2008-02-14 23:47:29]]></wp_comment_date>
      <wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2008-02-15 07:47:29]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
      <wp_comment_content><![CDATA[Hi, it's Christiaan Briggs here. Sorry to hear about all the shit you've been put through. I was on an email-free holiday in NZ so wasn't aware this had taken place. I'd be more than happy to provide testimony in a defamation or libel case. You'd reach quite an audience with these ideas if you were to take this to court!]]></wp_comment_content>
      <wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
      <wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
      <wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
      <wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
    </wp_comment>
    <wp_comment>
      <wp_comment_id>442</wp_comment_id>
      <wp_comment_author><![CDATA[Reynard]]></wp_comment_author>
      <wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[theninthcloud@gmail.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
      <wp_comment_author_url>http://</wp_comment_author_url>
      <wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[69.65.206.162]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
      <wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2008-02-15 07:23:26]]></wp_comment_date>
      <wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2008-02-15 15:23:26]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
      <wp_comment_content><![CDATA[No worries my friend!  For me, it's at the point where I can look back and laugh at the irony.]]></wp_comment_content>
      <wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
      <wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
      <wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
      <wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
    </wp_comment>
    <wp_comment>
      <wp_comment_id>443</wp_comment_id>
      <wp_comment_author><![CDATA[monkey_sj]]></wp_comment_author>
      <wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[libertyordeath.sj@gmail.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
      <wp_comment_author_url/>
      <wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[70.98.76.131]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
      <wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2008-02-17 16:10:31]]></wp_comment_date>
      <wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2008-02-18 00:10:31]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
      <wp_comment_content><![CDATA[Hey, I'm glad you got your story out somewhere. Christiaan Briggs posted something on ze's blog about it, too. Everybody (well, definitely not everybody I'm sure, but all parties involved) but The Daily Toreader get it, eh? I sent a letter to the editor of Daily Toreader. Told them their kneejerk reaction is stupid. Maybe won't make a difference, but at least they'll know more than one person disagrees with them.]]></wp_comment_content>
      <wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
      <wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
      <wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
      <wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
    </wp_comment>
    <wp_comment>
      <wp_comment_id>444</wp_comment_id>
      <wp_comment_author><![CDATA[Blankey86]]></wp_comment_author>
      <wp_comment_author_email><![CDATA[Blakey838@hotmail.com]]></wp_comment_author_email>
      <wp_comment_author_url/>
      <wp_comment_author_IP><![CDATA[24.21.143.28]]></wp_comment_author_IP>
      <wp_comment_date><![CDATA[2008-02-18 09:21:41]]></wp_comment_date>
      <wp_comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2008-02-18 17:21:41]]></wp_comment_date_gmt>
      <wp_comment_content><![CDATA[Speaking of illogical accusations of plagiarism:  http://www.politico.com/news/stories/0208/8570.html

Mmmm politics.]]></wp_comment_content>
      <wp_comment_approved><![CDATA[1]]></wp_comment_approved>
      <wp_comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp_comment_type>
      <wp_comment_parent>0</wp_comment_parent>
      <wp_comment_user_id>0</wp_comment_user_id>
    </wp_comment>
  </item>