<item>
		<title>From the Depths Touring East Coast in April</title>
		<link>http://www.crimethinc.com/blog/2008/03/31/from-the-depths-goes-on-tour/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2008 14:50:06 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc_creator><![CDATA[b. traven]]></dc_creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.crimethinc.com/blog/2008/03/31/from-the-depths-goes-on-tour/</guid>
		<description/>
		<content_encoded><![CDATA[A couple of the survivors of Requiem—not to mention other bands such as Intense Youth, Auryn, Balaclava, Network of Terror, and Catharsis—are in a new band now, <strong>From the Depths</strong>. Some of you may have seen them at their first out-of-state show in early March at the National Conference on Organized Resistance in Washington, DC. They're heading north next week for ten more shows, including one following the NYC anarchist bookfair. The tour dates and relevant information <a href="http://www.crimethinc.com/blog/2008/03/31/from-the-depths-goes-on-tour/">can all be found below</a>.

They'll have a great deal of literature with them, mostly free, and are eager to compare notes with other anarchist organizers and adventurists.

<!--more Tour dates and info after the jump.-->

<strong>From the Depths: April 2008 Tour</strong>
<em>for information: <a href="mailto:crimethincbooking@yahoo.com">crimethincbooking@yahoo.com</a></em>

<strong>Tuesday, April 8: Washington, DC</strong>
<em>with Ryan Harvey, Ingrid, and The Surge</em>
7 pm
the Bobby Fisher Memorial Building
1644 North Capitol St. NW, Washington DC, 20002
Four blocks from the "New York Ave/Florida Ave" Metro stop on the Red line.
Check out BFMB.ORG for more directions.
$7-10 sliding scale to benefit Elizabeth Sanders' legal fund
<blockquote> Elizabeth Sanders is a member of the activist community in DC. She is being falsely charged with participation in a mass grocery walkout at Whole Foods. On the eve of the October 22nd No War No Warming actions, while outside the convergence center, Elizabeth was snatched off the street by undercover police and interrogated. She was falsely identified, based on a physical resemblance to a person the police were seeking in connection to the incident at Whole Foods.
Throughout the court proceedings, the prosecution pressed on connections between Elizabeth and Food Not Bombs, veganism, and the activist community. The judge found Elizabeth guilty because of her ties to activism, not because her involvement in a crime had been proven beyond a reasonable doubt. This case has implications for all of us who are associated with activism in this city, including those kinds of activism that are supposedly 1st amendment protected rights.
This whole event has been traumatizing for Elizabeth and the legal battle has taken over a large part of her life. Her family is in debt due to legal costs, she has missed a semester of school, and she may not be able to afford to finish next year. While you may not know Elizabeth personally, chances are you have seen her at meetings, shows, or other events. To write Elizabeth a message of support, or to find out about how to help her cover legal costs, please write to <a href="mailto:supportelizabeth@riseup.net">supportelizabeth@riseup.net</a></blockquote>
<strong>Wednesday, April 9: Baltimore, MD</strong>
<em>with Army of Kashyyyk, Crypt of Raix, and Cassettes on Fire</em>
Charm City Arts Space, 1729 Maryland Avenue, Baltimore, MD 21201

<strong>Thursday, April 10: Philadelphia, PA</strong>
<em>with Elder and Dissystema</em>
Planet Mollie, 1019 S. 47th Street

<strong>Friday, April 11: Hartford, CT</strong>
7 pm
217 S Whitney St

<strong>Saturday, April 12: New York City, NY</strong>
Day: tabling at the NYC bookfair
Night: performing at John Bosch (the venue), 742 Willoughby Avenue, Brooklyn

<strong>Sunday, April 13: Allentown, PA</strong>
<em>with Screaming Females, Moister, the Dynamite Plan, and Alarm Clark</em>
5 pm matinee
Jan's Room $6
call 610 349 6607 for info

<strong>Monday, April 14: Pittsburgh, PA</strong>
<em>with Path to Misery, Drugdealer (x-CIC), and Auryn</em>
7 pm
Mr. Roboto Project
722 Wood St., Wilkinsburg, Pennsylvania 15221
$6

<strong>Tuesday, April 15: Columbus, OH</strong>
<em>with Paralyzer and one more TBA</em>
doors 8 pm, showtime 9 pm
The Legion Of Doom, 1579 Indianola Avenue, Columbus, Ohio 43201

<strong>Wednesday, April 16: Lexington, KY</strong>
Shrieking Shack, 503 Oldham Ct.

<strong>Thursday, April 17: Asheville, NC</strong>
<em>with Raccoon Party</em>
at Gourmet Perks]]></content_encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp_post_id>218</wp_post_id>
		<wp_post_date><![CDATA[2008-03-31 06:50:06]]></wp_post_date>
		<wp_post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2008-03-31 14:50:06]]></wp_post_date_gmt>
		<wp_comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp_comment_status>
		<wp_ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp_ping_status>
		<wp_post_name><![CDATA[from-the-depths-goes-on-tour]]></wp_post_name>
		<wp_status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp_status>
		<wp_post_parent>0</wp_post_parent>
		<wp_menu_order>0</wp_menu_order>
		<wp_post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp_post_type>
		<wp_post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp_post_password>
		<wp_is_sticky>0</wp_is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="calling-all-anarchists"><![CDATA[Calling All Anarchists]]></category>
		<wp_postmeta>
			<wp_meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp_meta_key>
			<wp_meta_value><![CDATA[2]]></wp_meta_value>
		</wp_postmeta>
	</item>